[
    {
        "category": "Americanisms",
        "question": "Britains say 'tarmac'; Americans say ------.",
        "answer": "runway"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Analogy: 'Ancient' is to 'old' as 'recent' is to --------.",
        "answer": "current"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Bull - cow as fox - ----------.",
        "answer": "vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Goose - geese as passerby - -----------.",
        "answer": "passersby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Your ---- holds your head to your shoulders.",
        "answer": "neck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "In what field of study would you find \"flying buttresses\"?",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "The study of building design is ------------.",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "This statue was found on the Greek island of Melos in 1820.",
        "answer": "Venus de Milo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Three main types of Greek columns are Doric, Ionic, and ----------.",
        "answer": "Corinthian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "What Dutch master painted 64 self-portraits?",
        "answer": "Rembrandt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Where is the Louvre located?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "What is the only sign in the zodiac which doesn't represent a living thing?",
        "answer": "Libra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "Which month has a diamond as a birthstone?",
        "answer": "April"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "A heavenly body moving under the attraction of the Sun and consisting of a nucleus and a tail is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "comet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Does Uranus have an aurora?",
        "answer": "yes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "From 1979 until 2000 the most distant planet from the earth was -------.",
        "answer": "Neptune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "How many planets are there in our solar system?",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "If you're in the northern hemisphere, Polaris, the North Star, can be found by looking which direction?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the second-largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "saturn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Our galaxy is commonly known as the --------.",
        "answer": "Milky Way"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The Big Dipper is part of what constellation?",
        "answer": "Ursa Major"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The North Star is also known as -------.",
        "answer": "Polaris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The fourth planet from the sun is ----.",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The name for the group of stars which form a hunter with a club and shield is -----.",
        "answer": "Orion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The planet closest to the sun is -------.",
        "answer": "Mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The spiral galaxy nearest ours is the --------- galaxy.",
        "answer": "Andromeda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The tides on the earth's oceans are actually created by gravitational pull from the ----.",
        "answer": "Moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This cluster of stars is also known as the Seven Sisters.",
        "answer": "Pleiades"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This comet appears every 76.3 years.",
        "answer": "Comet Halley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This planet's diameter is most equal to that of the earth's.",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What does \"Ursa Major\" mean in everyday English?",
        "answer": "great bear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the astronomical name for a group of stars?",
        "answer": "constellation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name for the theoretical end-product of the gravitational collapse of a massive star?",
        "answer": "black hole"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name used to describe the \"minor planets\"?",
        "answer": "asteroids"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the ocean of air around the earth called?",
        "answer": "atmosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the proper name for falling stars?",
        "answer": "meteors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the term for the path followed a by a small body around a massive body in space?",
        "answer": "orbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the moon?",
        "answer": "tides"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What planet boasts the Great Red Spot?",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Bet you don't know ;-)",
        "question": "The two sexes of humans are male and ------?",
        "answer": "female"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous, oily liquid occurs in tobacco leaves.",
        "answer": "nicotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color.",
        "answer": "Haemoglobin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "Every human has one of these on their tummies.",
        "answer": "navel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "How many large holes are in your head?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "This complex substance makes up all living things.",
        "answer": "protoplasm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is normal body temperature for an adult human (in degrees fahrenheit)?",
        "answer": "98.6"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "The practice of joining the parts of two plants to make them grow as one is called --------.",
        "answer": "grafting"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "These flowerless plants grow on bare rocks and tree stumps.",
        "answer": "lichen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This fruit has its seeds on the outside.",
        "answer": "strawberry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This term means 'cone-bearing trees'.",
        "answer": "conifers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "What fruit bear the latin name \"citrus grandis\"?",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Calendar",
        "question": "How many days where there in 1976?",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Alvin & Simon had a brother called ----.",
        "answer": "Theodore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An Andy Panda cartoon gave birth to a famous, cantankerous bird. Name him.",
        "answer": "Woody Woodpecker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An adventurous penguin named Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named -------?",
        "answer": "Chumley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An alien creature in a funny hat has opposed both Bugs Bunny and Daffy Duck.  Where is he from?",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Before Olive Oil met Popeye she was engaged to someone.  Who was he?",
        "answer": "Ham Gravy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Benny and Cecil were at odds with whom?",
        "answer": "John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Bugs always finds himself at the wrong end of a gun, usually toted by either Elmer Fudd or who?",
        "answer": "Yosemite Sam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Casper the Friendly Ghost frolicked with which witch?",
        "answer": "Wendy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Boyer inspired a cartoon skunk. Who?",
        "answer": "Pepe le Pew"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Famous Phrases: Who knows? The ------.",
        "answer": "Shadow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Gadzookie has a large, green friend. Who is he?",
        "answer": "Godzilla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Hanna-Barbera rose to fame by creating what duo for MGM?",
        "answer": "Tom and Jerry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "How does Wonder Woman control her invisible airplane?",
        "answer": "mental powers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In the cartoons who was Hokie Wolf's sidekick?",
        "answer": "Ding"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In what city does Fat Albert live?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Mentor of Titan had two children in the Marvel comics, Thanos and ---?",
        "answer": "Ero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Miss Buckley is secretary to what commanding officer?",
        "answer": "General Halftrack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Alley Oop's girl friend.",
        "answer": "Oola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Cathy's on again/off again boy friend?",
        "answer": "Irving"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Dennis the Menace's next door neighbors.",
        "answer": "Mr and Mrs Wilson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Donald Duck's girlfriend?",
        "answer": "Daisy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Hagar the Horrible's dog.",
        "answer": "Snert"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Li'l Abner's favorite Indian drink.",
        "answer": "Kickapoo Joy Juice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the European hit, now an animated series about underwater people.",
        "answer": "The Snorks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the apartments the Jetson's live in.",
        "answer": "The Skypad Apartments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the dog in the Yankee Doodle cartoons.",
        "answer": "Chopper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the fastest mouse in all of Mexico.",
        "answer": "Speedy Gonzalez"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the ranger who was always after Yogi Bear.",
        "answer": "Rick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the town that Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty lived in.",
        "answer": "Bedrock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "On what T.V. show could Tom Terrific be found?",
        "answer": "Captain Kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Popeye's chief adversary has two names, Bluto and ------?",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Porky Pig had a girlfriend named --------.",
        "answer": "Petunia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Tess Trueheart married which plainclothes detective?",
        "answer": "Dick Tracy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What came out of Milton's head?",
        "answer": "steam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What character did Tex Avery first create upon arriving at MGM?",
        "answer": "Screwball Squirrel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip character is Beetle Bailey's sister?",
        "answer": "Lois (of Hi and Lois)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Dagwood give up to marry Blondie?",
        "answer": "A family inheritance"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Peppermint Patty always call Charlie Brown?",
        "answer": "Chuck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Batman's butler Alfred's last name.",
        "answer": "Pennyworth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Blondie's maiden name?",
        "answer": "Oop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?",
        "answer": "Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Smokey Stover's job?",
        "answer": "fireman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Super Chicken's partners name?",
        "answer": "Fred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the mother's name in Family Circus?",
        "answer": "Thelma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Duddley Do-Right's horse?",
        "answer": "Horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the Family Circus's dog?",
        "answer": "Barf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What kind of dog is Scooby Doo?",
        "answer": "great dane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What type of plant does Broom Hilda sell?",
        "answer": "venus flytrap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was Daffy Duck's favorite insult?",
        "answer": "You're dispicable!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was George of the Jungle always running in to?",
        "answer": "A tree"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first cartoon to feature sound?",
        "answer": "Steamboat Willie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of George of the Jungle's pet elephant?",
        "answer": "Shep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Speed Racer's car?",
        "answer": "The Mach Five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the original name Charles Schultz had for Peanuts?",
        "answer": "Li'l Folks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the relationship between Superman and Supergirl?",
        "answer": "cousin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When Tweety exclaimed, \"I thought I saw a putty tat!\", who did he see?",
        "answer": "Sylvester"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When danger appeared, Quick Draw McGraw became which super hero?",
        "answer": "El KaBong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not a Birdman, what does Ray Randall do for a living?",
        "answer": "police officer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?",
        "answer": "shoeshine boy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirel and Bullwinkle Moose from?",
        "answer": "Frostbite Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Clark Kent attend college?",
        "answer": "Metropolis University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did George of the Jungle live?",
        "answer": "Imgwee Gwee Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Mighty Mouse get his superpowers?",
        "answer": "supermarket"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where do Rocky and Bullwinkle play football?",
        "answer": "What'samatta University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does George Jetson work?",
        "answer": "Spacely Sprockets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does Yogi Bear Live?",
        "answer": "Jellystone Park"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which comic strip was banned from \"Stars and Stripes\"?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which superhero loves peace enough to kill for it?",
        "answer": "Peacemaker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who always tried to kill Krazy Kat?",
        "answer": "Captain Marvel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Donald Duck's uncle?",
        "answer": "Scrooge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Sally Brown's sweet baboo?",
        "answer": "Linus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Scooby Doo's nephew??",
        "answer": "Scrappy Doo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Snoopy's arch enemy?",
        "answer": "The Red Baron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is stationed at Camp Swampy in the comic strips?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who runs Andy Capp's favorite pub?",
        "answer": "Jack and Jill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who says, \"Th-th-th-that's all folks!\"",
        "answer": "Porky Pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who shot Bruce Wayne's parents?",
        "answer": "Chill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Dick Dastardly's pet?",
        "answer": "Muttley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was always trying to get rent from Andy Capp?",
        "answer": "Percy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the Hulk's first friend?",
        "answer": "Rick Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the original voice of Mickey Mouse?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Hydrogen Hydroxide is more commonly known as what?",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Nitrogen, a poisonous gas, makes up 78% of the --- that we breathe.",
        "answer": "air"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium Hydroxide is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "lye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium bicarbonate is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "baking soda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The process of removing salt from sea water is known as -----------.",
        "answer": "desalination"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The smallest portion of a substance capable of existing independently and retaining its original properties is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "molecule"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into gold was called -------.",
        "answer": "alchemy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the heaviest naturally occurring element.",
        "answer": "uranium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the symbol for tin.",
        "answer": "Sn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous gas is in the exhaust fumes from cars.",
        "answer": "carbon monoxide"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Water containing carbon dioxide under pressure is called ---- -----.",
        "answer": "soda water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is it that turns blue litmus paper red?",
        "answer": "acid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?",
        "answer": "TNT"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for copper?",
        "answer": "Cu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
        "answer": "Au"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the main component of air?",
        "answer": "nitrogen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the more scientific name for quicksilver?",
        "answer": "mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for iron in chemistry?",
        "answer": "Fe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for silver?",
        "answer": "Ag"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Name the loner rebel reindeer with the red shiny nose.",
        "answer": "Rudolph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Santa Claus reportedly lives at the ----- Pole.",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Comic Strip Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip is set at Camp Swampy?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "That big square thing you're staring at right now is called a -------?",
        "answer": "monitor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "The Internet Relay Chat Program, which normally connects to port 6667, is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "IRC"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  Exalting one's country above all others.",
        "answer": "nationalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The belief that there is no God.",
        "answer": "atheism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The theory that man cannot prove the existence of a god.",
        "answer": "agnosticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-ism: The belief in the existence of a god or gods.",
        "answer": "theism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A diseased condition resulting from the use of beverages such as whiskey.",
        "answer": "alcoholism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A one-party system of government in which control is maintained by force and regimentation.",
        "answer": "fascism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A painful stiffness of the muscles and joints",
        "answer": "rheumatism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A severe or unfavorable judgment.",
        "answer": "criticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: An economic system characterized by private ownership and competition.",
        "answer": "capitalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive emphasis on financial gain.",
        "answer": "commercialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive enthusiasm or zeal for a cause.",
        "answer": "fanaticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Poisoning caused by a toxin in improperly prepared food.",
        "answer": "botulism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Public ownership of the basic means of production, distribution, and exchange.",
        "answer": "socialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: The belief in living a very austere and self-denying life.",
        "answer": "asceticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A clip, shaped like a bar to keep a woman's hair in place is a -------.",
        "answer": "barrette"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A depilatory is a substance used for removing ----.",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A device used to change the voltage of alternating currents is a ----------.",
        "answer": "transformer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A flat, round hat sometimes worn by soldiers is a -----.",
        "answer": "beret"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A government in which power is restricted to a few is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "oligarchy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person in his eighties is called a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "octogenarian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person who starts fires maliciously is a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "arsonist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person with a strong desire to steal is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "kleptomaniac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A pugilist is a -----.",
        "answer": "boxer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A receptacle for holy water is a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "font"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A sun-dried grape is known as a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "raisin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A word like 'NASA' formed from the initials of other words is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "acronym"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Acrophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "heights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited ----------.",
        "answer": "knowledge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An anemometer measures ---- --------.",
        "answer": "wind velocity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An animal stuffer is a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "taxidermist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An artist supports his canvas on a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "easel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An instrument on a car to measure the distance travelled is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "odometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Androphobia is the fear of -----.",
        "answer": "males"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Animals that once existed but don't exist now are said to be -------.",
        "answer": "extinct"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Any object worn as a charm may be called a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "amulet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Bibliophobia is a fear of -----.",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Brontophobia is the fear of -------.",
        "answer": "thunder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "ring dating"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Doraphobia is the fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "fur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Eleutherophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "freedom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Gymnophobia is the fear of ----------.",
        "answer": "naked bodies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Hills and ridges composed of drifting sand are known as -----.",
        "answer": "dunes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Ichthyology is the study of --------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A crime more serious than a misdemeanor.",
        "answer": "felony"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A formal agreement enforceable by law.",
        "answer": "contract"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A supplement to a will.",
        "answer": "codicil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: The people chosen to render a verdict in a court.",
        "answer": "jury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: To steal property entrusted to one's care.",
        "answer": "embezzle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the pain-inflicting person you go to to get your teeth fixed.",
        "answer": "dentist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the porceilan chair you sit on at least once a day.",
        "answer": "toilet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "One who tells fortunes by the stars is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "astrologer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Rats, mice, beavers, and squirrels are all -------.",
        "answer": "rodents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The art of tracing designs and taking impressions of them is -----------.",
        "answer": "lithography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The covering on the tip of a shoelace is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "aglet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The distance around the outside of a circle is its ------------.",
        "answer": "circumference"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The earth's atmosphere and the space beyond is known as ---------.",
        "answer": "aerospace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The effect produced when sound is reflected back is known as a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "echo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The feeling of having experienced something before is known as -------.",
        "answer": "deja vu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of preparing and dispensing drugs is --------.",
        "answer": "pharmacy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of providing men, equipment and supplies for military operations is called --------.",
        "answer": "logistics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human behaviour is ----------.",
        "answer": "psychology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human pre-history is -----------.",
        "answer": "archaeology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of insects is ----------.",
        "answer": "entomology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of light and its relation to sight is called ------.",
        "answer": "optics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of man and culture is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "anthropology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of natural phenomena: motion, forces, light, sound, etc. is called ------.",
        "answer": "physics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of plants is ------.",
        "answer": "botany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of religion is --------.",
        "answer": "theology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of sound is ---------.",
        "answer": "acoustics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the composition of substances and the changes that they undergo is ---------.",
        "answer": "chemistry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the earth's physical divisions into mountains, seas, etc. is ---------.",
        "answer": "geography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the manner in which organisms carry on their life processes is ---------.",
        "answer": "physiology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The symbols used on a map are explained by the ------.",
        "answer": "legend"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The treatment of disease by chemical substances which are toxic to the causative micro-organisms is called ------------.",
        "answer": "chemotherapy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The weight at the end of a pendulum is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "bob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The wide wall built along the banks of rivers to stop flooding is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "levee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The word \"cumulus\" refers to a type of -----------.",
        "answer": "cloud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points, on a curved surface.",
        "answer": "calliper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures atmospheric pressure.",
        "answer": "barometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures the velocity of the wind.",
        "answer": "anemometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This is the fear of enclosed spaces.",
        "answer": "claustrophobia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word is used as the international radio distress call.",
        "answer": "mayday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word means \"split personality\".",
        "answer": "schizophrenia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Throat, foxing, and platform are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "shoe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Toxiphobia is a fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "poison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a brandophile collect?",
        "answer": "cigar bands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a heliologist study?",
        "answer": "the sun"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does an ornithologist study?",
        "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?",
        "answer": "tourniquet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a dried plum called?",
        "answer": "prune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a female swan called?",
        "answer": "pen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?",
        "answer": "octagon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is another name for a tombstone inscription?",
        "answer": "epitaph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is measured by a chronometer?",
        "answer": "time"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for a Japanese dwarf tree?",
        "answer": "bonsai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for the Aurora Borealis?",
        "answer": "northern lights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common term for a \"somnambulist\"?",
        "answer": "sleepwalker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the name for a branch of a river?",
        "answer": "tributary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of heredity called?",
        "answer": "genetics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of prehistoric plants and animals called?",
        "answer": "paleontology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the term for a castrated rooster?",
        "answer": "capon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Which science studies weather?",
        "answer": "meteorology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Domestic Metallurgy",
        "question": "Name the clothing wrinkle remover that sounds like a kind of metal.",
        "answer": "iron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A 3 1/2\" floppy disk measures --- and 1/2 inches across.",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A brown crayon is what color?",
        "answer": "brown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A smoke detector will alarm if it detects -----.",
        "answer": "smoke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A water heater keeps ----- warm for you.",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "Although not all come from France, ------ fries are often served with hamburgers.",
        "answer": "french"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "An ----- clock usually wakes you in the morning.",
        "answer": "alarm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "During the American Revolution, the Boston Tea Party took place in ------ Harbor.",
        "answer": "boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How do you spell abbreviation?",
        "answer": "abbreviation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How many pencils are there in a dozen?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?",
        "answer": "Thornton Wilder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "The play \"Our Town\" is set where?",
        "answer": "Grover's Corners"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fantasy",
        "question": "What is a sorcerer who deals in black magic called?",
        "answer": "necromancer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Boston butt, jowl, and picnic ham are parts of a ------.",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Even though it tastes nothing like grapes, a ---------- is often eaten for breakfast.",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From what animal do we get venison?",
        "answer": "deer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fish is caviar obtained?",
        "answer": "sturgeon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fruit is the liqueur Kirsh made?",
        "answer": "cherry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Iceberg, Boston, and Bibb are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "lettuce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Laetrile is associated with the pit of which fruit?",
        "answer": "apricot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Little round chocolate candies are known as _&m's.",
        "answer": "m"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Mustard, ketchup and onions on a hotdog are all ----------.",
        "answer": "condiments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Name the only fruit named for its color.",
        "answer": "orange"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Natural vanilla flavoring comes from this plant.",
        "answer": "orchid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often drunk, this liquid is normally harvested from female cows.",
        "answer": "milk"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, bacon is actually the flesh of what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, the egg comes from what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "chicken"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Rum is made from this plant.",
        "answer": "sugar cane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Vermicelli literally means -----------.",
        "answer": "little worms"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?",
        "answer": "sangria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is Japanese \"sake\" made from?",
        "answer": "rice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is the name of the syrup drained from raw sugar?",
        "answer": "molasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What kind of nuts are used in marzipan?",
        "answer": "almonds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where is the best brandy bottled?",
        "answer": "cognac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where was Budweiser first brewed?",
        "answer": "St. Louis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Bourbon, sugar and mint make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "mint julep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Cognac (brandy) and white creme de menthe make a(n) -------------.",
        "answer": "stinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Creme de Cacao, cream, and brandy make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "brandy alexander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Gin and Collins mix make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "Tom Collins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Rum, lime, and cola drink make a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "cuba libre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Triple sec, tequila, and lemon or lime juice make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "margarita"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka and Kahlua make a -----------.",
        "answer": "black russian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka, orange juice and Galliano make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "Harvey Wallbanger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Whiskey, hot coffee, and whipped cream make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Irish coffee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A bridge hand with no cards in one suit is said to have a -------.",
        "answer": "void"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A poker hand consisting of three of a kind and a pair is called a -------.",
        "answer": "full house"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many balls are used in a game of snooker including the cue ball?",
        "answer": "twenty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?",
        "answer": "forty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?",
        "answer": "sixty four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "If you \"peg out\" what game are you playing?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In poker five cards of the same suit is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "flush"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?",
        "answer": "black"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game might a person have a \"full house\"?",
        "answer": "poker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport are \"Staunton\" pieces used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport can a person be \"skunked\"?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport are terms \"spare\" and \"gutter\" used?",
        "answer": "tenpin bowling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game are the terms: 'pin', 'fork', and 'skewer' used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game is the term \"rook\" used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only flexible murder weapon in the game of \"Cluedo\".",
        "answer": "rope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only woman suspect in the game of \"Cluedo\" who isn't married.",
        "answer": "Miss Scarlett"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "These are the two highest valued letters in \"Scrabble\".  \"Q\" and -----.",
        "answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This ancient Chinese game is played with 156 small rectangular tiles.",
        "answer": "mah jongg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This is the lowest ranking suit in Bridge.",
        "answer": "clubs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This term denotes a chess move in which both the king and the rook are moved.",
        "answer": "castling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What bowling term means three straight strikes?",
        "answer": "turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What game or sport is Bobby Fischer identified with?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What number is on the opposite side of the \"five\" on dice?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What score is not possible for a cribbage hand?",
        "answer": "nineteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which chess piece is usually valued as 5 points?",
        "answer": "rook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which game usually begins with, \"Is it animal, vegetable, or mineral?\"",
        "answer": "twenty questions"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Although it doesn't sound like a dog, ----dust is ornamental wood chips often placed in flowerbeds.",
        "answer": "bark"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Chicago Transit Authority is now known as which group?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "If you drive on a parkway, you park on a -------?",
        "answer": "driveway"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "To refuel your car you go to a ----- station.",
        "answer": "petrol"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Wedding rings are normally worn on what finger of your hand?",
        "answer": "ring finger"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are catalogued under the Dewey decimal system?",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are the 3 big colleges of the Ivy League? (name them alphabetically)",
        "answer": "Harvard, Princeton, Yale"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What company makes Pampers disposable diapers?",
        "answer": "Proctor & Gamble"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the initials U.F.O stand for?",
        "answer": "Unidentified Flying Object"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the letters in SAM missiles refer to?",
        "answer": "Surface-to-Air Missile"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does IRS stand for?",
        "answer": "Internal Revenue Service"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does a compass needle point to?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the abbreviation a.m. stand for?",
        "answer": "Ante Meridian"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the acronym CIA stand for?",
        "answer": "Central Intelligence Agency"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the minimum IQ score for the genius category?",
        "answer": "one hundred and forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is this sign called \"&\"?",
        "answer": "ampersand"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "When using a telephone, you must wait for a ---- tone before starting your call.",
        "answer": "dial"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which U.S. president is on the five-dollar bill?",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Acadia was the original name of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgeport is the largest city in which state?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgetown is the capital of --------.",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Brussels is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Frankfort is the capital of which state?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Guayaquil is the largest city in what country?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Halifax is the capital of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Havana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He invented the most common projection for world maps.",
        "answer": "Gerardus Mercator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He visited Australia and New Zealand, then surveyed the Pacific Coast of North America.",
        "answer": "Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "How many stars are on the flag of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "If its 4:00pm in Seattle, Washington what time is it in Portland, Oregon?",
        "answer": "4:00pm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city are the famous Tivoli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Leaning Tower?",
        "answer": "Pisa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Smithsonian Institute?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Banff National Park?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Lahore?",
        "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Mandalay?",
        "answer": "Myanmar (formerly known as Burma)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Taipei?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Jutland peninsula?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Mekong River Delta?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Waterloo battlefield?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the highest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the lowest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the source of the Blue Nile?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what island group is Corregidor?",
        "answer": "Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what mountain range is Kicking Horse Pass?",
        "answer": "Rocky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what state is Concord?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Red Square?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Saint Paul's Cathedral?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Wembley Stadium?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Bridge of Sighs?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Canale Grande?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Colliseum located?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Wailing Wall?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Angel Falls?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Brest? (NOT Breast!)",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Chennai (formerly Madras)?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Cusco?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Loch Ness?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Normandy?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Sapporo?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Calabria region?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Dalai Lama's palace?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Great Victoria Desert?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Machu Picchu?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country would you find the Yucatan Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?",
        "answer": "Indian Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are Gettysburg and the Liberty Bell?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are the Finger Lakes?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Appomattax?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Cape Hatteras?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Hoover Dam?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount McKinley?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount St. Helens?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount Vernon?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Stone Mountain?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Walla Walla?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Kennedy Space Center?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Mayo Clinic?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Painted Desert?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what bay does the Ganges River flow?",
        "answer": "Bay Of Bengal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River flow?",
        "answer": "Black Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Yukon River flow?",
        "answer": "Bering Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe River flow?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Mackenzie River flow?",
        "answer": "Beaufort Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kingston is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Linz, Austria is a leading port on which river?",
        "answer": "Danube"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Madrid and Lisbon are both located near this river.",
        "answer": "Tagus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Meridians converge at the --------.",
        "answer": "poles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Mount Victoria is the highest peak of this island country.",
        "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name a country which has the same name as a bird.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the U.S. state with the smallest population.",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Massachusetts.",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Rhode Island.",
        "answer": "Providence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Argentina.",
        "answer": "Buenos Aires"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Brazil.",
        "answer": "Brasilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Italy.",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the city at the west end of Lake Superior.",
        "answer": "Duluth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the continent that consists of a single country.",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the desert located in south-east California.",
        "answer": "Mojave"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the large mountain chain in the eastern U.S.A.",
        "answer": "The Appalachians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest cathedral in the world.",
        "answer": "St. Peter's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest city in Canada.",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest island in the world.",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest lake in Australia.",
        "answer": "Eyre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest river forming part of the U.S. - Mexican border.",
        "answer": "Rio Grande"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the last province to become part of Canada.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Asia.",
        "answer": "Yangtze"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Nigeria.",
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the most north-easterly of the 48 contiguous states.",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the only Central American country without an Atlantic coastline.",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Asia Minor and Greece.",
        "answer": "Aegean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Korea and China.",
        "answer": "Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Beaufort"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Murmansk, Russia.",
        "answer": "Barents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea west of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Bering"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in Africa.",
        "answer": "Algeria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in South America.",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest lake in North America.",
        "answer": "Huron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the smallest of the Great Lakes.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the strait joining the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean Sea.",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the world's most photographed and most climbed mountain.",
        "answer": "Fuji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Nassau is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Bahamas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Honolulu?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Pearl Harbour?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the Blue Grotto?",
        "answer": "Capri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the U.S. naval base, Guantanamo?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what mountain are four presidents' faces carved?",
        "answer": "Rushmore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what peninsula are Spain and Portugal located?",
        "answer": "The Iberian peninsula"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what river is the capital city of Canada?",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is London, England?",
        "answer": "Thames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is Rome located?",
        "answer": "Tiber"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is the Aswan High Dam?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Over 75% of the Earth's surface is covered by some form of -----.",
        "answer": "Water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Rabat is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "San Francisco Bay is located near what city?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Seoul is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "St. George's is the capital city of what island country?",
        "answer": "Grenada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Surfing is believed to have originated here.",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Auckland Islands belong to which country?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Hebrides are part of this country.",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Ionian and Cyclades are island groups of which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Little Mermaid is found in the harbour of which city?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Nationalist Chinese occupy this island.",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Thatcher Ferry Bridge crosses what canal?",
        "answer": "Panama Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The United States is made up of -- states.",
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Volta is the largest river in which country?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called --------.",
        "answer": "Benelux"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The longest river in Western Europe is ---------?",
        "answer": "Rhine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The sun sets in the ----?",
        "answer": "west"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Canadian island is the world's fifth largest.",
        "answer": "Baffin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Pacific island's puzzling monoliths attract ethnologists.",
        "answer": "Easter Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country is divided at the 38th parallel.",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country occupies the \"horn of Africa\".",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country's flag has a large \"R\" on it.",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This imaginary line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean.",
        "answer": "international date line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is called the \"Honeymoon Capital\" of the world.",
        "answer": "Niagara Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the bridge with the longest span in the U.S.A.",
        "answer": "Verrazano Narrows"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the only borough of New York City that is not on an island.",
        "answer": "The Bronx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the port city serving Tokyo.",
        "answer": "Yokohama"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the residence of English monarchs.",
        "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This island group is off the east coast of southern South America.",
        "answer": "Falkland Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This re-opened in 1975 after being closed for 8 years.",
        "answer": "Suez Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This section of Manhattan is noted for its Negro and Latin American residents.",
        "answer": "Harlem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country do the Faeroe Islands belong?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country does the Gaza Strip belong?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  The Easter Bunny is from Easter Island.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  There are only virgins on the Virgin Islands.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Under what river does the Holland Tunnel run?",
        "answer": "Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What American city is known as Little Havana?",
        "answer": "Miami"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Asian city was once called Edo?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Canadian city is at the west end of Lake Ontario?",
        "answer": "Hamilton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country administers the island of Martinique?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country has \"Vaduz\" as its capital city?",
        "answer": "Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What London borough does the Prime Meridian pass through?",
        "answer": "Greenwich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is known as Insurance City?",
        "answer": "Hartford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. state is known as The Land of 10,000 Lakes?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What US state is completely surrounded by the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are drumlins and eskers formed by?",
        "answer": "glaciers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are the worlds four oceans - alphabetically?",
        "answer": "Arctic, Atlantic, Indian and Pacific"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What body of water borders Saudi Arabia to the east?",
        "answer": "Persian Gulf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What canal connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie?",
        "answer": "Welland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city boasts the Copacabana Beach and Ipanema?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is associated with Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is on Lake Erie at the mouth of the Cuyahoga River?",
        "answer": "Cleveland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Christian Science Monitor based in?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Kremlin located in?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city was the setting for \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What color does the bride wear in China?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is Cyprus considered to be part of?",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is the home to the greatest number of countries?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country are the Islands of Quemoy and Matsu part of?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt on the west?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country does the island of Mykonos belong to?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country formed the union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country has the world's most southerly city?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Phnom Penh the capital of?",
        "answer": "Cambodia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Santo Domingo the capital of?",
        "answer": "Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of Israel?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of the continental United States?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly west of Spain?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is known as the Hellenic Republic?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is located between Panama and Nicaragua?",
        "answer": "Costa Rica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country owns the island of Corfu?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was once known as Gaul?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Casablanca\"?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Doctor Zhivago\"?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What famous geyser erupts regularly at the Yellowstone National Park?",
        "answer": "Old Faithful"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Alaska?",
        "answer": "Juneau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Bangladesh?",
        "answer": "Dacca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Burma?",
        "answer": "Rangoon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Chile?",
        "answer": "Santiago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Colorado?",
        "answer": "Denver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Florida?",
        "answer": "Tallahassee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of India?",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Indonesia?",
        "answer": "Jakarta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Maine?",
        "answer": "Augusta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nebraska",
        "answer": "Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Wellington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Washington state?",
        "answer": "Olympia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of West Virginia?",
        "answer": "Charleston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Madison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?",
        "answer": "Harare"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of the United Arab Emirates?",
        "answer": "Abu Dhabi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the current name for south-west Africa?",
        "answer": "Namibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in Canada?",
        "answer": "Mt. Logan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in Australia, in terms of population?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in China?",
        "answer": "Shanghai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest of the countries in Central America?",
        "answer": "Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the monetary unit of India?",
        "answer": "Rupee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the most sacred river in India?",
        "answer": "Ganges"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?",
        "answer": "Arabic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the principal river of Ireland?",
        "answer": "Shannon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest of the United States?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest independent state in the world?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest of the Central American countries?",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's highest city?",
        "answer": "Lhasa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island has Hamilton as its capital?",
        "answer": "Bermuda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island is known as the Spice Island?",
        "answer": "Zanzibar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
        "answer": "Ural"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What prison island was off the coast of French Guiana?",
        "answer": "Devil's Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river has the largest drainage basin?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is Liverpool on?",
        "answer": "Mersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is called \"Old Man River\"?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is known as China's Sorrow?",
        "answer": "Yellow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is the Temple of Karnak near?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What sea is between Italy and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Adriatic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What south American country has both a Pacific and Atlantic coastline?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state is the Golden State?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state was the home to Mayberry?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What symbol is on the flag of Vietnam?",
        "answer": "star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What unit of currency will buy you dinner in Iraq, Jordan, Tunisia, and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Dinar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What volcano showers ash on Sicily?",
        "answer": "Etna"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the former name of Istanbul?",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the highest mountain in the 48 contiguous U.S. states?",
        "answer": "Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the Nazca Lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the pyramids located?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Beacon Street?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Euston Station?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is George Washington buried?",
        "answer": "Mt. Vernon, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Westminster Abbey located?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Admirality Arch?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Holy Kaaba?",
        "answer": "Mecca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Parthenon located?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the city of Brotherly Love?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Canadian province extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Central American country extends furthest north?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the highest population density?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the lowest population density?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Irish city is famous for its crystal?",
        "answer": "Waterford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as Beantown?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the Biggest Little City in the World?",
        "answer": "Reno"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state borders a Canadian territory?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the least rainfall?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state receives the most rainfall?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which capital is known as the Glass Capital of the World?",
        "answer": "Toledo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city has the largest rodeo in the world?",
        "answer": "Calgary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as Motown?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as the Windy City?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is on the east side of San Francisco Bay?",
        "answer": "Oakland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country administers Christmas Island?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country are the Galapagos Islands part of?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country borders Italy, Switzerland, West Germany, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, and Liechtenstein?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country developed \"Tae-Kwan-Do\"?",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Ankara as its capital?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has the longest land border?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country hosted the 1982 World Cup of soccer?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country uses the \"yen\" for currency?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country would come first in an alphabetical list of countries?",
        "answer": "Afghanistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which islands were named after Prince Philip of Spain?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which mainland Latin American country is in neither South America nor Central America?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the U.S. states borders only one other state?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which river contains the most fresh water?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state has the most hospitals?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is divided into two parts by a large lake?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Evergreen State?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Garden State?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Wolverine State?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With what country is Fidel Castro associated?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With which country is Prince Rainier III identified?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geogrpahy",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Utah.",
        "answer": "Salt Lake City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Earth's outer layer of surface soil or crust is called the -------.",
        "answer": "Lithosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Peat, lignite and bituminous are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "coal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Slate is formed by the metamorphosis of ---------.",
        "answer": "shale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The green variety of beryl is called --------.",
        "answer": "emerald"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The molten material from a volcano is --------?",
        "answer": "lava"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The spot on the Earth's surface directly above an earthquake's focus is called the ------.",
        "answer": "epicenter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The violet variety of quartz is called --------.",
        "answer": "amethyst"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "There are three types of rocks: metamorphic, sedimentary, and ---------.",
        "answer": "igneous"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "These limestone deposits rise from the floor of caves.",
        "answer": "stalagmites"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "This is the hardest naturally occurring substance.",
        "answer": "diamond"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What name is used to describe permanently-frozen subsoil?",
        "answer": "permafrost"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hahaha",
        "question": "This normally has 4 legs and your butt is parked in it right now.",
        "answer": "chair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hirtory",
        "question": "Name the first black nation to gain freedom from European colonial rule.",
        "answer": "Haiti"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Britain and Argentina fought over these islands in 1982.",
        "answer": "Falklands Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Canadian Prime Minister: Pierre Elliott ----------.",
        "answer": "Trudeau"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Churchill, F.D. Roosvelt and Stalin met here in 1945.",
        "answer": "Yalta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Eras are divided into units called --------.",
        "answer": "periods"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "For what country did Columbus make his historic voyage?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Four Japanese carriers were destroyed in this battle.",
        "answer": "Midway"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Frankish ruler Charles the Great is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "Charlemagne"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "From what country did the U.S. buy the Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "General Sherman burned this city in 1864.",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's WW I allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and --------.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's allies in WW II were Japan, Italy, Hungary, Bulgaria, Finland, Libya, and ---------.",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He allowed the bugging of the Democratic Committee headquarters.",
        "answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He discovered the Grand Canyon.",
        "answer": "Francisco Coronado"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is identified with the expression, \"Eureka\".",
        "answer": "Archimedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is said to have fiddled while Rome burned.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He led 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1979.",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He ordered the persecution of Christians in which Peter and Paul died.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964 for his civil rights leadership.",
        "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He said, \"I have nothing to offer but blood, tears, toil and sweat.\"",
        "answer": "Sir Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He shot Lee Harvey Oswald.",
        "answer": "Jack Ruby"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He taught Alexander the Great.",
        "answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Dec. 8, 1980 in New York City.",
        "answer": "John Lennon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Nov. 22, 1963.",
        "answer": "John Fitzgerald Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn.",
        "answer": "General Custer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was stabbed by Gaius Cassius Longinus.",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the American inventor of the Cotton Gin.",
        "answer": "Eli Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the U.S. president during the Civil War.",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His ship was the H.M.S. Beagle.",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His wife was Roxana. His horse was Bacephalus. He was --------.",
        "answer": "Alexander the Great"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How do you write 69 in Roman numerals?",
        "answer": "LXIX"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many astronauts manned each Apollo flight?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How old was John F. Kennedy when he became president?",
        "answer": "forty three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In 1902 this volcano erupted, killing 30,000.",
        "answer": "Pelee"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In what country did \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city was President Kennedy killed?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city were the Hanging Gardens?",
        "answer": "Babylon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country did the Boxer Rebellion take place?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was Adolf Hitler born?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the Golan Heights.  Whose territory was it?",
        "answer": "Syria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the West Bank.  It belonged to -------.",
        "answer": "Jordan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport in New York used to be called ----------.",
        "answer": "Idlewind"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Mussolini invaded this country in 1935.",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name Jacques Cousteau's research ship.",
        "answer": "Calypso"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name the incident in which tea was dumped into the harbour.",
        "answer": "Boston Tea Party"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "One who fought professionally in Roman arenas was a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "Gladiator"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She overcame her handicaps to become a lecturer and a scholar.",
        "answer": "Helen Keller"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was Queen of Egypt and mistress of Julius Caesar.",
        "answer": "Cleopatra"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was called \"The Maid of Orleans\".",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first First Lady to be received privately by the Pope.",
        "answer": "Jackie Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman premier of Israel.",
        "answer": "Golda Meir"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to fly the Atlantic solo.",
        "answer": "Amelia Earhart"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to swim the English channel.",
        "answer": "Gertrude Caroline Ederle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the greatest trick shot artist of all time.",
        "answer": "Annie Oakley"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She won the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her work among the poor.",
        "answer": "Mother Teresa"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Spain ceded Florida to Britain in exchange for this territory.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The \"Bay of Pigs\" fiasco took place in this country.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Devonian Period is also known as the Age of ----------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Inquisition forced him to recant his belief in the Copernican Theory.",
        "answer": "Galileo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Romans built these to convey water.",
        "answer": "aqueducts"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The St. Valentine's Day massacre took place in this city.",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The first dog in space was named ---------.",
        "answer": "Laika"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The last line of this document is \"Working men of all countries, unite.\"",
        "answer": "Communist Manifesto"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This F.B.I agent headed the investigation of Al Capone.",
        "answer": "Elliot Ness"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This French peasant girl led the army to victories.",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Indian group ruled in early Peru.",
        "answer": "Inca"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Nazi leader had his six children poisoned prior to his own death.",
        "answer": "Joseph Goebbels"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Queen of France was beheaded in 1793.",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Roman killed himself after his defeat at Actium.",
        "answer": "Marc Antony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Sioux Indian toured with Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show.",
        "answer": "Sitting Bull"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Spaniard conquered Mexico.",
        "answer": "Hernando Cortez"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. Secretary of State won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973.",
        "answer": "Henry Kissinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. president was fatally shot in 1881.",
        "answer": "James Garfield"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This assassin of Julius Caesar was his friend.",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This frontiersman and politician was killed at the Alamo.",
        "answer": "Davy Crockett"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This is said to be history's greatest military evacuation.",
        "answer": "Dunkirk"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This military attack took place on Dec. 7, 1941.",
        "answer": "Pearl Harbour"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This organization was founded by William Booth.",
        "answer": "Salvation Army"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This racist organization was formed in Tennessee in 1865.",
        "answer": "Ku Klux Klan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This war began on June 25, 1950.",
        "answer": "Korean"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This was the largest real estate deal in U.S. history.",
        "answer": "Louisiana Purchase"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This word describes the Nazi annihilation of Jews.",
        "answer": "holocaust"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Those big black CD's that you see at garage sales that people call \"albums\" are made of -----.",
        "answer": "vinyl"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Two 747's collided here in 1977.",
        "answer": "Canary Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Chester Alan --------.",
        "answer": "Arthur"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Herbert C. ---------.",
        "answer": "Hoover"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, John Quincy --------.",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President: Calvin ---------.",
        "answer": "Coolidge"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What American feminist went bust as a silver dollar?",
        "answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What Chinese dynasty was overthrown in 1911?",
        "answer": "Manchu"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What age preceded the Iron Age?",
        "answer": "The Bronze Age"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did President J. Buchanan not have?",
        "answer": "A wife"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did presidents Madison, Monroe, Polk, and Garfield have in common?",
        "answer": "The first name \"James\""
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What group landed in America in 1620?",
        "answer": "The Pilgrims"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the Roman numeral for fifty?",
        "answer": "L"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the name of the Russian Czar's daughter who might-or might not-have survived the Russian revolution?",
        "answer": "Anastasia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What volcano destroyed Pompeii?",
        "answer": "Vesuvius"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the instrument of execution during the \"Reign of Terror\"?",
        "answer": "guillotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of Plato's school?",
        "answer": "Academy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of the B-29 used at Hiroshima to drop the bomb?",
        "answer": "Enola Gay"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the nationality of the prisoners in the \"Black hole of Calcutta\"?",
        "answer": "British"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the third country to get the \"bomb\"?",
        "answer": "Britain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What's the resting place of those buried at sea?",
        "answer": "Davey Jones's Locker"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which U.S. president said, \"The buck stops here\"?",
        "answer": "Truman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which military battle took place in 1815?",
        "answer": "Waterloo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nation was led by Genghis Khan?",
        "answer": "The Mongols"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which president was responsible for the Louisiana Purchase?",
        "answer": "Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is \"The Iron Lady\"?",
        "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led the attack on the Alamo?",
        "answer": "Santa Ana"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who rode naked through the streets of Coventry?",
        "answer": "Lady Godiva"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said \"Veni, vidi, vici\" (I came, I saw, I conquered)?",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said: \"Let them eat cake\"?",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who sang Happy Birthday to John F. Kennedy for his 45th?",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who succeeded Churchill when he resigned in 1955?",
        "answer": "Sir Anthony Eden"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was \"The Mad Monk\"?",
        "answer": "Rasputin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was George Washington's vice-president?",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first chancellor of West Germany after WW II?",
        "answer": "Konrad Adenauer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?",
        "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was, \"First in war, first in peace and first in the hearts of his countrymen\"?",
        "answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "What three letters are overly used to indicate \"Laugh Out Loud\"?",
        "answer": "lol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Langauge",
        "question": "Many Meanings:  Fuel, vapor, flattulence, helium.  What is it?",
        "answer": "gas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Drinking utensils or sight-enhancers.",
        "answer": "glasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Slamming your hands together quickly, or a venereal disease.",
        "answer": "clap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Name the soda that is often confused with a drug.",
        "answer": "Coke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Subject, verb and object are parts of a ---------.",
        "answer": "sentence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "This animal is found at the beginning of an (English) encyclopedia",
        "answer": "aardvark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the only English word formed by the first three letters of the alphabet?",
        "answer": "cab"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What three letter word means the same as \"to ingest\"?",
        "answer": "eat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "\"faux pas\" means -----------.",
        "answer": "mistake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "Mardi Gras is French for -----------.",
        "answer": "fat tuesday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name Australia is derived from the Latin word \"australis\" which means -------.",
        "answer": "southern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name for this semi-precious stone comes from the Latin for \"sea water\"",
        "answer": "aquamarine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----hood; ----hole; ----date.",
        "answer": "man"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----stream; ----hill; -----pour.",
        "answer": "down"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What does \"c'est la vie\" mean?",
        "answer": "that's life"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What word contains the combination of letters: \"xop\"?",
        "answer": "saXOPhone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "\"The Diary of Anne Frank\" was first published in English under what title?",
        "answer": "The Diary of a Young Girl"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Captain Hook, Tiger Lily, and Tinker Bell are characters in what story?",
        "answer": "Peter Pan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Dr. Seuss wrote this book: The Cat in the ------.",
        "answer": "Hat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Edgar Allen Poe wrote a famous poem about this animal.",
        "answer": "raven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Double, double ... \"",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Goodnight, goodnight! Parting is such sweet sorrow, That I should say goodnight till it be morrow.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"To be or not to be?\"",
        "answer": "Hamlet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"What in a name? That which we call a rose, by any other name would smell as sweet.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many lines are in a sonnet?",
        "answer": "fourteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many plays is Shakespeare generally credited with today?",
        "answer": "thirty seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Name the Shakespeare play from this ultra short plot summary: Urged on by his wife, a man murders his king in order to take his place.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Pet --------\".",
        "answer": "Semetary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Salem's ---------\".",
        "answer": "Lot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"The Dead --------\".",
        "answer": "Zone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This Shakespearean king was the actual king of Scotland for 17 years.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This girl hid from the Nazis in Amsterdam.",
        "answer": "Anne Frank"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What Shakespearean play features the line: A plague on both your houses?",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What did Jeannie C. Riley describe as \"a little Peyton Place\"?",
        "answer": "Harper Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What other name does Stephen King write under?",
        "answer": "Richard Bachman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What publication was subtitled The What's New Magazine?",
        "answer": "Popular Science"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What was the name of Mother Goose's son?",
        "answer": "Jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What's Penthouse's sister publication for women?",
        "answer": "Viva"
    },
    {
        "category": "Litterature",
        "question": "Homer wrote this account of the Trojan War.",
        "answer": "Iliad"
    },
    {
        "category": "Logic",
        "question": "You are in a room where all walls face south.  A bear walks by.  What color is it?",
        "answer": "White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A U.S. dime is worth --- cents.",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A line drawn from an angle of a triangle to the mid-point of the opposite side is a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "median"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with three equal sides is called -------.",
        "answer": "equilateral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with two equal sides is called ----------.",
        "answer": "isosceles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 180 degrees and less than 360 degrees is a(n) -------- angle.",
        "answer": "reflex"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees is said to be ---------.",
        "answer": "obtuse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An integer that is greater than 1 and is divisible only by itself and 1 is known as a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "prime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Approximately how many inches are there in one meter?",
        "answer": "thirty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Arc, radius, and sector are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "He is known as \"The Father of Geometry\".",
        "answer": "Euclid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many corners are there in a cube?",
        "answer": "eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many nickles are there in 2.25?",
        "answer": "forty five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "If you cut through a solid sphere what shape will the flat area be?",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Name the number system which uses only the symbols 1 and 0.",
        "answer": "The binary system"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The angles inside a square total ------- degrees.",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The mathematical study of properties of lines, angels, etc., is --------.",
        "answer": "geometry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The space occupied by a body is called its ------.",
        "answer": "volume"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The square root of 1 is?",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Two angles that total 180 degrees are called -------.",
        "answer": "supplementary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What geometric shape has 4 equal sides?",
        "answer": "square"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A baby doctor is a ---------.",
        "answer": "pediatrician"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A bone specialist is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "osteopath"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A loss of memory is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "amnesia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a --------.",
        "answer": "laxative"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A non-cancerous tumor is said to be -------.",
        "answer": "benign"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A thread used in surgery to tie a bleeding blood vessel is called a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "ligature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Carditis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "heart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Doctors often have this instrument around their neck.",
        "answer": "stethoscope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Due to a lack of vitamin C, sailors used to contract this disease.",
        "answer": "scurvy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Encephalitis affects the --------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Gastritis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "stomach"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hammer, anvil, and stirrup are parts of the --------.",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "He discovered the process of vaccination for prevention of smallpox.",
        "answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hepatitis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "Liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?",
        "answer": "two hundred and six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many pints of blood does the average human have in his/her body?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In the field of psychiatry this term means self-love.",
        "answer": "narcissism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In what organ of the body is insulin produced?",
        "answer": "pancreas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a clear watery solution known as the \"aqueous humor\" found?",
        "answer": "eye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a pulmonary disease located?",
        "answer": "lung"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is your \"hypothalmus\" located?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Infantile Paralysis is commonly known as --------.",
        "answer": "polio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Meningitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Myositis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "muscles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the hardest substance in the human body.",
        "answer": "enamel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest artery in the human body.",
        "answer": "aorta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest gland in the human body.",
        "answer": "liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Osteomyelitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "bones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Peritonitis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "abdomen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Prosthetics deals with the making of ----------.",
        "answer": "artificial limbs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Tarsus, metatarsus, and phalanges are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "foot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The branch of medicine dealing with curing by operative procedures is --------.",
        "answer": "surgery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The lack of this element in the diet is a cause of goitre.",
        "answer": "iodine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The largest single organ of the human body is the --------.",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The medical name for the voice box is the ---------.",
        "answer": "larynx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The teeth used for biting or cutting are known as -------.",
        "answer": "incisors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These animals were once used to bleed the sick.",
        "answer": "leeches"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These attach muscles to bones or cartilage.",
        "answer": "tendons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This branch of medicine deals with old age and its diseases.",
        "answer": "geriatrics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This disease consists of a purposeless, continual growth of white blood cells.",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This fingerlike projection is attached to the large intestine.",
        "answer": "appendix"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This is known as \"The Royal Disease\".",
        "answer": "haemophilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This large bean-shaped lymph gland can expand and contract as needed.",
        "answer": "spleen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This membrane controls the amount of light entering the eye.",
        "answer": "iris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This organ is a small pouch that stores bile.",
        "answer": "gall bladder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This parasite lives in the intestines of man and animals.",
        "answer": "tapeworm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This small gland attached to the brain exerts a control over growth.",
        "answer": "pituitary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Ulna, radius, and clavicle are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "bone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What disease is also known as \"rubella\"?",
        "answer": "German measles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What hormone is produced by the adrenal glands?",
        "answer": "adrenaline"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is a skin specialist called?",
        "answer": "dermatologist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?",
        "answer": "parasite"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the biggest disqualifying factor for prospective astronauts?",
        "answer": "eyesight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the medical term for cancer of the blood?",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the name of the bone in the lower leg?",
        "answer": "tibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?",
        "answer": "lead poisoning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?",
        "answer": "big toe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where do you find the medulla oblongata?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where in the body is the tiniest human muscle?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Which disease is also known as \"Hansen's Disease\"?",
        "answer": "leprosy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "With what body part is otology involved?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "If the groundhog sees his shadow on Feb. 2, there will be how many more weeks of bad weather?",
        "answer": "six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "This dry, warm wind flows eastward down the slopes of the Rocky Mountains.",
        "answer": "Chinook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ------- Borgnine.",
        "answer": "Ernest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: -------- Hackman.",
        "answer": "Gene"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Nimoy.",
        "answer": "Leonard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Savalas.",
        "answer": "Telly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what protruded from the rocks?",
        "answer": "Statue of Liberty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Barbara Streisand was the female lead in \"Hello, Dolly\".  Who was the male lead?",
        "answer": "Walter Matthau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Laughton played Quasimodo in this epic film.",
        "answer": "Hunchback of Notre Dame"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Darth Vader was the villan in the movie, \"---- Wars\".",
        "answer": "Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: An Officer and a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Gentleman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: Fahrenheit --------. (a number)",
        "answer": "451"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: The Last Days of ---------. (a city)",
        "answer": "Pompeii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: ------ (a number) Leagues Under the Sea.",
        "answer": "20,000"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Forrest ---- liked shrimp.",
        "answer": "Gump"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed \"The Godfather\".",
        "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed the movie E.T.",
        "answer": "Stephen Spielberg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He played Superman in the 1978 movie version.",
        "answer": "Christopher Reeve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in \"Conan the Barbarian\".",
        "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in, \"City Lights\".",
        "answer": "Charlie Chaplin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was known as the \"Elephant Man\".",
        "answer": "Joseph Merrick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was the villain in \"Star Wars\".",
        "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Giant, Written on the Wind, and A Farewell to Arms.",
        "answer": "Rock Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Spartacus, The Vikings, and Ulysses.",
        "answer": "Kirk Douglas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In \"Gone With the Wind\", Scarlett regains her wealth by investing in what type of business?",
        "answer": "sawmill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In 1975 Jack Nicholson won the best actor Oscar for his role in this film.",
        "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the 1996 version of \"Romeo and Juliet\", who played Juliet?",
        "answer": "Claire Danes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film \"Bright Eyes\", Shirley Temple sang about this boat.",
        "answer": "The Good Ship Lollipop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In this 1968 film the husband of an unsuspecting young wife becomes involved with a witch's coven.",
        "answer": "Rosemary's Baby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which Disney movie is the song \"So This Is Love\"?",
        "answer": "Cinderella"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the Disney cartoon in which the character \"Belle\" appears.",
        "answer": "Beauty and the Beast"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the actor who played the leading role in \"The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly\".",
        "answer": "Clint Eastwood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the first full length color cartoon talking picture.",
        "answer": "Snow White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the musical film named after a state.",
        "answer": "Oklahoma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Nick Nolte and Eddie Murphy star in this 1982 film.",
        "answer": "48 Hours"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Peter Sellers is best known for his role as Inspector ---------.",
        "answer": "Clouseau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played Lois Lane in the 1978 film version of \"Superman\".",
        "answer": "Margot Kidder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played a Polish refugee in \"Sophie's Choice\".",
        "answer": "Meryl Streep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played the lead role in \"Coal Miner's Daughter\".",
        "answer": "Sissy Spacek"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She starred in the 1952 film, \"Niagara\".",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The first 18 minutes of this movie is black and white.",
        "answer": "Wizard of Oz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical play?",
        "answer": "Fiddler On The Roof"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The two rival gangs in \"West Side Story\" were the Sharks and the ---------.",
        "answer": "Jets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This 1974 film started a run of nostalgia culminating in the TV series \"Happy Days\".",
        "answer": "American Graffiti"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This Disney movie relies heavily on computer animation.",
        "answer": "TRON"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This actress appeared in \"St. Elmo's Fire\", \"The Scarlett Letter\", and \"Striptease\".",
        "answer": "Demi Moore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This actress was Miss Hungary of 1936.",
        "answer": "Zsa-Zsa Gabor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film starring Julie Andrews and Christopher Plummer wont he best picture Oscar for 1965.",
        "answer": "Sound of Music"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film starring Richard Beymer and Natalie Wood won the best picture Oscar for 1961.",
        "answer": "West Side Story"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film was an ambitious concert sequence of cartoons by Walt Disney.",
        "answer": "Fantasia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This is a classic film about a huge gorilla.",
        "answer": "King Kong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This magic word was in the movie, \"Mary Poppins\".",
        "answer": "Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie directed by Woody Allen won the best picture Oscar in 1978.",
        "answer": "Annie Hall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie is about the migration of poor workers from the dust bowl to the Californian fruit valleys.",
        "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie starring Marlon Brando won the best picture award in 1972.",
        "answer": "The Godfather"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the first 3-D film.",
        "answer": "Bwana Devil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the first cartoon talking picture.",
        "answer": "Steamboat Willie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the sequel to \"Star Wars\".",
        "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the sequel to \"The Empire Strikes Back\".",
        "answer": "Return of the Jedi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actor appeared in all three of these films, Straw Dogs, Midnight Cowboy, and The Graduate?",
        "answer": "Dustin Hoffman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actress has received the most Oscar nominations?",
        "answer": "Katherine Hepburn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actress's real name was Frances Gumm?",
        "answer": "Judy Garland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What city's police force did Charlie Chan work with?",
        "answer": "Honolulu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What color was Bullitt's car?",
        "answer": "Green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"The King and I\"?",
        "answer": "Siam (Thailand)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What detective duo was featured in Mystery at Devil's Paw?",
        "answer": "Hardy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What does the statue of Oscar stand on?",
        "answer": "A Reel of Film"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What famous animal character called \"Skull Island\" home?",
        "answer": "King Kong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?",
        "answer": "True Grit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is Hawkeye's full name in M.A.S.H.?",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin Pierce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the destination of the plane at the end of the film \"Casablanca\"?",
        "answer": "Lisbon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Pearce Brosnan's first James Bond film?",
        "answer": "Goldeneye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the Volkswagen in the film, \"The Love Bug\"?",
        "answer": "Herbie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the film, \"Bambi\"?",
        "answer": "Thumper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the skunk in the film, \"Bambi\"?",
        "answer": "Flower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the whale that swallowed Pinocchio.",
        "answer": "Monstro"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the stage name of Greta Gustafson?",
        "answer": "Greta Garbo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the title of the 1996 sequel to \"Terms of Endearment\"?",
        "answer": "Morning Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What kind of creature was Chewbacca in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Wookiee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What two words are normally at the end of most movies?",
        "answer": "The End"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was \"Rocky's\" last name?",
        "answer": "Balboa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Citizen Kane's dying word?",
        "answer": "Rosebud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Dorothy's last name in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Gale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Rocky's nickname in the ring?",
        "answer": "The Italian Stallion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Sir Alec Guinness's role in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Obi-Wan Kenobi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first film directed by Robert Redford?",
        "answer": "Ordinary People"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Ashley Wilkes' plantation in \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Twelve Oaks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Han Solo's spaceship in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Millennium Falcon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Luke's strange little advisor in \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?",
        "answer": "Yoda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the motel in the film \"Psycho\"?",
        "answer": "Bates Motel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the setting for \"The Sound of Music\"?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which actor said, \"Love means never having to say you're sorry\"?",
        "answer": "Ryan O'Neil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character in \"Forrest Gump\" loved shrimp?",
        "answer": "Bubba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character sang \"Come Out, Come Out, Wherever You Are\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Glinda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character sang, \"When you wish upon a star..\" in Disney's \"Pinocchio\"?",
        "answer": "Jiminy Cricket"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which comedy duo did the famous, \"Who's on first?\" routine?",
        "answer": "Abbott and Costello"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which planet was the \"Planet of the Apes\"?",
        "answer": "Earth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who co-starred with Julie Andrews in \"Mary Poppins\"?",
        "answer": "Dick Van Dyke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?",
        "answer": "Ellen Degeneres"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Warren Beatty's sister?",
        "answer": "Shirley MacLaine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the fastest mouse in all of Mexico?",
        "answer": "Speedy Gonzalez"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the male lead in the \"Naked Gun\" movies?",
        "answer": "Leslie Nielsen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the voice of Darth Vadar?",
        "answer": "James Earl Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played \"Robin\" to Val Kilmer's \"Batman\"?",
        "answer": "Christopher O'Donnell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Brad Pitt's cop partner in the movie \"Seven\"?",
        "answer": "Morgan Freeman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Dorothy in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Judy Garland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Garth in \"Wayne's World\"?",
        "answer": "Dana Carvey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Matt Helm in the movies?",
        "answer": "Dean Martin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Scarlette O'Hara in \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Vivien Leigh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the 'Wicked Witch of the West' in \"The Wizard of Oz\"",
        "answer": "Margaret Hamilton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the role of Richard Blaine in Casablanca?",
        "answer": "Humphrey Bogart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who plays the character of the only escapee from Alcatraz in the movie \"The Rock\"?",
        "answer": "Sean Connery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who portrayed Han Solo in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Harrison Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who portrayed Moses in \"The Ten Commandments\"?",
        "answer": "Charlton Heston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who produced, directed and starred in \"Citizen Kane\"?",
        "answer": "Orson Welles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred with John Travolta in the movie \"Broken Arrow\"?",
        "answer": "Christian Slater"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was C3PO's sidekick in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "R2D2"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "\"He's So Fine\", \"One Fine Day\" and \"A Love So Fine\" where hits for what fine group?",
        "answer": "The Chiffons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "\"Joy to the World\" was a hit in 1971 for what band with three lead vocalists?",
        "answer": "Three Dog Night"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Besides \"Auld Lang Syne\" and \"For He's a Jolly Good Fellow\", what is the most frequently sung song in English?",
        "answer": "Happy Birthday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Fifties rock \"n\" roll was revived by what greased hair, T-shirted, TV frequenting group?",
        "answer": "Sha Na Na"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Jerry Lee Lewis had Great ----- Of Fire.",
        "answer": "balls!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Name Jerry Garcia's long lived group.",
        "answer": "The Grateful Dead"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "The Who's rock musical stars Elton John.  It's called --------.",
        "answer": "Tommy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "This female artist enjoyed sucess on both popular and country & western stations with such tunes as \"Let Me Be There\" and \"Have You Never Been Mellow.\"",
        "answer": "Olivia Newton-John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "This was the Beatle's first film.",
        "answer": "A Hard Day's Night"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Through 1963 this duo's total record sales exceeded 18 million with successes including \"Cathy's Clown\" and \"Wake Up Little Suzie\".",
        "answer": "The Everly Brothers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What Procol Harem tune was based on the Bach cantata \"Sleepers Awake\"?",
        "answer": "A Whiter Shade of Pale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What band recorded the 1978 hit album: \"Briefcase Full of Blues\"?",
        "answer": "The Blues Brothers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What city is also known as Music City, U.S.A.?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What country singer/songwriter (and sometimes actor) is known as \"the country outlaw\"?",
        "answer": "Willie Nelson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What entertainer is allowing one of his songs to be used in a government campaign to beat drunk driving?",
        "answer": "Michael Jackson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What famous classical composer continued to compose great music after becoming deaf?",
        "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What famous singer was known to give automobiles to complete strangers?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What group refused to have their pictures taken while they were not in their makeup?",
        "answer": "Kiss"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What group's biggest-ever hit was Be My Baby?",
        "answer": "The Ronettes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song by Don McLean talks about the day Buddy Holly died?",
        "answer": "American Pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song did Aretha Franklin sing in \"The Blues Brothers\"?",
        "answer": "Think"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was Elvis Presley's wife's name?",
        "answer": "Priscilla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was The Beatles' biggest hit single?",
        "answer": "Hey Jude"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What's the name of B.B. King's guitar?",
        "answer": "Lucille"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which of Paul Simon's musical characters was told to hop on the bus?",
        "answer": "Gus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who invented the electrical bass?",
        "answer": "Leo Fender"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who recorded the 1957 hit \"Tammy\"?",
        "answer": "Debby Reynolds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who recorded the lengthy song: \"In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida\" in 1969?",
        "answer": "Iron Butterfly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the first singer in Genesis?",
        "answer": "Peter Gabriel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Whose theme song was Back In The Saddle Again?",
        "answer": "Gene Autry's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "The sea gods had a three-pronged spear called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "trident"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "This Greek mountain was known as the home of the gods.",
        "answer": "Olympus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "What has no reflection, no shadow, and can't stand the smell of garlic?",
        "answer": "vampire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "What's heaven to fallen Norse warriors?",
        "answer": "Valhalla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Where did Robin Hood supposedly live?",
        "answer": "Sherwood Forest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Which ancient continent is said to be submerged?",
        "answer": "Atlantis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Natural History",
        "question": "Name the largest of the dinosaurs.",
        "answer": "brachiosaurus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Natural History",
        "question": "The remains of prehistoric organisms that have been preserved in rocks are called --------.",
        "answer": "fossils"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A \"sirocco\" refers to a type of ----------.",
        "answer": "wind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A calm ocean region near the equator.",
        "answer": "doldrums"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A coral island consisting of a ring of rock enclosing a central lagoon is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "atoll"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A great wave resulting from an earthquakes is called a (an) --------.",
        "answer": "tsunami"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A group of gorillas is known as a -----------.",
        "answer": "band"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A group of kangaroos is known as a -------.",
        "answer": "troop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A hot spring which shoots steam into the air is a -------.",
        "answer": "geyser"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A one-humped camel is called a ---------.",
        "answer": "dromedary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A relationship between two different types of organism which live together for their mutual benefit.",
        "answer": "symbiosis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A terrapin is a type of ---------.",
        "answer": "turtle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "An animal is a bird if it has -------.",
        "answer": "feathers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "An animal is a fish if it has ---------.",
        "answer": "gills"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Corolla, filament and stigma are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "flower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Dense sea-water swamps along coasts of hot countries are called --------.",
        "answer": "mangroves"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Dogs bark.  What do donkeys do?",
        "answer": "bray"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Excluding man, what is the longest-lived land mammal?",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Fandible, lateral line, and dorsal fin are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "From what animal is \"ambergis\" obtained?",
        "answer": "sperm whale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How man legs does a crab have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How many teats does a cow have?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How many tentacles does a squid have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Imperial, Buck, and Luna are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "moth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Knife, Clown, and Pencil are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Linseed oil is obtained from the seed of which plant?",
        "answer": "flax"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Maxillary palps, abdomen, and metathorax are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "insect"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the fastest land animal over a prolonged distance (1,000 yd. plus)",
        "answer": "antelope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the heaviest breed of domestic dog.",
        "answer": "St. Bernard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the heaviest flying bird of prey.",
        "answer": "condor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the largest living bird.",
        "answer": "ostrich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the largest web-footed bird.",
        "answer": "albatross"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the longest venomous snake.",
        "answer": "cobra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the mammal living at the highest altitude.",
        "answer": "yak"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the most venomous spider.",
        "answer": "black widow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the only native North American marsupial.",
        "answer": "opossum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the slowest moving land mammal.",
        "answer": "sloth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the smallest breed of dog.",
        "answer": "chihuahua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the wild dogs of Australia.",
        "answer": "dingo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Paper is made from the pulp of -----.",
        "answer": "wood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Snakes are reptiles.  What are frogs?",
        "answer": "amphibians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Some animals spend the winter in a sleep-like state known as ---------.",
        "answer": "hibernation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what?",
        "answer": "rattlesnake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The fins of which fish are made into a soup?",
        "answer": "shark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The four stages in the life-cycle of an insect are: egg, adult, pupa, and --------.",
        "answer": "larva"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The koala bear eats the leaves from this tree.",
        "answer": "eucalyptus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "These marine crustaceans often attach themselves to the hulls of ships.",
        "answer": "barnacles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This African animal kills the most people.",
        "answer": "crocodile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is armed with bony plates and rolls up into a ball if frightened.",
        "answer": "armadillo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is kept as a house pet to kill cobras.",
        "answer": "mongoose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is normally measured in \"hands\".",
        "answer": "horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is the symbol of the U.S. Democratic Party.",
        "answer": "donkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is the symbol of the U.S. Republican Party.",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal's name is the same as that given to a high church official.",
        "answer": "cardinal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal's shell is used to make attractive jewelry.",
        "answer": "abalone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This bird lays its eggs in the nests of other birds.",
        "answer": "cuckoo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the largest of the deer family.",
        "answer": "moose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the main food of the blue whale.",
        "answer": "plankton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the only mammal with four knees.",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This order of insects contains the most species.",
        "answer": "beetle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This organic gem is a deep red secretion from a marine animal.",
        "answer": "coral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This small animal is trained to hunt rats and rabbits.",
        "answer": "ferret"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This two ton animal can gallop at over 50 miles an hour.",
        "answer": "rhinoceros"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This ugly creature has patches of red on his rear-end.",
        "answer": "mandrill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Walrus tusks are made of --------.",
        "answer": "ivory"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What are the pouched animals called?",
        "answer": "marsupials"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What bird is an excellent swimmer, but can't fly?",
        "answer": "penguin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What does a camel store in its hump?",
        "answer": "fat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What fish is the fastest?",
        "answer": "sailfish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of larks called?",
        "answer": "exaltation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of peacocks called?",
        "answer": "muster"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of whales called?",
        "answer": "pod"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male goose called?",
        "answer": "gander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male swan called?",
        "answer": "cob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male swine called?",
        "answer": "boar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a young goose called?",
        "answer": "gosling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a young swan called?",
        "answer": "cygnet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is an emasculated stallion called?",
        "answer": "gelding"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is another term for a black leopard?",
        "answer": "panther"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the horn of a rhinoceros made of?",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the only dog that doesn't have a pink tongue?",
        "answer": "chow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the world's longest snake?",
        "answer": "python"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What large herbivore sleeps only one hour a night?",
        "answer": "antelope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What name is given to a female calf?",
        "answer": "heifer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What plant is opium derived from?",
        "answer": "poppy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What travels in gaggles?",
        "answer": "geese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What type of animal is a wallaby?",
        "answer": "marsupial"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What type of animal lives in a formicary?",
        "answer": "ant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a female fox?",
        "answer": "vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a female sheep?",
        "answer": "ewe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male ass? (Other than that the word used for that *-^*&%@! ex-boyfriend.)",
        "answer": "jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male deer?",
        "answer": "buck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male duck?",
        "answer": "drake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Neture",
        "question": "What do oak trees grow from?",
        "answer": "acorns"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "What would be kept in an \"aviary\"?",
        "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "Where is the Ocean of Storms located?",
        "answer": "On the moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "Who is Robert Zimmermann?",
        "answer": "Bob Dylan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-P",
        "question": "What are white dwarfs and red giants?",
        "answer": "stars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not telling ;-P",
        "question": "What are these: chrysolite, beryl, jasper, and tourmaline?",
        "answer": "gems"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Jack and Jill went up a ---- to fetch a pail of water?",
        "answer": "hill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Name the nursery rhyme mother whos last name is that of a bird?",
        "answer": "goose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The energy which a body possesses by virtue of its motion is called --------.",
        "answer": "kinetic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The pivot point of a lever is called the ---------.",
        "answer": "fulcrum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The process of water changing to water vapor is known as -------.",
        "answer": "evaporation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as ---------.",
        "answer": "acceleration"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The visible spectrum of light ranges from red to --------.",
        "answer": "violet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "True Or False: Contrary to popular belief, a lightbulb actually absorbs darkness?",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Two 1.5 volt batteries, when connected in series, produces _ volts.",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Water freezes at _ degrees Celcius.",
        "answer": "zero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Water freezes at -- degrees Fahrenheit.",
        "answer": "thirty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "What is measured by a Geiger counter?",
        "answer": "radioactivity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "When light waves pass from one medium into another they change direction.  This is called ---------.",
        "answer": "refraction"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Work done, equals force multiplied by --------.",
        "answer": "distance"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "For what does O.P.E.C. stand?",
        "answer": "The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "He was elected President of France, in 1981.",
        "answer": "Francios Mitterrand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Name Ronald Reagan's first wife.",
        "answer": "Wyman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Presidents",
        "question": "U.S. President, Woodrow ----------.",
        "answer": "Wilson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "How is the state of Mississippi spelled?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Name the circular plastic media you put in a CD-ROM drive.",
        "answer": "CD"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "On a standard computer keyboard, this is the letter just to the right of Z.",
        "answer": "x"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "The longest key on your keyboard is the ----- bar.",
        "answer": "space"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "The season ------ comes right after Spring.",
        "answer": "summer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "There are -- seconds in a minute.",
        "answer": "sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "This is required to make all electric things work?",
        "answer": "electricity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a blue crayon?",
        "answer": "blue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a green crayon?",
        "answer": "green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a red crayon?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What company makes Microsoft Windows 2000?",
        "answer": "microsoft"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Whats radar spelled backwards?",
        "answer": "radar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Whats the abbreviation for United States of America?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Where's my mirror? ;-",
        "question": "When spelled backwards, the word \"retupmoc\" becomes what?",
        "answer": "computer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Followers of the Unification Church are called --------.",
        "answer": "Moonies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He led the Israelites out of Egypt.",
        "answer": "Moses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He was the first King of the Hebrews.",
        "answer": "Saul"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He was the second King of Israel.",
        "answer": "David"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "In what month is Christmas observed?",
        "answer": "December"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Name the holiest day in the Jewish calendar.",
        "answer": "Yom Kippur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "On which mountain did Moses receive the Ten Commandments?",
        "answer": "Sinai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Which city is sacred to Jews, Christians, and Muslims?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Who founded Mormonism?",
        "answer": "Joseph Smith"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Who founded the People's Temple Commune?",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A flat-bottomed conical laboratory flask with a narrow neck is called a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "erlenmeyer flask"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A phrenologist reads ---------.",
        "answer": "skulls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A point to which rays of light converge is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "focus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A shallow dish with a cover, used for science specimens is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "petri dish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Acetylsalicylic acid is more commonly known as ---------.",
        "answer": "aspirin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Botany and Zoology combined make up the science of -------.",
        "answer": "biology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "By what chemical process do plants manufacture food?",
        "answer": "photosynthesis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "By what name is Lysergic acid diethylamide better known?",
        "answer": "LSD"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Cetology is the study of --------.",
        "answer": "whales"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Circuits can be wired in series or in ---------.",
        "answer": "parallel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Cocci, Spirilla, and Streptococci are types of --------.",
        "answer": "bacteria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Deoxyribonucleic acid is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "DNA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Dermatitis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Epidermal cells, palisade cells, and veins are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "leaf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Ethylene glycol is frequently used in automobiles.. How?",
        "answer": "anti-freeze"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Forked, Sheet, and Ball are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "lightning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Growing plants in liquids rather than soil is known as --------.",
        "answer": "hydroponics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He designed the first feasible automobile with an internal combustion engine.",
        "answer": "Karl Freidrich Benz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He invented \"bifocal\" lenses for eyeglasses.",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He is known for his theory of \"Evolution\".",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He transmitted radio signals across the Atlantic in 1901.",
        "answer": "Enrico Marconi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He wrote \"Sexual Behaviour in the Human Male\" in 1948.",
        "answer": "Alfred Kinsey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "How many degrees does the earth rotate each hour?",
        "answer": "fifteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "In which country was the match invented?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Nitrous oxide is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "laughing gas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Nuclear membrane, cytoplasm, and nucleus are parts of a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "cell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Pulp, crown, and root are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "tooth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Quinine is added to water to make -------.",
        "answer": "tonic water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Sound Navigation Ranging is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "sonar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The Kelvin scale is used to measure ---------.",
        "answer": "temperature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The filament of a regular light bulb is usually made of --------.",
        "answer": "tungsten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The instrument used in geometry to measure angles is a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "protractor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The name for the Russian equivalent of Skylab is --------.",
        "answer": "Salyut"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The second space shuttle was named ----------.",
        "answer": "Columbia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The vernal equinox is the beginning of --------.",
        "answer": "spring"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This Russian scientist used dogs to study conditioned reflexes.",
        "answer": "Ivan Pavlov"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This is like an airplane but has its propeller on top instead.",
        "answer": "helicopter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This is the reading system used by the blind.",
        "answer": "Braille"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This science deals with the motion of projectiles.",
        "answer": "ballistics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "To make a car go backwards you have to put it in what gear?",
        "answer": "reverse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What are these: Ceres, Juno, Iris, and Flora?",
        "answer": "asteroids"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What branch of science studies the motion of air and the forces acting on objects in air?",
        "answer": "aerodynamics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What did Lewis E. Waterman invent in 1884?",
        "answer": "fountain pen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does the \"lithosphere\" refer to?",
        "answer": "The earth's crust"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does the Binet test measure?",
        "answer": "intelligence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who invented dynamite?",
        "answer": "Alfred Nobel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who is known as the father of genetics?",
        "answer": "Gregor Mendel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As bold as -------.",
        "answer": "brass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As clean as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "whistle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As clear as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "bell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As cute as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "button"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As easy as --------.",
        "answer": "pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As fit as a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "fiddle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As good as ---------.",
        "answer": "gold"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As graceful as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "swan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As large as --------.",
        "answer": "life"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As loud as ---------.",
        "answer": "thunder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pale as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "ghost"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pleased as ---------.",
        "answer": "punch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pretty as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "picture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As proud as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "peacock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As quiet as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "mouse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As sick as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "dog"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As sly as a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "fox"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As smart as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "whip"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "Fresh as a(n) --------------.",
        "answer": "daisy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Baltimore --------.",
        "answer": "Orioles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Toronto ---------.",
        "answer": "Bluejays"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Boston -----------.",
        "answer": "Celtics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Denver ---------.",
        "answer": "Nuggets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Los Angeles ---------.",
        "answer": "Lakers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The New York ----------.",
        "answer": "Knicks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Seattle --------.",
        "answer": "Supersonics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Utah --------.",
        "answer": "Jazz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Baltimore --------.",
        "answer": "Colts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Buffalo -------.",
        "answer": "Bills"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Cincinnati ---------.",
        "answer": "Bengals"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Cleveland --------.",
        "answer": "Browns"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Dallas ---------.",
        "answer": "Cowboys"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Denver ---------.",
        "answer": "Broncos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Miami ----------.",
        "answer": "Dolphins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Minnesota -------.",
        "answer": "Vikings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The New Orleans ----------.",
        "answer": "Saints"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Seattle -------.",
        "answer": "Seahawks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "He holds the NHL record for the most goals scored during the regular season.",
        "answer": "Wayne Gretzky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "He was the NBA, MVP in 1976, 77, and 80.",
        "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Boston -----------.",
        "answer": "Bruins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Buffalo ---------.",
        "answer": "Sabres"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Calgary ----------.",
        "answer": "Flames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Chicago ---------.",
        "answer": "Blackhawks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Detroit --------.",
        "answer": "Red Wings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Edmonton ----------.",
        "answer": "Oilers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Los Angeles --------.",
        "answer": "Kings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Montreal --------.",
        "answer": "Canadians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Pittsburgh ----------.",
        "answer": "Penguins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The St. Louis ----------.",
        "answer": "Blues"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Toronto -------.",
        "answer": "Maple Leafs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Vancouver --------.",
        "answer": "Canucks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many feet high is a basketball net?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many games must you win to win a normal set in tennis?",
        "answer": "six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many minutes is a major penalty in hockey?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many minutes is each period of hockey?",
        "answer": "twenty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players are there on a soccer team?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players are there on a water polo team?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players make up a field hockey team?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many points are awarded for a safety touch in football?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many referees work a soccer game?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many seams are there on a football? (American)",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many sides does a home-plate have?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In pro football a \"sudden death\" period lasts how many minutes long?",
        "answer": "fifteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In ten-pin bowling, how many points does a perfect game consist of?",
        "answer": "three hundred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In this team sport each player gets a chance to play every position.",
        "answer": "volleyball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In what sport is the Heisman trophy awarded?",
        "answer": "American football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which city is the Cotton Bowl played?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which city is the Hockey Hall of Fame located?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which game or sport is a \"Zamboni\" used?",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is a \"hole-in-one\" possible?",
        "answer": "golf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?",
        "answer": "sailing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the Cy Young Trophy awarded?",
        "answer": "baseball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the Davis Cup awarded?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term \"love\" used?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term \"wishbone\" used?",
        "answer": "football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term, \"Hang ten\" used?",
        "answer": "surfing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport would you find the \"slapshot\".",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Name the hockey trophy awarded to the player demonstrating the best sportsmanship.",
        "answer": "The Lady Byng Trophy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "On what type of surface are the tennis matches at Wimbledon played?",
        "answer": "grass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "She was \"Sports Illustrated's\" first female \"Sportsman of the Year\".",
        "answer": "Billie Jean King"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Soccer: The New York ---------.",
        "answer": "Cosmos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in this city.",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The Japanese martial art of fencing is called --------.",
        "answer": "kendo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The person who carries the golfer's clubs is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "caddie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The white marks intersecting each five yard line are called --------.",
        "answer": "hash marks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This is the most coveted trophy in Candian football.",
        "answer": "Grey Cup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This sport allows substitutions without a stoppage in play.",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This sport is called the \"American pastime\".",
        "answer": "baseball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This team won their first World Series in 1969.",
        "answer": "New York Mets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This traditional Japanese wrestling sport takes place in a circular ring.",
        "answer": "sumo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Two under par on a hole of golf is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "eagle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What are large snow bumps known as in skiing terms?",
        "answer": "moguls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What do runners pass to each other in a relay race?",
        "answer": "baton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What do the letters ERA mean in baseball?",
        "answer": "Earned Run Average"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What does TKO stand for?",
        "answer": "Technical Knock Out"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What football player rushed for 2,003 yards in 1973?",
        "answer": "OJ Simpson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What game features the largest ball?",
        "answer": "earthball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is it called when a football team loses possession of the ball due to a misplay?",
        "answer": "turnover"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the heaviest class of weight-lifting?",
        "answer": "super heavyweight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What number wood is a driver in golf?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport do the Harlem Globetrotters play?",
        "answer": "basketball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?",
        "answer": "rugby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport would you helicopter to the Bugaboos for?",
        "answer": "skiing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What trophy is awarded to the winner of the NHL play-offs?",
        "answer": "Stanley Cup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What vehicles are involved in the \"Tour de France\"?",
        "answer": "bicycles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What was football player Dick Lane's nickname?",
        "answer": "Night Train"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What's the nickname of the University of Georgia football team?",
        "answer": "Bulldogs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Where are the U.S. Tennis Open Championships held?",
        "answer": "Flushing Meadows, NY"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which NFL team's defensive unit was nicknamed \"The Purple People Eaters\"?",
        "answer": "Minnesota Vikings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which country won the World Cup of Soccer in 1982.",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which football team was nicknamed the \"Orange Crush\"?",
        "answer": "Denver Broncos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which is the only position in soccer allowed to handle the ball?",
        "answer": "goalkeeper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which position is usually played by the tallest member on a basketball team?",
        "answer": "centre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which sport has a movement called a \"telemark\"?",
        "answer": "skiing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which sport uses stones and brooms?",
        "answer": "curling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which swimming stroke is named after an insect?",
        "answer": "butterfly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was known as the \"Sultan of Swat\"?",
        "answer": "Babe Ruth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the 1978 Wimbledon Women's Singles champ?",
        "answer": "Martina Navratilova"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the first NHL player to score 50 goals in one season?",
        "answer": "Maurice Richard <-- pronounced \"Reeee-shard\""
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the first to win the grand slam of tennis?",
        "answer": "Don Budge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With which sport is Chris Evert Lloyd identified?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Stand on your heads.... NOW! ;-)",
        "question": "When read upside down, what does the term \"umop apisdn\" signify?",
        "answer": "upside down"
    },
    {
        "category": "Stupid things to do ;-)",
        "question": "If you look at the sun long enough, you go -----.",
        "answer": "blind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Summertime",
        "question": "This is the sandy area nearest the ocean.",
        "answer": "beach"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What did TVs IMF stand for?",
        "answer": "Impossible Mission Forces"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first network series devoted entirely to rock and roll?",
        "answer": "American Bandstand"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Carl in Five Easy Pieces before going to Walton's Mountain?",
        "answer": "Waite"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Chief Marshall of the Mickey Mouse Club?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Triplets",
        "question": "Hook, line and -----------.",
        "answer": "sinker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "\"7X\" was used to refer to the secret ingredient of which drink?",
        "answer": "Coca Cola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A \"pigskin\" is another name for a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A can of Pepsi holds -- fluid ounces.",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A foot-long ruler is -- inches long.",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Most men do this each morning, using a razor.",
        "answer": "shave"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Most people wear a watch on their ---- wrist.",
        "answer": "left"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Name the implement that removes water from your windshield on your car?",
        "answer": "wiper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Traffic Trivia:  Red means stop, ----- means go.",
        "answer": "green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What US state has the Worlds Champion Chili Cookoff every year?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What bit of Bobby Goldsboro syrup focused on a dying young wife?",
        "answer": "honey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What did Sally Rogers always wear in her hair?",
        "answer": "a bow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What does the typical American eat 263 of each year? not pizza!!",
        "answer": "eggs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What game show had people dressed up funny?",
        "answer": "Let's Make A Deal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What is Grimace of the McDonald's characters?",
        "answer": "A tastebud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was Simple Simon fishing for in his mother's pail?",
        "answer": "whale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the Akla-Seltzer boy?",
        "answer": "Speedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the dog in RCA Victor's trademark?",
        "answer": "Nipper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What's the telephone area code for Chicago?",
        "answer": "312"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Howdy Doody live?",
        "answer": "Doodyville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Where were Archie and Edith Bunker's chairs enshrined?",
        "answer": "The Smithsonian Institute"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Who is also known as Mr. Warmth?",
        "answer": "Don Rickles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Who is known as \"the world's oldest teenager\"?",
        "answer": "Dick Clark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Ball and --------.",
        "answer": "chain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Peace and ---------.",
        "answer": "quiet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: nap, walk, call?",
        "answer": "cat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: painting, bowl, nail?",
        "answer": "finger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: rat, blue, cottage?",
        "answer": "cheese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "A castle or enclosed place.",
        "answer": "FORt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Make holes through something.",
        "answer": "perFORate"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Many trees.",
        "answer": "FORest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Pardon.",
        "answer": "FORgive"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'ten'",
        "question": "A choice cut of meat.",
        "answer": "tenderloi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Americanisms",
        "question": "Britains say 'tarmac'; Americans say ------.",
        "answer": "runway"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Analogy: 'Ancient' is to 'old' as 'recent' is to --------.",
        "answer": "current"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Bull - cow as fox - ----------.",
        "answer": "vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Goose - geese as passerby - -----------.",
        "answer": "passersby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Your ---- holds your head to your shoulders.",
        "answer": "neck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "In what field of study would you find \"flying buttresses\"?",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "The study of building design is ------------.",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "This statue was found on the Greek island of Melos in 1820.",
        "answer": "Venus de Milo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Three main types of Greek columns are Doric, Ionic, and ----------.",
        "answer": "Corinthian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "What Dutch master painted 64 self-portraits?",
        "answer": "Rembrandt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Where is the Louvre located?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "What is the only sign in the zodiac which doesn't represent a living thing?",
        "answer": "Libra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "Which month has a diamond as a birthstone?",
        "answer": "April"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "A heavenly body moving under the attraction of the Sun and consisting of a nucleus and a tail is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "comet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Does Uranus have an aurora?",
        "answer": "yes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "From 1979 until 2000 the most distant planet from the earth was -------.",
        "answer": "Neptune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "How many planets are there in our solar system?",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "If you're in the northern hemisphere, Polaris, the North Star, can be found by looking which direction?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the second-largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "saturn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Our galaxy is commonly known as the --------.",
        "answer": "Milky Way"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The Big Dipper is part of what constellation?",
        "answer": "Ursa Major"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The North Star is also known as -------.",
        "answer": "Polaris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The fourth planet from the sun is ----.",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The name for the group of stars which form a hunter with a club and shield is -----.",
        "answer": "Orion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The planet closest to the sun is -------.",
        "answer": "Mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The spiral galaxy nearest ours is the --------- galaxy.",
        "answer": "Andromeda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The tides on the earth's oceans are actually created by gravitational pull from the ----.",
        "answer": "Moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This cluster of stars is also known as the Seven Sisters.",
        "answer": "Pleiades"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This comet appears every 76.3 years.",
        "answer": "Comet Halley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This planet's diameter is most equal to that of the earth's.",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What does \"Ursa Major\" mean in everyday English?",
        "answer": "great bear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the astronomical name for a group of stars?",
        "answer": "constellation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name for the theoretical end-product of the gravitational collapse of a massive star?",
        "answer": "black hole"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name used to describe the \"minor planets\"?",
        "answer": "asteroids"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the ocean of air around the earth called?",
        "answer": "atmosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the proper name for falling stars?",
        "answer": "meteors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the term for the path followed a by a small body around a massive body in space?",
        "answer": "orbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the moon?",
        "answer": "tides"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What planet boasts the Great Red Spot?",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Bet you don't know ;-)",
        "question": "The two sexes of humans are male and ------?",
        "answer": "female"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous, oily liquid occurs in tobacco leaves.",
        "answer": "nicotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color.",
        "answer": "Haemoglobin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "Every human has one of these on their tummies.",
        "answer": "navel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "How many large holes are in your head?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "This complex substance makes up all living things.",
        "answer": "protoplasm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is normal body temperature for an adult human (in degrees fahrenheit)?",
        "answer": "98.6"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "The practice of joining the parts of two plants to make them grow as one is called --------.",
        "answer": "grafting"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "These flowerless plants grow on bare rocks and tree stumps.",
        "answer": "lichen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This fruit has its seeds on the outside.",
        "answer": "strawberry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This term means 'cone-bearing trees'.",
        "answer": "conifers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "What fruit bear the latin name \"citrus grandis\"?",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Calendar",
        "question": "How many days where there in 1976?",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Alvin & Simon had a brother called ----.",
        "answer": "Theodore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An Andy Panda cartoon gave birth to a famous, cantankerous bird. Name him.",
        "answer": "Woody Woodpecker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An adventurous penguin named Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named -------?",
        "answer": "Chumley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An alien creature in a funny hat has opposed both Bugs Bunny and Daffy Duck.  Where is he from?",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Before Olive Oil met Popeye she was engaged to someone.  Who was he?",
        "answer": "Ham Gravy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Benny and Cecil were at odds with whom?",
        "answer": "John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Bugs always finds himself at the wrong end of a gun, usually toted by either Elmer Fudd or who?",
        "answer": "Yosemite Sam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Casper the Friendly Ghost frolicked with which witch?",
        "answer": "Wendy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Boyer inspired a cartoon skunk. Who?",
        "answer": "Pepe le Pew"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Famous Phrases: Who knows? The ------.",
        "answer": "Shadow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Gadzookie has a large, green friend. Who is he?",
        "answer": "Godzilla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Hanna-Barbera rose to fame by creating what duo for MGM?",
        "answer": "Tom and Jerry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "How does Wonder Woman control her invisible airplane?",
        "answer": "mental powers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In the cartoons who was Hokie Wolf's sidekick?",
        "answer": "Ding"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In what city does Fat Albert live?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Mentor of Titan had two children in the Marvel comics, Thanos and ---?",
        "answer": "Ero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Miss Buckley is secretary to what commanding officer?",
        "answer": "General Halftrack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Alley Oop's girl friend.",
        "answer": "Oola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Cathy's on again/off again boy friend?",
        "answer": "Irving"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Dennis the Menace's next door neighbors.",
        "answer": "Mr and Mrs Wilson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Donald Duck's girlfriend?",
        "answer": "Daisy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Hagar the Horrible's dog.",
        "answer": "Snert"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Li'l Abner's favorite Indian drink.",
        "answer": "Kickapoo Joy Juice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the European hit, now an animated series about underwater people.",
        "answer": "The Snorks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the apartments the Jetson's live in.",
        "answer": "The Skypad Apartments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the dog in the Yankee Doodle cartoons.",
        "answer": "Chopper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the fastest mouse in all of Mexico.",
        "answer": "Speedy Gonzalez"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the ranger who was always after Yogi Bear.",
        "answer": "Rick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the town that Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty lived in.",
        "answer": "Bedrock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "On what T.V. show could Tom Terrific be found?",
        "answer": "Captain Kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Popeye's chief adversary has two names, Bluto and ------?",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Porky Pig had a girlfriend named --------.",
        "answer": "Petunia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Tess Trueheart married which plainclothes detective?",
        "answer": "Dick Tracy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What came out of Milton's head?",
        "answer": "steam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What character did Tex Avery first create upon arriving at MGM?",
        "answer": "Screwball Squirrel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip character is Beetle Bailey's sister?",
        "answer": "Lois (of Hi and Lois)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Dagwood give up to marry Blondie?",
        "answer": "A family inheritance"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Peppermint Patty always call Charlie Brown?",
        "answer": "Chuck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Batman's butler Alfred's last name.",
        "answer": "Pennyworth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Blondie's maiden name?",
        "answer": "Oop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?",
        "answer": "Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Smokey Stover's job?",
        "answer": "fireman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Super Chicken's partners name?",
        "answer": "Fred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the mother's name in Family Circus?",
        "answer": "Thelma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Duddley Do-Right's horse?",
        "answer": "Horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the Family Circus's dog?",
        "answer": "Barf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What kind of dog is Scooby Doo?",
        "answer": "great dane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What type of plant does Broom Hilda sell?",
        "answer": "venus flytrap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was Daffy Duck's favorite insult?",
        "answer": "You're dispicable!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was George of the Jungle always running in to?",
        "answer": "A tree"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first cartoon to feature sound?",
        "answer": "Steamboat Willie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of George of the Jungle's pet elephant?",
        "answer": "Shep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Speed Racer's car?",
        "answer": "The Mach Five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the original name Charles Schultz had for Peanuts?",
        "answer": "Li'l Folks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the relationship between Superman and Supergirl?",
        "answer": "cousin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When Tweety exclaimed, \"I thought I saw a putty tat!\", who did he see?",
        "answer": "Sylvester"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When danger appeared, Quick Draw McGraw became which super hero?",
        "answer": "El KaBong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not a Birdman, what does Ray Randall do for a living?",
        "answer": "police officer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?",
        "answer": "shoeshine boy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirel and Bullwinkle Moose from?",
        "answer": "Frostbite Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Clark Kent attend college?",
        "answer": "Metropolis University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did George of the Jungle live?",
        "answer": "Imgwee Gwee Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Mighty Mouse get his superpowers?",
        "answer": "supermarket"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where do Rocky and Bullwinkle play football?",
        "answer": "What'samatta University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does George Jetson work?",
        "answer": "Spacely Sprockets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does Yogi Bear Live?",
        "answer": "Jellystone Park"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which comic strip was banned from \"Stars and Stripes\"?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which superhero loves peace enough to kill for it?",
        "answer": "Peacemaker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who always tried to kill Krazy Kat?",
        "answer": "Captain Marvel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Donald Duck's uncle?",
        "answer": "Scrooge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Sally Brown's sweet baboo?",
        "answer": "Linus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Scooby Doo's nephew??",
        "answer": "Scrappy Doo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Snoopy's arch enemy?",
        "answer": "The Red Baron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is stationed at Camp Swampy in the comic strips?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who runs Andy Capp's favorite pub?",
        "answer": "Jack and Jill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who says, \"Th-th-th-that's all folks!\"",
        "answer": "Porky Pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who shot Bruce Wayne's parents?",
        "answer": "Chill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Dick Dastardly's pet?",
        "answer": "Muttley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was always trying to get rent from Andy Capp?",
        "answer": "Percy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the Hulk's first friend?",
        "answer": "Rick Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the original voice of Mickey Mouse?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Hydrogen Hydroxide is more commonly known as what?",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Nitrogen, a poisonous gas, makes up 78% of the --- that we breathe.",
        "answer": "air"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium Hydroxide is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "lye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium bicarbonate is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "baking soda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The process of removing salt from sea water is known as -----------.",
        "answer": "desalination"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The smallest portion of a substance capable of existing independently and retaining its original properties is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "molecule"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into gold was called -------.",
        "answer": "alchemy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the heaviest naturally occurring element.",
        "answer": "uranium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the symbol for tin.",
        "answer": "Sn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous gas is in the exhaust fumes from cars.",
        "answer": "carbon monoxide"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Water containing carbon dioxide under pressure is called ---- -----.",
        "answer": "soda water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is it that turns blue litmus paper red?",
        "answer": "acid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?",
        "answer": "TNT"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for copper?",
        "answer": "Cu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
        "answer": "Au"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the main component of air?",
        "answer": "nitrogen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the more scientific name for quicksilver?",
        "answer": "mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for iron in chemistry?",
        "answer": "Fe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for silver?",
        "answer": "Ag"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Name the loner rebel reindeer with the red shiny nose.",
        "answer": "Rudolph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Santa Claus reportedly lives at the ----- Pole.",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Comic Strip Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip is set at Camp Swampy?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "That big square thing you're staring at right now is called a -------?",
        "answer": "monitor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "The Internet Relay Chat Program, which normally connects to port 6667, is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "IRC"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  Exalting one's country above all others.",
        "answer": "nationalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The belief that there is no God.",
        "answer": "atheism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The theory that man cannot prove the existence of a god.",
        "answer": "agnosticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-ism: The belief in the existence of a god or gods.",
        "answer": "theism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A diseased condition resulting from the use of beverages such as whiskey.",
        "answer": "alcoholism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A one-party system of government in which control is maintained by force and regimentation.",
        "answer": "fascism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A painful stiffness of the muscles and joints",
        "answer": "rheumatism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A severe or unfavorable judgment.",
        "answer": "criticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: An economic system characterized by private ownership and competition.",
        "answer": "capitalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive emphasis on financial gain.",
        "answer": "commercialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive enthusiasm or zeal for a cause.",
        "answer": "fanaticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Poisoning caused by a toxin in improperly prepared food.",
        "answer": "botulism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Public ownership of the basic means of production, distribution, and exchange.",
        "answer": "socialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: The belief in living a very austere and self-denying life.",
        "answer": "asceticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A clip, shaped like a bar to keep a woman's hair in place is a -------.",
        "answer": "barrette"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A depilatory is a substance used for removing ----.",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A device used to change the voltage of alternating currents is a ----------.",
        "answer": "transformer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A flat, round hat sometimes worn by soldiers is a -----.",
        "answer": "beret"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A government in which power is restricted to a few is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "oligarchy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person in his eighties is called a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "octogenarian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person who starts fires maliciously is a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "arsonist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person with a strong desire to steal is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "kleptomaniac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A pugilist is a -----.",
        "answer": "boxer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A receptacle for holy water is a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "font"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A sun-dried grape is known as a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "raisin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A word like 'NASA' formed from the initials of other words is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "acronym"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Acrophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "heights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited ----------.",
        "answer": "knowledge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An anemometer measures ---- --------.",
        "answer": "wind velocity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An animal stuffer is a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "taxidermist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An artist supports his canvas on a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "easel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An instrument on a car to measure the distance travelled is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "odometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Androphobia is the fear of -----.",
        "answer": "males"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Animals that once existed but don't exist now are said to be -------.",
        "answer": "extinct"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Any object worn as a charm may be called a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "amulet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Bibliophobia is a fear of -----.",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Brontophobia is the fear of -------.",
        "answer": "thunder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "ring dating"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Doraphobia is the fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "fur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Eleutherophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "freedom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Gymnophobia is the fear of ----------.",
        "answer": "naked bodies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Hills and ridges composed of drifting sand are known as -----.",
        "answer": "dunes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Ichthyology is the study of --------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A crime more serious than a misdemeanor.",
        "answer": "felony"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A formal agreement enforceable by law.",
        "answer": "contract"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A supplement to a will.",
        "answer": "codicil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: The people chosen to render a verdict in a court.",
        "answer": "jury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: To steal property entrusted to one's care.",
        "answer": "embezzle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the pain-inflicting person you go to to get your teeth fixed.",
        "answer": "dentist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the porceilan chair you sit on at least once a day.",
        "answer": "toilet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "One who tells fortunes by the stars is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "astrologer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Rats, mice, beavers, and squirrels are all -------.",
        "answer": "rodents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The art of tracing designs and taking impressions of them is -----------.",
        "answer": "lithography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The covering on the tip of a shoelace is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "aglet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The distance around the outside of a circle is its ------------.",
        "answer": "circumference"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The earth's atmosphere and the space beyond is known as ---------.",
        "answer": "aerospace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The effect produced when sound is reflected back is known as a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "echo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The feeling of having experienced something before is known as -------.",
        "answer": "deja vu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of preparing and dispensing drugs is --------.",
        "answer": "pharmacy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of providing men, equipment and supplies for military operations is called --------.",
        "answer": "logistics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human behaviour is ----------.",
        "answer": "psychology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human pre-history is -----------.",
        "answer": "archaeology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of insects is ----------.",
        "answer": "entomology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of light and its relation to sight is called ------.",
        "answer": "optics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of man and culture is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "anthropology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of natural phenomena: motion, forces, light, sound, etc. is called ------.",
        "answer": "physics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of plants is ------.",
        "answer": "botany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of religion is --------.",
        "answer": "theology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of sound is ---------.",
        "answer": "acoustics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the composition of substances and the changes that they undergo is ---------.",
        "answer": "chemistry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the earth's physical divisions into mountains, seas, etc. is ---------.",
        "answer": "geography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the manner in which organisms carry on their life processes is ---------.",
        "answer": "physiology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The symbols used on a map are explained by the ------.",
        "answer": "legend"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The treatment of disease by chemical substances which are toxic to the causative micro-organisms is called ------------.",
        "answer": "chemotherapy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The weight at the end of a pendulum is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "bob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The wide wall built along the banks of rivers to stop flooding is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "levee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The word \"cumulus\" refers to a type of -----------.",
        "answer": "cloud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points, on a curved surface.",
        "answer": "calliper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures atmospheric pressure.",
        "answer": "barometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures the velocity of the wind.",
        "answer": "anemometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This is the fear of enclosed spaces.",
        "answer": "claustrophobia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word is used as the international radio distress call.",
        "answer": "mayday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word means \"split personality\".",
        "answer": "schizophrenia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Throat, foxing, and platform are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "shoe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Toxiphobia is a fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "poison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a brandophile collect?",
        "answer": "cigar bands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a heliologist study?",
        "answer": "the sun"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does an ornithologist study?",
        "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?",
        "answer": "tourniquet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a dried plum called?",
        "answer": "prune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a female swan called?",
        "answer": "pen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?",
        "answer": "octagon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is another name for a tombstone inscription?",
        "answer": "epitaph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is measured by a chronometer?",
        "answer": "time"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for a Japanese dwarf tree?",
        "answer": "bonsai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for the Aurora Borealis?",
        "answer": "northern lights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common term for a \"somnambulist\"?",
        "answer": "sleepwalker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the name for a branch of a river?",
        "answer": "tributary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of heredity called?",
        "answer": "genetics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of prehistoric plants and animals called?",
        "answer": "paleontology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the term for a castrated rooster?",
        "answer": "capon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Which science studies weather?",
        "answer": "meteorology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Domestic Metallurgy",
        "question": "Name the clothing wrinkle remover that sounds like a kind of metal.",
        "answer": "iron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A 3 1/2\" floppy disk measures --- and 1/2 inches across.",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A brown crayon is what color?",
        "answer": "brown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A smoke detector will alarm if it detects -----.",
        "answer": "smoke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A water heater keeps ----- warm for you.",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "Although not all come from France, ------ fries are often served with hamburgers.",
        "answer": "french"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "An ----- clock usually wakes you in the morning.",
        "answer": "alarm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "During the American Revolution, the Boston Tea Party took place in ------ Harbor.",
        "answer": "boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How do you spell abbreviation?",
        "answer": "abbreviation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How many pencils are there in a dozen?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?",
        "answer": "Thornton Wilder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "The play \"Our Town\" is set where?",
        "answer": "Grover's Corners"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fantasy",
        "question": "What is a sorcerer who deals in black magic called?",
        "answer": "necromancer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Boston butt, jowl, and picnic ham are parts of a ------.",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Even though it tastes nothing like grapes, a ---------- is often eaten for breakfast.",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From what animal do we get venison?",
        "answer": "deer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fish is caviar obtained?",
        "answer": "sturgeon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fruit is the liqueur Kirsh made?",
        "answer": "cherry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Iceberg, Boston, and Bibb are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "lettuce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Laetrile is associated with the pit of which fruit?",
        "answer": "apricot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Little round chocolate candies are known as _&m's.",
        "answer": "m"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Mustard, ketchup and onions on a hotdog are all ----------.",
        "answer": "condiments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Name the only fruit named for its color.",
        "answer": "orange"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Natural vanilla flavoring comes from this plant.",
        "answer": "orchid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often drunk, this liquid is normally harvested from female cows.",
        "answer": "milk"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, bacon is actually the flesh of what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, the egg comes from what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "chicken"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Rum is made from this plant.",
        "answer": "sugar cane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Vermicelli literally means -----------.",
        "answer": "little worms"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?",
        "answer": "sangria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is Japanese \"sake\" made from?",
        "answer": "rice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is the name of the syrup drained from raw sugar?",
        "answer": "molasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What kind of nuts are used in marzipan?",
        "answer": "almonds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where is the best brandy bottled?",
        "answer": "cognac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where was Budweiser first brewed?",
        "answer": "St. Louis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Bourbon, sugar and mint make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "mint julep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Cognac (brandy) and white creme de menthe make a(n) -------------.",
        "answer": "stinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Creme de Cacao, cream, and brandy make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "brandy alexander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Gin and Collins mix make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "Tom Collins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Rum, lime, and cola drink make a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "cuba libre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Triple sec, tequila, and lemon or lime juice make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "margarita"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka and Kahlua make a -----------.",
        "answer": "black russian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka, orange juice and Galliano make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "Harvey Wallbanger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Whiskey, hot coffee, and whipped cream make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Irish coffee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A bridge hand with no cards in one suit is said to have a -------.",
        "answer": "void"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A poker hand consisting of three of a kind and a pair is called a -------.",
        "answer": "full house"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many balls are used in a game of snooker including the cue ball?",
        "answer": "twenty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?",
        "answer": "forty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?",
        "answer": "sixty four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "If you \"peg out\" what game are you playing?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In poker five cards of the same suit is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "flush"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?",
        "answer": "black"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game might a person have a \"full house\"?",
        "answer": "poker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport are \"Staunton\" pieces used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport can a person be \"skunked\"?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport are terms \"spare\" and \"gutter\" used?",
        "answer": "tenpin bowling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game are the terms: 'pin', 'fork', and 'skewer' used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game is the term \"rook\" used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only flexible murder weapon in the game of \"Cluedo\".",
        "answer": "rope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only woman suspect in the game of \"Cluedo\" who isn't married.",
        "answer": "Miss Scarlett"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "These are the two highest valued letters in \"Scrabble\".  \"Q\" and -----.",
        "answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This ancient Chinese game is played with 156 small rectangular tiles.",
        "answer": "mah jongg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This is the lowest ranking suit in Bridge.",
        "answer": "clubs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This term denotes a chess move in which both the king and the rook are moved.",
        "answer": "castling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What bowling term means three straight strikes?",
        "answer": "turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What game or sport is Bobby Fischer identified with?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What number is on the opposite side of the \"five\" on dice?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What score is not possible for a cribbage hand?",
        "answer": "nineteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which chess piece is usually valued as 5 points?",
        "answer": "rook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which game usually begins with, \"Is it animal, vegetable, or mineral?\"",
        "answer": "twenty questions"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Although it doesn't sound like a dog, ----dust is ornamental wood chips often placed in flowerbeds.",
        "answer": "bark"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Chicago Transit Authority is now known as which group?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "If you drive on a parkway, you park on a -------?",
        "answer": "driveway"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "To refuel your car you go to a ----- station.",
        "answer": "petrol"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Wedding rings are normally worn on what finger of your hand?",
        "answer": "ring finger"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are catalogued under the Dewey decimal system?",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are the 3 big colleges of the Ivy League? (name them alphabetically)",
        "answer": "Harvard, Princeton, Yale"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What company makes Pampers disposable diapers?",
        "answer": "Proctor & Gamble"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the initials U.F.O stand for?",
        "answer": "Unidentified Flying Object"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the letters in SAM missiles refer to?",
        "answer": "Surface-to-Air Missile"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does IRS stand for?",
        "answer": "Internal Revenue Service"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does a compass needle point to?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the abbreviation a.m. stand for?",
        "answer": "Ante Meridian"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the acronym CIA stand for?",
        "answer": "Central Intelligence Agency"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the minimum IQ score for the genius category?",
        "answer": "one hundred and forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is this sign called \"&\"?",
        "answer": "ampersand"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "When using a telephone, you must wait for a ---- tone before starting your call.",
        "answer": "dial"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which U.S. president is on the five-dollar bill?",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Acadia was the original name of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgeport is the largest city in which state?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgetown is the capital of --------.",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Brussels is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Frankfort is the capital of which state?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Guayaquil is the largest city in what country?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Halifax is the capital of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Havana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He invented the most common projection for world maps.",
        "answer": "Gerardus Mercator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He visited Australia and New Zealand, then surveyed the Pacific Coast of North America.",
        "answer": "Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "How many stars are on the flag of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "If its 4:00pm in Seattle, Washington what time is it in Portland, Oregon?",
        "answer": "4:00pm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city are the famous Tivoli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Leaning Tower?",
        "answer": "Pisa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Smithsonian Institute?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Banff National Park?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Lahore?",
        "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Mandalay?",
        "answer": "Myanmar (formerly known as Burma)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Taipei?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Jutland peninsula?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Mekong River Delta?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Waterloo battlefield?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the highest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the lowest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the source of the Blue Nile?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what island group is Corregidor?",
        "answer": "Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what mountain range is Kicking Horse Pass?",
        "answer": "Rocky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what state is Concord?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Red Square?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Saint Paul's Cathedral?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Wembley Stadium?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Bridge of Sighs?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Canale Grande?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Colliseum located?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Wailing Wall?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Angel Falls?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Brest? (NOT Breast!)",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Chennai (formerly Madras)?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Cusco?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Loch Ness?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Normandy?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Sapporo?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Calabria region?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Dalai Lama's palace?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Great Victoria Desert?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Machu Picchu?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country would you find the Yucatan Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?",
        "answer": "Indian Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are Gettysburg and the Liberty Bell?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are the Finger Lakes?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Appomattax?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Cape Hatteras?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Hoover Dam?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount McKinley?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount St. Helens?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount Vernon?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Stone Mountain?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Walla Walla?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Kennedy Space Center?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Mayo Clinic?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Painted Desert?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what bay does the Ganges River flow?",
        "answer": "Bay Of Bengal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River flow?",
        "answer": "Black Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Yukon River flow?",
        "answer": "Bering Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe River flow?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Mackenzie River flow?",
        "answer": "Beaufort Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kingston is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Linz, Austria is a leading port on which river?",
        "answer": "Danube"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Madrid and Lisbon are both located near this river.",
        "answer": "Tagus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Meridians converge at the --------.",
        "answer": "poles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Mount Victoria is the highest peak of this island country.",
        "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name a country which has the same name as a bird.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the U.S. state with the smallest population.",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Massachusetts.",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Rhode Island.",
        "answer": "Providence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Argentina.",
        "answer": "Buenos Aires"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Brazil.",
        "answer": "Brasilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Italy.",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the city at the west end of Lake Superior.",
        "answer": "Duluth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the continent that consists of a single country.",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the desert located in south-east California.",
        "answer": "Mojave"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the large mountain chain in the eastern U.S.A.",
        "answer": "The Appalachians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest cathedral in the world.",
        "answer": "St. Peter's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest city in Canada.",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest island in the world.",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest lake in Australia.",
        "answer": "Eyre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest river forming part of the U.S. - Mexican border.",
        "answer": "Rio Grande"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the last province to become part of Canada.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Asia.",
        "answer": "Yangtze"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Nigeria.",
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the most north-easterly of the 48 contiguous states.",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the only Central American country without an Atlantic coastline.",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Asia Minor and Greece.",
        "answer": "Aegean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Korea and China.",
        "answer": "Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Beaufort"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Murmansk, Russia.",
        "answer": "Barents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea west of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Bering"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in Africa.",
        "answer": "Algeria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in South America.",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest lake in North America.",
        "answer": "Huron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the smallest of the Great Lakes.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the strait joining the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean Sea.",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the world's most photographed and most climbed mountain.",
        "answer": "Fuji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Nassau is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Bahamas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Honolulu?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Pearl Harbour?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the Blue Grotto?",
        "answer": "Capri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the U.S. naval base, Guantanamo?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what mountain are four presidents' faces carved?",
        "answer": "Rushmore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what peninsula are Spain and Portugal located?",
        "answer": "The Iberian peninsula"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what river is the capital city of Canada?",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is London, England?",
        "answer": "Thames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is Rome located?",
        "answer": "Tiber"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is the Aswan High Dam?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Over 75% of the Earth's surface is covered by some form of -----.",
        "answer": "Water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Rabat is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "San Francisco Bay is located near what city?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Seoul is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "St. George's is the capital city of what island country?",
        "answer": "Grenada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Surfing is believed to have originated here.",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Auckland Islands belong to which country?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Hebrides are part of this country.",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Ionian and Cyclades are island groups of which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Little Mermaid is found in the harbour of which city?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Nationalist Chinese occupy this island.",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Thatcher Ferry Bridge crosses what canal?",
        "answer": "Panama Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The United States is made up of -- states.",
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Volta is the largest river in which country?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called --------.",
        "answer": "Benelux"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The longest river in Western Europe is ---------?",
        "answer": "Rhine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The sun sets in the ----?",
        "answer": "west"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Canadian island is the world's fifth largest.",
        "answer": "Baffin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Pacific island's puzzling monoliths attract ethnologists.",
        "answer": "Easter Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country is divided at the 38th parallel.",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country occupies the \"horn of Africa\".",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country's flag has a large \"R\" on it.",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This imaginary line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean.",
        "answer": "international date line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is called the \"Honeymoon Capital\" of the world.",
        "answer": "Niagara Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the bridge with the longest span in the U.S.A.",
        "answer": "Verrazano Narrows"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the only borough of New York City that is not on an island.",
        "answer": "The Bronx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the port city serving Tokyo.",
        "answer": "Yokohama"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the residence of English monarchs.",
        "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This island group is off the east coast of southern South America.",
        "answer": "Falkland Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This re-opened in 1975 after being closed for 8 years.",
        "answer": "Suez Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This section of Manhattan is noted for its Negro and Latin American residents.",
        "answer": "Harlem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country do the Faeroe Islands belong?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country does the Gaza Strip belong?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  The Easter Bunny is from Easter Island.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  There are only virgins on the Virgin Islands.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Under what river does the Holland Tunnel run?",
        "answer": "Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What American city is known as Little Havana?",
        "answer": "Miami"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Asian city was once called Edo?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Canadian city is at the west end of Lake Ontario?",
        "answer": "Hamilton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country administers the island of Martinique?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country has \"Vaduz\" as its capital city?",
        "answer": "Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What London borough does the Prime Meridian pass through?",
        "answer": "Greenwich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is known as Insurance City?",
        "answer": "Hartford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. state is known as The Land of 10,000 Lakes?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What US state is completely surrounded by the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are drumlins and eskers formed by?",
        "answer": "glaciers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are the worlds four oceans - alphabetically?",
        "answer": "Arctic, Atlantic, Indian and Pacific"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What body of water borders Saudi Arabia to the east?",
        "answer": "Persian Gulf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What canal connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie?",
        "answer": "Welland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city boasts the Copacabana Beach and Ipanema?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is associated with Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is on Lake Erie at the mouth of the Cuyahoga River?",
        "answer": "Cleveland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Christian Science Monitor based in?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Kremlin located in?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city was the setting for \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What color does the bride wear in China?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is Cyprus considered to be part of?",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is the home to the greatest number of countries?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country are the Islands of Quemoy and Matsu part of?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt on the west?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country does the island of Mykonos belong to?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country formed the union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country has the world's most southerly city?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Phnom Penh the capital of?",
        "answer": "Cambodia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Santo Domingo the capital of?",
        "answer": "Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of Israel?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of the continental United States?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly west of Spain?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is known as the Hellenic Republic?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is located between Panama and Nicaragua?",
        "answer": "Costa Rica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country owns the island of Corfu?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was once known as Gaul?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Casablanca\"?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Doctor Zhivago\"?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What famous geyser erupts regularly at the Yellowstone National Park?",
        "answer": "Old Faithful"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Alaska?",
        "answer": "Juneau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Bangladesh?",
        "answer": "Dacca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Burma?",
        "answer": "Rangoon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Chile?",
        "answer": "Santiago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Colorado?",
        "answer": "Denver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Florida?",
        "answer": "Tallahassee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of India?",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Indonesia?",
        "answer": "Jakarta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Maine?",
        "answer": "Augusta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nebraska",
        "answer": "Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Wellington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Washington state?",
        "answer": "Olympia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of West Virginia?",
        "answer": "Charleston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Madison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?",
        "answer": "Harare"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of the United Arab Emirates?",
        "answer": "Abu Dhabi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the current name for south-west Africa?",
        "answer": "Namibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in Canada?",
        "answer": "Mt. Logan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in Australia, in terms of population?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in China?",
        "answer": "Shanghai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest of the countries in Central America?",
        "answer": "Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the monetary unit of India?",
        "answer": "Rupee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the most sacred river in India?",
        "answer": "Ganges"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?",
        "answer": "Arabic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the principal river of Ireland?",
        "answer": "Shannon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest of the United States?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest independent state in the world?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest of the Central American countries?",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's highest city?",
        "answer": "Lhasa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island has Hamilton as its capital?",
        "answer": "Bermuda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island is known as the Spice Island?",
        "answer": "Zanzibar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
        "answer": "Ural"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What prison island was off the coast of French Guiana?",
        "answer": "Devil's Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river has the largest drainage basin?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is Liverpool on?",
        "answer": "Mersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is called \"Old Man River\"?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is known as China's Sorrow?",
        "answer": "Yellow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is the Temple of Karnak near?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What sea is between Italy and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Adriatic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What south American country has both a Pacific and Atlantic coastline?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state is the Golden State?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state was the home to Mayberry?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What symbol is on the flag of Vietnam?",
        "answer": "star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What unit of currency will buy you dinner in Iraq, Jordan, Tunisia, and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Dinar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What volcano showers ash on Sicily?",
        "answer": "Etna"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the former name of Istanbul?",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the highest mountain in the 48 contiguous U.S. states?",
        "answer": "Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the Nazca Lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the pyramids located?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Beacon Street?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Euston Station?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is George Washington buried?",
        "answer": "Mt. Vernon, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Westminster Abbey located?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Admirality Arch?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Holy Kaaba?",
        "answer": "Mecca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Parthenon located?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the city of Brotherly Love?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Canadian province extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Central American country extends furthest north?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the highest population density?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the lowest population density?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Irish city is famous for its crystal?",
        "answer": "Waterford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as Beantown?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the Biggest Little City in the World?",
        "answer": "Reno"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state borders a Canadian territory?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the least rainfall?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state receives the most rainfall?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which capital is known as the Glass Capital of the World?",
        "answer": "Toledo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city has the largest rodeo in the world?",
        "answer": "Calgary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as Motown?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as the Windy City?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is on the east side of San Francisco Bay?",
        "answer": "Oakland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country administers Christmas Island?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country are the Galapagos Islands part of?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country borders Italy, Switzerland, West Germany, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, and Liechtenstein?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country developed \"Tae-Kwan-Do\"?",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Ankara as its capital?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has the longest land border?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country hosted the 1982 World Cup of soccer?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country uses the \"yen\" for currency?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country would come first in an alphabetical list of countries?",
        "answer": "Afghanistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which islands were named after Prince Philip of Spain?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which mainland Latin American country is in neither South America nor Central America?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the U.S. states borders only one other state?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which river contains the most fresh water?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state has the most hospitals?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is divided into two parts by a large lake?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Evergreen State?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Garden State?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Wolverine State?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With what country is Fidel Castro associated?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With which country is Prince Rainier III identified?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geogrpahy",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Utah.",
        "answer": "Salt Lake City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Earth's outer layer of surface soil or crust is called the -------.",
        "answer": "Lithosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Peat, lignite and bituminous are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "coal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Slate is formed by the metamorphosis of ---------.",
        "answer": "shale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The green variety of beryl is called --------.",
        "answer": "emerald"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The molten material from a volcano is --------?",
        "answer": "lava"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The spot on the Earth's surface directly above an earthquake's focus is called the ------.",
        "answer": "epicenter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The violet variety of quartz is called --------.",
        "answer": "amethyst"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "There are three types of rocks: metamorphic, sedimentary, and ---------.",
        "answer": "igneous"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "These limestone deposits rise from the floor of caves.",
        "answer": "stalagmites"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "This is the hardest naturally occurring substance.",
        "answer": "diamond"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What name is used to describe permanently-frozen subsoil?",
        "answer": "permafrost"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hahaha",
        "question": "This normally has 4 legs and your butt is parked in it right now.",
        "answer": "chair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hirtory",
        "question": "Name the first black nation to gain freedom from European colonial rule.",
        "answer": "Haiti"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Britain and Argentina fought over these islands in 1982.",
        "answer": "Falklands Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Canadian Prime Minister: Pierre Elliott ----------.",
        "answer": "Trudeau"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Churchill, F.D. Roosvelt and Stalin met here in 1945.",
        "answer": "Yalta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Eras are divided into units called --------.",
        "answer": "periods"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "For what country did Columbus make his historic voyage?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Four Japanese carriers were destroyed in this battle.",
        "answer": "Midway"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Frankish ruler Charles the Great is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "Charlemagne"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "From what country did the U.S. buy the Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "General Sherman burned this city in 1864.",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's WW I allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and --------.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's allies in WW II were Japan, Italy, Hungary, Bulgaria, Finland, Libya, and ---------.",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He allowed the bugging of the Democratic Committee headquarters.",
        "answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He discovered the Grand Canyon.",
        "answer": "Francisco Coronado"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is identified with the expression, \"Eureka\".",
        "answer": "Archimedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is said to have fiddled while Rome burned.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He led 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1979.",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He ordered the persecution of Christians in which Peter and Paul died.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964 for his civil rights leadership.",
        "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He said, \"I have nothing to offer but blood, tears, toil and sweat.\"",
        "answer": "Sir Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He shot Lee Harvey Oswald.",
        "answer": "Jack Ruby"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He taught Alexander the Great.",
        "answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Dec. 8, 1980 in New York City.",
        "answer": "John Lennon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Nov. 22, 1963.",
        "answer": "John Fitzgerald Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn.",
        "answer": "General Custer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was stabbed by Gaius Cassius Longinus.",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the American inventor of the Cotton Gin.",
        "answer": "Eli Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the U.S. president during the Civil War.",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His ship was the H.M.S. Beagle.",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His wife was Roxana. His horse was Bacephalus. He was --------.",
        "answer": "Alexander the Great"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How do you write 69 in Roman numerals?",
        "answer": "LXIX"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many astronauts manned each Apollo flight?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How old was John F. Kennedy when he became president?",
        "answer": "forty three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In 1902 this volcano erupted, killing 30,000.",
        "answer": "Pelee"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In what country did \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city was President Kennedy killed?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city were the Hanging Gardens?",
        "answer": "Babylon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country did the Boxer Rebellion take place?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was Adolf Hitler born?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the Golan Heights.  Whose territory was it?",
        "answer": "Syria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the West Bank.  It belonged to -------.",
        "answer": "Jordan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport in New York used to be called ----------.",
        "answer": "Idlewind"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Mussolini invaded this country in 1935.",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name Jacques Cousteau's research ship.",
        "answer": "Calypso"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name the incident in which tea was dumped into the harbour.",
        "answer": "Boston Tea Party"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "One who fought professionally in Roman arenas was a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "Gladiator"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She overcame her handicaps to become a lecturer and a scholar.",
        "answer": "Helen Keller"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was Queen of Egypt and mistress of Julius Caesar.",
        "answer": "Cleopatra"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was called \"The Maid of Orleans\".",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first First Lady to be received privately by the Pope.",
        "answer": "Jackie Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman premier of Israel.",
        "answer": "Golda Meir"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to fly the Atlantic solo.",
        "answer": "Amelia Earhart"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to swim the English channel.",
        "answer": "Gertrude Caroline Ederle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the greatest trick shot artist of all time.",
        "answer": "Annie Oakley"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She won the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her work among the poor.",
        "answer": "Mother Teresa"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Spain ceded Florida to Britain in exchange for this territory.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The \"Bay of Pigs\" fiasco took place in this country.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Devonian Period is also known as the Age of ----------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Inquisition forced him to recant his belief in the Copernican Theory.",
        "answer": "Galileo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Romans built these to convey water.",
        "answer": "aqueducts"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The St. Valentine's Day massacre took place in this city.",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The first dog in space was named ---------.",
        "answer": "Laika"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The last line of this document is \"Working men of all countries, unite.\"",
        "answer": "Communist Manifesto"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This F.B.I agent headed the investigation of Al Capone.",
        "answer": "Elliot Ness"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This French peasant girl led the army to victories.",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Indian group ruled in early Peru.",
        "answer": "Inca"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Nazi leader had his six children poisoned prior to his own death.",
        "answer": "Joseph Goebbels"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Queen of France was beheaded in 1793.",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Roman killed himself after his defeat at Actium.",
        "answer": "Marc Antony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Sioux Indian toured with Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show.",
        "answer": "Sitting Bull"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Spaniard conquered Mexico.",
        "answer": "Hernando Cortez"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. Secretary of State won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973.",
        "answer": "Henry Kissinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. president was fatally shot in 1881.",
        "answer": "James Garfield"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This assassin of Julius Caesar was his friend.",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This frontiersman and politician was killed at the Alamo.",
        "answer": "Davy Crockett"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This is said to be history's greatest military evacuation.",
        "answer": "Dunkirk"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This military attack took place on Dec. 7, 1941.",
        "answer": "Pearl Harbour"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This organization was founded by William Booth.",
        "answer": "Salvation Army"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This racist organization was formed in Tennessee in 1865.",
        "answer": "Ku Klux Klan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This war began on June 25, 1950.",
        "answer": "Korean"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This was the largest real estate deal in U.S. history.",
        "answer": "Louisiana Purchase"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This word describes the Nazi annihilation of Jews.",
        "answer": "holocaust"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Those big black CD's that you see at garage sales that people call \"albums\" are made of -----.",
        "answer": "vinyl"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Two 747's collided here in 1977.",
        "answer": "Canary Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Chester Alan --------.",
        "answer": "Arthur"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Herbert C. ---------.",
        "answer": "Hoover"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, John Quincy --------.",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President: Calvin ---------.",
        "answer": "Coolidge"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What American feminist went bust as a silver dollar?",
        "answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What Chinese dynasty was overthrown in 1911?",
        "answer": "Manchu"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What age preceded the Iron Age?",
        "answer": "The Bronze Age"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did President J. Buchanan not have?",
        "answer": "A wife"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did presidents Madison, Monroe, Polk, and Garfield have in common?",
        "answer": "The first name \"James\""
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What group landed in America in 1620?",
        "answer": "The Pilgrims"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the Roman numeral for fifty?",
        "answer": "L"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the name of the Russian Czar's daughter who might-or might not-have survived the Russian revolution?",
        "answer": "Anastasia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What volcano destroyed Pompeii?",
        "answer": "Vesuvius"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the instrument of execution during the \"Reign of Terror\"?",
        "answer": "guillotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of Plato's school?",
        "answer": "Academy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of the B-29 used at Hiroshima to drop the bomb?",
        "answer": "Enola Gay"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the nationality of the prisoners in the \"Black hole of Calcutta\"?",
        "answer": "British"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the third country to get the \"bomb\"?",
        "answer": "Britain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What's the resting place of those buried at sea?",
        "answer": "Davey Jones's Locker"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which U.S. president said, \"The buck stops here\"?",
        "answer": "Truman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which military battle took place in 1815?",
        "answer": "Waterloo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nation was led by Genghis Khan?",
        "answer": "The Mongols"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which president was responsible for the Louisiana Purchase?",
        "answer": "Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is \"The Iron Lady\"?",
        "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led the attack on the Alamo?",
        "answer": "Santa Ana"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who rode naked through the streets of Coventry?",
        "answer": "Lady Godiva"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said \"Veni, vidi, vici\" (I came, I saw, I conquered)?",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said: \"Let them eat cake\"?",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who sang Happy Birthday to John F. Kennedy for his 45th?",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who succeeded Churchill when he resigned in 1955?",
        "answer": "Sir Anthony Eden"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was \"The Mad Monk\"?",
        "answer": "Rasputin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was George Washington's vice-president?",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first chancellor of West Germany after WW II?",
        "answer": "Konrad Adenauer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?",
        "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was, \"First in war, first in peace and first in the hearts of his countrymen\"?",
        "answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "What three letters are overly used to indicate \"Laugh Out Loud\"?",
        "answer": "lol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Langauge",
        "question": "Many Meanings:  Fuel, vapor, flattulence, helium.  What is it?",
        "answer": "gas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Drinking utensils or sight-enhancers.",
        "answer": "glasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Slamming your hands together quickly, or a venereal disease.",
        "answer": "clap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Name the soda that is often confused with a drug.",
        "answer": "Coke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Subject, verb and object are parts of a ---------.",
        "answer": "sentence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "This animal is found at the beginning of an (English) encyclopedia",
        "answer": "aardvark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the only English word formed by the first three letters of the alphabet?",
        "answer": "cab"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What three letter word means the same as \"to ingest\"?",
        "answer": "eat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "\"faux pas\" means -----------.",
        "answer": "mistake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "Mardi Gras is French for -----------.",
        "answer": "fat tuesday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name Australia is derived from the Latin word \"australis\" which means -------.",
        "answer": "southern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name for this semi-precious stone comes from the Latin for \"sea water\"",
        "answer": "aquamarine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----hood; ----hole; ----date.",
        "answer": "man"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----stream; ----hill; -----pour.",
        "answer": "down"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What does \"c'est la vie\" mean?",
        "answer": "that's life"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What word contains the combination of letters: \"xop\"?",
        "answer": "saXOPhone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "\"The Diary of Anne Frank\" was first published in English under what title?",
        "answer": "The Diary of a Young Girl"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Captain Hook, Tiger Lily, and Tinker Bell are characters in what story?",
        "answer": "Peter Pan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Dr. Seuss wrote this book: The Cat in the ------.",
        "answer": "Hat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Edgar Allen Poe wrote a famous poem about this animal.",
        "answer": "raven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Double, double ... \"",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Goodnight, goodnight! Parting is such sweet sorrow, That I should say goodnight till it be morrow.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"To be or not to be?\"",
        "answer": "Hamlet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"What in a name? That which we call a rose, by any other name would smell as sweet.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many lines are in a sonnet?",
        "answer": "fourteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many plays is Shakespeare generally credited with today?",
        "answer": "thirty seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Name the Shakespeare play from this ultra short plot summary: Urged on by his wife, a man murders his king in order to take his place.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Pet --------\".",
        "answer": "Semetary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Salem's ---------\".",
        "answer": "Lot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"The Dead --------\".",
        "answer": "Zone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This Shakespearean king was the actual king of Scotland for 17 years.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This girl hid from the Nazis in Amsterdam.",
        "answer": "Anne Frank"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What Shakespearean play features the line: A plague on both your houses?",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What did Jeannie C. Riley describe as \"a little Peyton Place\"?",
        "answer": "Harper Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What other name does Stephen King write under?",
        "answer": "Richard Bachman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What publication was subtitled The What's New Magazine?",
        "answer": "Popular Science"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What was the name of Mother Goose's son?",
        "answer": "Jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What's Penthouse's sister publication for women?",
        "answer": "Viva"
    },
    {
        "category": "Litterature",
        "question": "Homer wrote this account of the Trojan War.",
        "answer": "Iliad"
    },
    {
        "category": "Logic",
        "question": "You are in a room where all walls face south.  A bear walks by.  What color is it?",
        "answer": "White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A U.S. dime is worth --- cents.",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A line drawn from an angle of a triangle to the mid-point of the opposite side is a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "median"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with three equal sides is called -------.",
        "answer": "equilateral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with two equal sides is called ----------.",
        "answer": "isosceles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 180 degrees and less than 360 degrees is a(n) -------- angle.",
        "answer": "reflex"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees is said to be ---------.",
        "answer": "obtuse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An integer that is greater than 1 and is divisible only by itself and 1 is known as a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "prime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Approximately how many inches are there in one meter?",
        "answer": "thirty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Arc, radius, and sector are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "He is known as \"The Father of Geometry\".",
        "answer": "Euclid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many corners are there in a cube?",
        "answer": "eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many nickles are there in 2.25?",
        "answer": "forty five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "If you cut through a solid sphere what shape will the flat area be?",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Name the number system which uses only the symbols 1 and 0.",
        "answer": "The binary system"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The angles inside a square total ------- degrees.",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The mathematical study of properties of lines, angels, etc., is --------.",
        "answer": "geometry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The space occupied by a body is called its ------.",
        "answer": "volume"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The square root of 1 is?",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Two angles that total 180 degrees are called -------.",
        "answer": "supplementary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What geometric shape has 4 equal sides?",
        "answer": "square"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A baby doctor is a ---------.",
        "answer": "pediatrician"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A bone specialist is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "osteopath"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A loss of memory is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "amnesia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a --------.",
        "answer": "laxative"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A non-cancerous tumor is said to be -------.",
        "answer": "benign"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A thread used in surgery to tie a bleeding blood vessel is called a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "ligature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Carditis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "heart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Doctors often have this instrument around their neck.",
        "answer": "stethoscope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Due to a lack of vitamin C, sailors used to contract this disease.",
        "answer": "scurvy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Encephalitis affects the --------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Gastritis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "stomach"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hammer, anvil, and stirrup are parts of the --------.",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "He discovered the process of vaccination for prevention of smallpox.",
        "answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hepatitis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "Liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?",
        "answer": "two hundred and six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many pints of blood does the average human have in his/her body?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In the field of psychiatry this term means self-love.",
        "answer": "narcissism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In what organ of the body is insulin produced?",
        "answer": "pancreas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a clear watery solution known as the \"aqueous humor\" found?",
        "answer": "eye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a pulmonary disease located?",
        "answer": "lung"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is your \"hypothalmus\" located?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Infantile Paralysis is commonly known as --------.",
        "answer": "polio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Meningitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Myositis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "muscles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the hardest substance in the human body.",
        "answer": "enamel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest artery in the human body.",
        "answer": "aorta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest gland in the human body.",
        "answer": "liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Osteomyelitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "bones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Peritonitis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "abdomen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Prosthetics deals with the making of ----------.",
        "answer": "artificial limbs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Tarsus, metatarsus, and phalanges are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "foot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The branch of medicine dealing with curing by operative procedures is --------.",
        "answer": "surgery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The lack of this element in the diet is a cause of goitre.",
        "answer": "iodine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The largest single organ of the human body is the --------.",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The medical name for the voice box is the ---------.",
        "answer": "larynx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The teeth used for biting or cutting are known as -------.",
        "answer": "incisors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These animals were once used to bleed the sick.",
        "answer": "leeches"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These attach muscles to bones or cartilage.",
        "answer": "tendons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This branch of medicine deals with old age and its diseases.",
        "answer": "geriatrics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This disease consists of a purposeless, continual growth of white blood cells.",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This fingerlike projection is attached to the large intestine.",
        "answer": "appendix"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This is known as \"The Royal Disease\".",
        "answer": "haemophilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This large bean-shaped lymph gland can expand and contract as needed.",
        "answer": "spleen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This membrane controls the amount of light entering the eye.",
        "answer": "iris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This organ is a small pouch that stores bile.",
        "answer": "gall bladder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This parasite lives in the intestines of man and animals.",
        "answer": "tapeworm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This small gland attached to the brain exerts a control over growth.",
        "answer": "pituitary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Ulna, radius, and clavicle are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "bone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What disease is also known as \"rubella\"?",
        "answer": "German measles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What hormone is produced by the adrenal glands?",
        "answer": "adrenaline"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is a skin specialist called?",
        "answer": "dermatologist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?",
        "answer": "parasite"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the biggest disqualifying factor for prospective astronauts?",
        "answer": "eyesight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the medical term for cancer of the blood?",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the name of the bone in the lower leg?",
        "answer": "tibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?",
        "answer": "lead poisoning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?",
        "answer": "big toe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where do you find the medulla oblongata?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where in the body is the tiniest human muscle?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Which disease is also known as \"Hansen's Disease\"?",
        "answer": "leprosy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "With what body part is otology involved?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "If the groundhog sees his shadow on Feb. 2, there will be how many more weeks of bad weather?",
        "answer": "six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "This dry, warm wind flows eastward down the slopes of the Rocky Mountains.",
        "answer": "Chinook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ------- Borgnine.",
        "answer": "Ernest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: -------- Hackman.",
        "answer": "Gene"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Nimoy.",
        "answer": "Leonard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Savalas.",
        "answer": "Telly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what protruded from the rocks?",
        "answer": "Statue of Liberty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Barbara Streisand was the female lead in \"Hello, Dolly\".  Who was the male lead?",
        "answer": "Walter Matthau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Laughton played Quasimodo in this epic film.",
        "answer": "Hunchback of Notre Dame"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Darth Vader was the villan in the movie, \"---- Wars\".",
        "answer": "Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: An Officer and a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Gentleman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: Fahrenheit --------. (a number)",
        "answer": "451"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: The Last Days of ---------. (a city)",
        "answer": "Pompeii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: ------ (a number) Leagues Under the Sea.",
        "answer": "20,000"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Forrest ---- liked shrimp.",
        "answer": "Gump"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed \"The Godfather\".",
        "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed the movie E.T.",
        "answer": "Stephen Spielberg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He played Superman in the 1978 movie version.",
        "answer": "Christopher Reeve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in \"Conan the Barbarian\".",
        "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in, \"City Lights\".",
        "answer": "Charlie Chaplin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was known as the \"Elephant Man\".",
        "answer": "Joseph Merrick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was the villain in \"Star Wars\".",
        "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Giant, Written on the Wind, and A Farewell to Arms.",
        "answer": "Rock Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Spartacus, The Vikings, and Ulysses.",
        "answer": "Kirk Douglas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In \"Gone With the Wind\", Scarlett regains her wealth by investing in what type of business?",
        "answer": "sawmill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In 1975 Jack Nicholson won the best actor Oscar for his role in this film.",
        "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the 1996 version of \"Romeo and Juliet\", who played Juliet?",
        "answer": "Claire Danes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film \"Bright Eyes\", Shirley Temple sang about this boat.",
        "answer": "The Good Ship Lollipop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In this 1968 film the husband of an unsuspecting young wife becomes involved with a witch's coven.",
        "answer": "Rosemary's Baby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which Disney movie is the song \"So This Is Love\"?",
        "answer": "Cinderella"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the Disney cartoon in which the character \"Belle\" appears.",
        "answer": "Beauty and the Beast"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the actor who played the leading role in \"The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly\".",
        "answer": "Clint Eastwood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the first full length color cartoon talking picture.",
        "answer": "Snow White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the musical film named after a state.",
        "answer": "Oklahoma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Nick Nolte and Eddie Murphy star in this 1982 film.",
        "answer": "48 Hours"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Peter Sellers is best known for his role as Inspector ---------.",
        "answer": "Clouseau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played Lois Lane in the 1978 film version of \"Superman\".",
        "answer": "Margot Kidder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played a Polish refugee in \"Sophie's Choice\".",
        "answer": "Meryl Streep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played the lead role in \"Coal Miner's Daughter\".",
        "answer": "Sissy Spacek"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She starred in the 1952 film, \"Niagara\".",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The first 18 minutes of this movie is black and white.",
        "answer": "Wizard of Oz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical play?",
        "answer": "Fiddler On The Roof"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The two rival gangs in \"West Side Story\" were the Sharks and the ---------.",
        "answer": "Jets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This 1974 film started a run of nostalgia culminating in the TV series \"Happy Days\".",
        "answer": "American Graffiti"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This Disney movie relies heavily on computer animation.",
        "answer": "TRON"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This actress appeared in \"St. Elmo's Fire\", \"The Scarlett Letter\", and \"Striptease\".",
        "answer": "Demi Moore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This actress was Miss Hungary of 1936.",
        "answer": "Zsa-Zsa Gabor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film starring Julie Andrews and Christopher Plummer wont he best picture Oscar for 1965.",
        "answer": "Sound of Music"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film starring Richard Beymer and Natalie Wood won the best picture Oscar for 1961.",
        "answer": "West Side Story"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This film was an ambitious concert sequence of cartoons by Walt Disney.",
        "answer": "Fantasia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This is a classic film about a huge gorilla.",
        "answer": "King Kong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This magic word was in the movie, \"Mary Poppins\".",
        "answer": "Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie directed by Woody Allen won the best picture Oscar in 1978.",
        "answer": "Annie Hall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie is about the migration of poor workers from the dust bowl to the Californian fruit valleys.",
        "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This movie starring Marlon Brando won the best picture award in 1972.",
        "answer": "The Godfather"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the first 3-D film.",
        "answer": "Bwana Devil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the first cartoon talking picture.",
        "answer": "Steamboat Willie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the sequel to \"Star Wars\".",
        "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "This was the sequel to \"The Empire Strikes Back\".",
        "answer": "Return of the Jedi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actor appeared in all three of these films, Straw Dogs, Midnight Cowboy, and The Graduate?",
        "answer": "Dustin Hoffman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actress has received the most Oscar nominations?",
        "answer": "Katherine Hepburn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What actress's real name was Frances Gumm?",
        "answer": "Judy Garland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What city's police force did Charlie Chan work with?",
        "answer": "Honolulu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What color was Bullitt's car?",
        "answer": "Green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"The King and I\"?",
        "answer": "Siam (Thailand)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What detective duo was featured in Mystery at Devil's Paw?",
        "answer": "Hardy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What does the statue of Oscar stand on?",
        "answer": "A Reel of Film"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What famous animal character called \"Skull Island\" home?",
        "answer": "King Kong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?",
        "answer": "True Grit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is Hawkeye's full name in M.A.S.H.?",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin Pierce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the destination of the plane at the end of the film \"Casablanca\"?",
        "answer": "Lisbon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Pearce Brosnan's first James Bond film?",
        "answer": "Goldeneye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the Volkswagen in the film, \"The Love Bug\"?",
        "answer": "Herbie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the film, \"Bambi\"?",
        "answer": "Thumper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the skunk in the film, \"Bambi\"?",
        "answer": "Flower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the whale that swallowed Pinocchio.",
        "answer": "Monstro"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the stage name of Greta Gustafson?",
        "answer": "Greta Garbo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the title of the 1996 sequel to \"Terms of Endearment\"?",
        "answer": "Morning Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What kind of creature was Chewbacca in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Wookiee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What two words are normally at the end of most movies?",
        "answer": "The End"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was \"Rocky's\" last name?",
        "answer": "Balboa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Citizen Kane's dying word?",
        "answer": "Rosebud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Dorothy's last name in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Gale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Rocky's nickname in the ring?",
        "answer": "The Italian Stallion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Sir Alec Guinness's role in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Obi-Wan Kenobi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first film directed by Robert Redford?",
        "answer": "Ordinary People"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Ashley Wilkes' plantation in \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Twelve Oaks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Han Solo's spaceship in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Millennium Falcon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Luke's strange little advisor in \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?",
        "answer": "Yoda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the motel in the film \"Psycho\"?",
        "answer": "Bates Motel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the setting for \"The Sound of Music\"?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which actor said, \"Love means never having to say you're sorry\"?",
        "answer": "Ryan O'Neil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character in \"Forrest Gump\" loved shrimp?",
        "answer": "Bubba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character sang \"Come Out, Come Out, Wherever You Are\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Glinda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which character sang, \"When you wish upon a star..\" in Disney's \"Pinocchio\"?",
        "answer": "Jiminy Cricket"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which comedy duo did the famous, \"Who's on first?\" routine?",
        "answer": "Abbott and Costello"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which planet was the \"Planet of the Apes\"?",
        "answer": "Earth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who co-starred with Julie Andrews in \"Mary Poppins\"?",
        "answer": "Dick Van Dyke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?",
        "answer": "Ellen Degeneres"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Warren Beatty's sister?",
        "answer": "Shirley MacLaine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the fastest mouse in all of Mexico?",
        "answer": "Speedy Gonzalez"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the male lead in the \"Naked Gun\" movies?",
        "answer": "Leslie Nielsen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the voice of Darth Vadar?",
        "answer": "James Earl Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played \"Robin\" to Val Kilmer's \"Batman\"?",
        "answer": "Christopher O'Donnell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Brad Pitt's cop partner in the movie \"Seven\"?",
        "answer": "Morgan Freeman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Dorothy in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?",
        "answer": "Judy Garland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Garth in \"Wayne's World\"?",
        "answer": "Dana Carvey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Matt Helm in the movies?",
        "answer": "Dean Martin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Scarlette O'Hara in \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Vivien Leigh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the 'Wicked Witch of the West' in \"The Wizard of Oz\"",
        "answer": "Margaret Hamilton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the role of Richard Blaine in Casablanca?",
        "answer": "Humphrey Bogart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who plays the character of the only escapee from Alcatraz in the movie \"The Rock\"?",
        "answer": "Sean Connery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who portrayed Han Solo in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "Harrison Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who portrayed Moses in \"The Ten Commandments\"?",
        "answer": "Charlton Heston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who produced, directed and starred in \"Citizen Kane\"?",
        "answer": "Orson Welles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred with John Travolta in the movie \"Broken Arrow\"?",
        "answer": "Christian Slater"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was C3PO's sidekick in \"Star Wars\"?",
        "answer": "R2D2"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "\"He's So Fine\", \"One Fine Day\" and \"A Love So Fine\" where hits for what fine group?",
        "answer": "The Chiffons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "\"Joy to the World\" was a hit in 1971 for what band with three lead vocalists?",
        "answer": "Three Dog Night"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Besides \"Auld Lang Syne\" and \"For He's a Jolly Good Fellow\", what is the most frequently sung song in English?",
        "answer": "Happy Birthday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Fifties rock \"n\" roll was revived by what greased hair, T-shirted, TV frequenting group?",
        "answer": "Sha Na Na"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Jerry Lee Lewis had Great ----- Of Fire.",
        "answer": "balls!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Name Jerry Garcia's long lived group.",
        "answer": "The Grateful Dead"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "The Who's rock musical stars Elton John.  It's called --------.",
        "answer": "Tommy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "This female artist enjoyed sucess on both popular and country & western stations with such tunes as \"Let Me Be There\" and \"Have You Never Been Mellow.\"",
        "answer": "Olivia Newton-John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "This was the Beatle's first film.",
        "answer": "A Hard Day's Night"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Through 1963 this duo's total record sales exceeded 18 million with successes including \"Cathy's Clown\" and \"Wake Up Little Suzie\".",
        "answer": "The Everly Brothers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What Procol Harem tune was based on the Bach cantata \"Sleepers Awake\"?",
        "answer": "A Whiter Shade of Pale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What band recorded the 1978 hit album: \"Briefcase Full of Blues\"?",
        "answer": "The Blues Brothers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What city is also known as Music City, U.S.A.?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What country singer/songwriter (and sometimes actor) is known as \"the country outlaw\"?",
        "answer": "Willie Nelson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What entertainer is allowing one of his songs to be used in a government campaign to beat drunk driving?",
        "answer": "Michael Jackson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What famous classical composer continued to compose great music after becoming deaf?",
        "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What famous singer was known to give automobiles to complete strangers?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What group refused to have their pictures taken while they were not in their makeup?",
        "answer": "Kiss"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What group's biggest-ever hit was Be My Baby?",
        "answer": "The Ronettes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song by Don McLean talks about the day Buddy Holly died?",
        "answer": "American Pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song did Aretha Franklin sing in \"The Blues Brothers\"?",
        "answer": "Think"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was Elvis Presley's wife's name?",
        "answer": "Priscilla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was The Beatles' biggest hit single?",
        "answer": "Hey Jude"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What's the name of B.B. King's guitar?",
        "answer": "Lucille"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which of Paul Simon's musical characters was told to hop on the bus?",
        "answer": "Gus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who invented the electrical bass?",
        "answer": "Leo Fender"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who recorded the 1957 hit \"Tammy\"?",
        "answer": "Debby Reynolds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who recorded the lengthy song: \"In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida\" in 1969?",
        "answer": "Iron Butterfly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the first singer in Genesis?",
        "answer": "Peter Gabriel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Whose theme song was Back In The Saddle Again?",
        "answer": "Gene Autry's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "The sea gods had a three-pronged spear called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "trident"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "This Greek mountain was known as the home of the gods.",
        "answer": "Olympus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "What has no reflection, no shadow, and can't stand the smell of garlic?",
        "answer": "vampire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "What's heaven to fallen Norse warriors?",
        "answer": "Valhalla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Where did Robin Hood supposedly live?",
        "answer": "Sherwood Forest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Which ancient continent is said to be submerged?",
        "answer": "Atlantis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Natural History",
        "question": "Name the largest of the dinosaurs.",
        "answer": "brachiosaurus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Natural History",
        "question": "The remains of prehistoric organisms that have been preserved in rocks are called --------.",
        "answer": "fossils"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A \"sirocco\" refers to a type of ----------.",
        "answer": "wind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A calm ocean region near the equator.",
        "answer": "doldrums"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A coral island consisting of a ring of rock enclosing a central lagoon is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "atoll"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A great wave resulting from an earthquakes is called a (an) --------.",
        "answer": "tsunami"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A group of gorillas is known as a -----------.",
        "answer": "band"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A group of kangaroos is known as a -------.",
        "answer": "troop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A hot spring which shoots steam into the air is a -------.",
        "answer": "geyser"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A one-humped camel is called a ---------.",
        "answer": "dromedary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A relationship between two different types of organism which live together for their mutual benefit.",
        "answer": "symbiosis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "A terrapin is a type of ---------.",
        "answer": "turtle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "An animal is a bird if it has -------.",
        "answer": "feathers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "An animal is a fish if it has ---------.",
        "answer": "gills"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Corolla, filament and stigma are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "flower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Dense sea-water swamps along coasts of hot countries are called --------.",
        "answer": "mangroves"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Dogs bark.  What do donkeys do?",
        "answer": "bray"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Excluding man, what is the longest-lived land mammal?",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Fandible, lateral line, and dorsal fin are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "From what animal is \"ambergis\" obtained?",
        "answer": "sperm whale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How man legs does a crab have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How many teats does a cow have?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How many tentacles does a squid have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Imperial, Buck, and Luna are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "moth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Knife, Clown, and Pencil are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Linseed oil is obtained from the seed of which plant?",
        "answer": "flax"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Maxillary palps, abdomen, and metathorax are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "insect"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the fastest land animal over a prolonged distance (1,000 yd. plus)",
        "answer": "antelope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the heaviest breed of domestic dog.",
        "answer": "St. Bernard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the heaviest flying bird of prey.",
        "answer": "condor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the largest living bird.",
        "answer": "ostrich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the largest web-footed bird.",
        "answer": "albatross"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the longest venomous snake.",
        "answer": "cobra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the mammal living at the highest altitude.",
        "answer": "yak"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the most venomous spider.",
        "answer": "black widow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the only native North American marsupial.",
        "answer": "opossum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the slowest moving land mammal.",
        "answer": "sloth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the smallest breed of dog.",
        "answer": "chihuahua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Name the wild dogs of Australia.",
        "answer": "dingo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Paper is made from the pulp of -----.",
        "answer": "wood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Snakes are reptiles.  What are frogs?",
        "answer": "amphibians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Some animals spend the winter in a sleep-like state known as ---------.",
        "answer": "hibernation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what?",
        "answer": "rattlesnake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The fins of which fish are made into a soup?",
        "answer": "shark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The four stages in the life-cycle of an insect are: egg, adult, pupa, and --------.",
        "answer": "larva"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "The koala bear eats the leaves from this tree.",
        "answer": "eucalyptus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "These marine crustaceans often attach themselves to the hulls of ships.",
        "answer": "barnacles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This African animal kills the most people.",
        "answer": "crocodile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is armed with bony plates and rolls up into a ball if frightened.",
        "answer": "armadillo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is kept as a house pet to kill cobras.",
        "answer": "mongoose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is normally measured in \"hands\".",
        "answer": "horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is the symbol of the U.S. Democratic Party.",
        "answer": "donkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal is the symbol of the U.S. Republican Party.",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal's name is the same as that given to a high church official.",
        "answer": "cardinal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This animal's shell is used to make attractive jewelry.",
        "answer": "abalone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This bird lays its eggs in the nests of other birds.",
        "answer": "cuckoo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the largest of the deer family.",
        "answer": "moose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the main food of the blue whale.",
        "answer": "plankton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This is the only mammal with four knees.",
        "answer": "elephant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This order of insects contains the most species.",
        "answer": "beetle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This organic gem is a deep red secretion from a marine animal.",
        "answer": "coral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This small animal is trained to hunt rats and rabbits.",
        "answer": "ferret"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This two ton animal can gallop at over 50 miles an hour.",
        "answer": "rhinoceros"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "This ugly creature has patches of red on his rear-end.",
        "answer": "mandrill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Walrus tusks are made of --------.",
        "answer": "ivory"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What are the pouched animals called?",
        "answer": "marsupials"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What bird is an excellent swimmer, but can't fly?",
        "answer": "penguin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What does a camel store in its hump?",
        "answer": "fat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What fish is the fastest?",
        "answer": "sailfish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of larks called?",
        "answer": "exaltation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of peacocks called?",
        "answer": "muster"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a group of whales called?",
        "answer": "pod"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male goose called?",
        "answer": "gander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male swan called?",
        "answer": "cob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a male swine called?",
        "answer": "boar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a young goose called?",
        "answer": "gosling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is a young swan called?",
        "answer": "cygnet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is an emasculated stallion called?",
        "answer": "gelding"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is another term for a black leopard?",
        "answer": "panther"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the horn of a rhinoceros made of?",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the only dog that doesn't have a pink tongue?",
        "answer": "chow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the world's longest snake?",
        "answer": "python"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What large herbivore sleeps only one hour a night?",
        "answer": "antelope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What name is given to a female calf?",
        "answer": "heifer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What plant is opium derived from?",
        "answer": "poppy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What travels in gaggles?",
        "answer": "geese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What type of animal is a wallaby?",
        "answer": "marsupial"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What type of animal lives in a formicary?",
        "answer": "ant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a female fox?",
        "answer": "vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a female sheep?",
        "answer": "ewe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male ass? (Other than that the word used for that *-^*&%@! ex-boyfriend.)",
        "answer": "jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male deer?",
        "answer": "buck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What word is used for a male duck?",
        "answer": "drake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Neture",
        "question": "What do oak trees grow from?",
        "answer": "acorns"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "What would be kept in an \"aviary\"?",
        "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "Where is the Ocean of Storms located?",
        "answer": "On the moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-)",
        "question": "Who is Robert Zimmermann?",
        "answer": "Bob Dylan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling ;-P",
        "question": "What are white dwarfs and red giants?",
        "answer": "stars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not telling ;-P",
        "question": "What are these: chrysolite, beryl, jasper, and tourmaline?",
        "answer": "gems"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Jack and Jill went up a ---- to fetch a pail of water?",
        "answer": "hill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Name the nursery rhyme mother whos last name is that of a bird?",
        "answer": "goose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The energy which a body possesses by virtue of its motion is called --------.",
        "answer": "kinetic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The pivot point of a lever is called the ---------.",
        "answer": "fulcrum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The process of water changing to water vapor is known as -------.",
        "answer": "evaporation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as ---------.",
        "answer": "acceleration"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "The visible spectrum of light ranges from red to --------.",
        "answer": "violet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "True Or False: Contrary to popular belief, a lightbulb actually absorbs darkness?",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Two 1.5 volt batteries, when connected in series, produces _ volts.",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Water freezes at _ degrees Celcius.",
        "answer": "zero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Water freezes at -- degrees Fahrenheit.",
        "answer": "thirty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "What is measured by a Geiger counter?",
        "answer": "radioactivity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "When light waves pass from one medium into another they change direction.  This is called ---------.",
        "answer": "refraction"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Work done, equals force multiplied by --------.",
        "answer": "distance"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "For what does O.P.E.C. stand?",
        "answer": "The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "He was elected President of France, in 1981.",
        "answer": "Francios Mitterrand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Name Ronald Reagan's first wife.",
        "answer": "Wyman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Presidents",
        "question": "U.S. President, Woodrow ----------.",
        "answer": "Wilson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "How is the state of Mississippi spelled?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Name the circular plastic media you put in a CD-ROM drive.",
        "answer": "CD"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "On a standard computer keyboard, this is the letter just to the right of Z.",
        "answer": "x"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "The longest key on your keyboard is the ----- bar.",
        "answer": "space"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "The season ------ comes right after Spring.",
        "answer": "summer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "There are -- seconds in a minute.",
        "answer": "sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "This is required to make all electric things work?",
        "answer": "electricity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a blue crayon?",
        "answer": "blue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a green crayon?",
        "answer": "green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What color is a red crayon?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "What company makes Microsoft Windows 2000?",
        "answer": "microsoft"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Whats radar spelled backwards?",
        "answer": "radar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Quick!",
        "question": "Whats the abbreviation for United States of America?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Quick! Where's my mirror? ;-",
        "question": "When spelled backwards, the word \"retupmoc\" becomes what?",
        "answer": "computer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Followers of the Unification Church are called --------.",
        "answer": "Moonies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He led the Israelites out of Egypt.",
        "answer": "Moses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He was the first King of the Hebrews.",
        "answer": "Saul"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "He was the second King of Israel.",
        "answer": "David"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "In what month is Christmas observed?",
        "answer": "December"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Name the holiest day in the Jewish calendar.",
        "answer": "Yom Kippur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "On which mountain did Moses receive the Ten Commandments?",
        "answer": "Sinai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Which city is sacred to Jews, Christians, and Muslims?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Who founded Mormonism?",
        "answer": "Joseph Smith"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Who founded the People's Temple Commune?",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A flat-bottomed conical laboratory flask with a narrow neck is called a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "erlenmeyer flask"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A phrenologist reads ---------.",
        "answer": "skulls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A point to which rays of light converge is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "focus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "A shallow dish with a cover, used for science specimens is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "petri dish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Acetylsalicylic acid is more commonly known as ---------.",
        "answer": "aspirin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Botany and Zoology combined make up the science of -------.",
        "answer": "biology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "By what chemical process do plants manufacture food?",
        "answer": "photosynthesis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "By what name is Lysergic acid diethylamide better known?",
        "answer": "LSD"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Cetology is the study of --------.",
        "answer": "whales"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Circuits can be wired in series or in ---------.",
        "answer": "parallel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Cocci, Spirilla, and Streptococci are types of --------.",
        "answer": "bacteria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Deoxyribonucleic acid is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "DNA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Dermatitis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Epidermal cells, palisade cells, and veins are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "leaf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Ethylene glycol is frequently used in automobiles.. How?",
        "answer": "anti-freeze"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Forked, Sheet, and Ball are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "lightning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Growing plants in liquids rather than soil is known as --------.",
        "answer": "hydroponics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He designed the first feasible automobile with an internal combustion engine.",
        "answer": "Karl Freidrich Benz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He invented \"bifocal\" lenses for eyeglasses.",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He is known for his theory of \"Evolution\".",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He transmitted radio signals across the Atlantic in 1901.",
        "answer": "Enrico Marconi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "He wrote \"Sexual Behaviour in the Human Male\" in 1948.",
        "answer": "Alfred Kinsey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "How many degrees does the earth rotate each hour?",
        "answer": "fifteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "In which country was the match invented?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Nitrous oxide is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "laughing gas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Nuclear membrane, cytoplasm, and nucleus are parts of a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "cell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Pulp, crown, and root are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "tooth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Quinine is added to water to make -------.",
        "answer": "tonic water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Sound Navigation Ranging is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "sonar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The Kelvin scale is used to measure ---------.",
        "answer": "temperature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The filament of a regular light bulb is usually made of --------.",
        "answer": "tungsten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The instrument used in geometry to measure angles is a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "protractor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The name for the Russian equivalent of Skylab is --------.",
        "answer": "Salyut"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The second space shuttle was named ----------.",
        "answer": "Columbia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "The vernal equinox is the beginning of --------.",
        "answer": "spring"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This Russian scientist used dogs to study conditioned reflexes.",
        "answer": "Ivan Pavlov"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This is like an airplane but has its propeller on top instead.",
        "answer": "helicopter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This is the reading system used by the blind.",
        "answer": "Braille"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "This science deals with the motion of projectiles.",
        "answer": "ballistics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "To make a car go backwards you have to put it in what gear?",
        "answer": "reverse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What are these: Ceres, Juno, Iris, and Flora?",
        "answer": "asteroids"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What branch of science studies the motion of air and the forces acting on objects in air?",
        "answer": "aerodynamics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What did Lewis E. Waterman invent in 1884?",
        "answer": "fountain pen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does the \"lithosphere\" refer to?",
        "answer": "The earth's crust"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does the Binet test measure?",
        "answer": "intelligence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who invented dynamite?",
        "answer": "Alfred Nobel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who is known as the father of genetics?",
        "answer": "Gregor Mendel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As bold as -------.",
        "answer": "brass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As clean as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "whistle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As clear as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "bell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As cute as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "button"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As easy as --------.",
        "answer": "pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As fit as a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "fiddle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As good as ---------.",
        "answer": "gold"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As graceful as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "swan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As large as --------.",
        "answer": "life"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As loud as ---------.",
        "answer": "thunder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pale as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "ghost"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pleased as ---------.",
        "answer": "punch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As pretty as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "picture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As proud as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "peacock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As quiet as a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "mouse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As sick as a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "dog"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As sly as a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "fox"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As smart as a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "whip"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "Fresh as a(n) --------------.",
        "answer": "daisy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Baltimore --------.",
        "answer": "Orioles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Toronto ---------.",
        "answer": "Bluejays"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Boston -----------.",
        "answer": "Celtics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Denver ---------.",
        "answer": "Nuggets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Los Angeles ---------.",
        "answer": "Lakers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The New York ----------.",
        "answer": "Knicks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Seattle --------.",
        "answer": "Supersonics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Utah --------.",
        "answer": "Jazz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Baltimore --------.",
        "answer": "Colts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Buffalo -------.",
        "answer": "Bills"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Cincinnati ---------.",
        "answer": "Bengals"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Cleveland --------.",
        "answer": "Browns"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Dallas ---------.",
        "answer": "Cowboys"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Denver ---------.",
        "answer": "Broncos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Miami ----------.",
        "answer": "Dolphins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Minnesota -------.",
        "answer": "Vikings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The New Orleans ----------.",
        "answer": "Saints"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Seattle -------.",
        "answer": "Seahawks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "He holds the NHL record for the most goals scored during the regular season.",
        "answer": "Wayne Gretzky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "He was the NBA, MVP in 1976, 77, and 80.",
        "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Boston -----------.",
        "answer": "Bruins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Buffalo ---------.",
        "answer": "Sabres"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Calgary ----------.",
        "answer": "Flames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Chicago ---------.",
        "answer": "Blackhawks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Detroit --------.",
        "answer": "Red Wings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Edmonton ----------.",
        "answer": "Oilers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Los Angeles --------.",
        "answer": "Kings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Montreal --------.",
        "answer": "Canadians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Pittsburgh ----------.",
        "answer": "Penguins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The St. Louis ----------.",
        "answer": "Blues"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Toronto -------.",
        "answer": "Maple Leafs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Vancouver --------.",
        "answer": "Canucks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many feet high is a basketball net?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many games must you win to win a normal set in tennis?",
        "answer": "six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many minutes is a major penalty in hockey?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many minutes is each period of hockey?",
        "answer": "twenty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players are there on a soccer team?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players are there on a water polo team?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many players make up a field hockey team?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many points are awarded for a safety touch in football?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many referees work a soccer game?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many seams are there on a football? (American)",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many sides does a home-plate have?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In pro football a \"sudden death\" period lasts how many minutes long?",
        "answer": "fifteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In ten-pin bowling, how many points does a perfect game consist of?",
        "answer": "three hundred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In this team sport each player gets a chance to play every position.",
        "answer": "volleyball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In what sport is the Heisman trophy awarded?",
        "answer": "American football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which city is the Cotton Bowl played?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which city is the Hockey Hall of Fame located?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which game or sport is a \"Zamboni\" used?",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is a \"hole-in-one\" possible?",
        "answer": "golf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?",
        "answer": "sailing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the Cy Young Trophy awarded?",
        "answer": "baseball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the Davis Cup awarded?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term \"love\" used?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term \"wishbone\" used?",
        "answer": "football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport is the term, \"Hang ten\" used?",
        "answer": "surfing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In which sport would you find the \"slapshot\".",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Name the hockey trophy awarded to the player demonstrating the best sportsmanship.",
        "answer": "The Lady Byng Trophy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "On what type of surface are the tennis matches at Wimbledon played?",
        "answer": "grass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "She was \"Sports Illustrated's\" first female \"Sportsman of the Year\".",
        "answer": "Billie Jean King"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Soccer: The New York ---------.",
        "answer": "Cosmos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in this city.",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The Japanese martial art of fencing is called --------.",
        "answer": "kendo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The person who carries the golfer's clubs is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "caddie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The white marks intersecting each five yard line are called --------.",
        "answer": "hash marks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This is the most coveted trophy in Candian football.",
        "answer": "Grey Cup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This sport allows substitutions without a stoppage in play.",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This sport is called the \"American pastime\".",
        "answer": "baseball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This team won their first World Series in 1969.",
        "answer": "New York Mets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "This traditional Japanese wrestling sport takes place in a circular ring.",
        "answer": "sumo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Two under par on a hole of golf is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "eagle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What are large snow bumps known as in skiing terms?",
        "answer": "moguls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What do runners pass to each other in a relay race?",
        "answer": "baton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What do the letters ERA mean in baseball?",
        "answer": "Earned Run Average"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What does TKO stand for?",
        "answer": "Technical Knock Out"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What football player rushed for 2,003 yards in 1973?",
        "answer": "OJ Simpson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What game features the largest ball?",
        "answer": "earthball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is it called when a football team loses possession of the ball due to a misplay?",
        "answer": "turnover"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the heaviest class of weight-lifting?",
        "answer": "super heavyweight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What number wood is a driver in golf?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport do the Harlem Globetrotters play?",
        "answer": "basketball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?",
        "answer": "rugby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport would you helicopter to the Bugaboos for?",
        "answer": "skiing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What trophy is awarded to the winner of the NHL play-offs?",
        "answer": "Stanley Cup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What vehicles are involved in the \"Tour de France\"?",
        "answer": "bicycles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What was football player Dick Lane's nickname?",
        "answer": "Night Train"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What's the nickname of the University of Georgia football team?",
        "answer": "Bulldogs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Where are the U.S. Tennis Open Championships held?",
        "answer": "Flushing Meadows, NY"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which NFL team's defensive unit was nicknamed \"The Purple People Eaters\"?",
        "answer": "Minnesota Vikings"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which country won the World Cup of Soccer in 1982.",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which football team was nicknamed the \"Orange Crush\"?",
        "answer": "Denver Broncos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which is the only position in soccer allowed to handle the ball?",
        "answer": "goalkeeper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which position is usually played by the tallest member on a basketball team?",
        "answer": "centre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which sport has a movement called a \"telemark\"?",
        "answer": "skiing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which sport uses stones and brooms?",
        "answer": "curling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which swimming stroke is named after an insect?",
        "answer": "butterfly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was known as the \"Sultan of Swat\"?",
        "answer": "Babe Ruth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the 1978 Wimbledon Women's Singles champ?",
        "answer": "Martina Navratilova"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the first NHL player to score 50 goals in one season?",
        "answer": "Maurice Richard <-- pronounced \"Reeee-shard\""
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the first to win the grand slam of tennis?",
        "answer": "Don Budge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With which sport is Chris Evert Lloyd identified?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Stand on your heads.... NOW! ;-)",
        "question": "When read upside down, what does the term \"umop apisdn\" signify?",
        "answer": "upside down"
    },
    {
        "category": "Stupid things to do ;-)",
        "question": "If you look at the sun long enough, you go -----.",
        "answer": "blind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Summertime",
        "question": "This is the sandy area nearest the ocean.",
        "answer": "beach"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What did TVs IMF stand for?",
        "answer": "Impossible Mission Forces"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first network series devoted entirely to rock and roll?",
        "answer": "American Bandstand"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Carl in Five Easy Pieces before going to Walton's Mountain?",
        "answer": "Waite"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Chief Marshall of the Mickey Mouse Club?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Triplets",
        "question": "Hook, line and -----------.",
        "answer": "sinker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "\"7X\" was used to refer to the secret ingredient of which drink?",
        "answer": "Coca Cola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A \"pigskin\" is another name for a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "football"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A can of Pepsi holds -- fluid ounces.",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "A foot-long ruler is -- inches long.",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Most men do this each morning, using a razor.",
        "answer": "shave"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Most people wear a watch on their ---- wrist.",
        "answer": "left"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Name the implement that removes water from your windshield on your car?",
        "answer": "wiper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Traffic Trivia:  Red means stop, ----- means go.",
        "answer": "green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What US state has the Worlds Champion Chili Cookoff every year?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What bit of Bobby Goldsboro syrup focused on a dying young wife?",
        "answer": "honey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What did Sally Rogers always wear in her hair?",
        "answer": "a bow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What does the typical American eat 263 of each year? not pizza!!",
        "answer": "eggs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What game show had people dressed up funny?",
        "answer": "Let's Make A Deal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What is Grimace of the McDonald's characters?",
        "answer": "A tastebud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was Simple Simon fishing for in his mother's pail?",
        "answer": "whale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the Akla-Seltzer boy?",
        "answer": "Speedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the dog in RCA Victor's trademark?",
        "answer": "Nipper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What's the telephone area code for Chicago?",
        "answer": "312"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Howdy Doody live?",
        "answer": "Doodyville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Where were Archie and Edith Bunker's chairs enshrined?",
        "answer": "The Smithsonian Institute"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Who is also known as Mr. Warmth?",
        "answer": "Don Rickles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Who is known as \"the world's oldest teenager\"?",
        "answer": "Dick Clark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Ball and --------.",
        "answer": "chain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Peace and ---------.",
        "answer": "quiet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: nap, walk, call?",
        "answer": "cat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: painting, bowl, nail?",
        "answer": "finger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Asssociation",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: rat, blue, cottage?",
        "answer": "cheese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "A castle or enclosed place.",
        "answer": "FORt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Make holes through something.",
        "answer": "perFORate"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Many trees.",
        "answer": "FORest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Pardon.",
        "answer": "FORgive"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'ten'",
        "question": "A choice cut of meat.",
        "answer": "tenderloi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Abbreviations",
        "question": "What do the initials 'VCP' stand for?",
        "answer": "Video Cassette Player"
    },
    {
        "category": "Abbreviations",
        "question": "What do the initials 'VCR' stand for?",
        "answer": "Video Cassette Recorder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Abbreviations",
        "question": "What does 'A&W' (of root beer fame) stand for ?",
        "answer": "Allen & Wright"
    },
    {
        "category": "Abbreviations",
        "question": "What does 'AOL' stand for?",
        "answer": "America Online"
    },
    {
        "category": "Abbreviations",
        "question": "What does S.O.S. stand for?",
        "answer": "Save Our Souls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Acronyms",
        "question": "What does N.A.S.A stand for?",
        "answer": "National Aeronautics and Space Administration"
    },
    {
        "category": "Acronyms",
        "question": "What does the acronym 'scuba' mean?",
        "answer": "Self Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advertising",
        "question": "Who is the dog on the crackerjack box?",
        "answer": "Bingo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Agriculture",
        "question": "What is ground being 'rested' for a season called?",
        "answer": "fallow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "After what were the B52 bombers named?",
        "answer": "a fifties hairdo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "How many engines are on a B52 bomber?",
        "answer": "eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "How many gallons of fuel does a jumbo jet use during take off?",
        "answer": "four thousand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "What does a pilot drop to slow an airplane?",
        "answer": "flaps"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "What is the world's fastest passenger aircraft?",
        "answer": "Concorde"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "What type of craft is the US's Airforce One?",
        "answer": "Boeing 747"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "Whic country developed the first jet fighter?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "Which two nations built the concorde?",
        "answer": "Britain and France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "Who built the 'Cherokee' and 'Comanche' aircraft?",
        "answer": "Piper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aircraft",
        "question": "Who built the hurricane aircraft?",
        "answer": "Hawker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Alcohol",
        "question": "From what is the liqueur kirsch made?",
        "answer": "cherries"
    },
    {
        "category": "Alcohol",
        "question": "From which plant is tequila derived?",
        "answer": "cactus"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "As what is California also known?",
        "answer": "Golden State"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "As what is Minnesota also known?",
        "answer": "Gopher State"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "What city is also known as Beantown?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "What state is 'The Golden State'?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "What state is also called the 'Garden State'?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "What state is the 'Hoosier State'?",
        "answer": "Indiana"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "Where are the headquarters of the CIA?",
        "answer": "Langley, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "America",
        "question": "Which date is inscribed on the book held by the Statue Of Liberty?",
        "answer": "July 4 1776"
    },
    {
        "category": "American Cities",
        "question": "What is the most air polluted city in the United States?",
        "answer": "Los Angeles"
    },
    {
        "category": "American General Knowledge",
        "question": "Where is the Kitty Hawk?",
        "answer": "The Smithsonian Institute"
    },
    {
        "category": "American History",
        "question": "What mountain has the figures of three mounted confederate heroes of the Civil War?",
        "answer": "Stone Mountain"
    },
    {
        "category": "American History",
        "question": "What state is only part of the United States by treaty?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anagrams",
        "question": "Which two fruits are an anagram of each other?",
        "answer": "lemon and melon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "How many litres of air is in an adult lung?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "How many times do your ribs move every year during breathing?",
        "answer": "five million"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Like fingerprints, what other print is individual?",
        "answer": "tongueprints"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Of what does the typical man have 13,000?",
        "answer": "whiskers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What do the auricularis muscles move?",
        "answer": "ears"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the Scientific name for the eardrum?",
        "answer": "tympanic membrane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the common name for the scapula?",
        "answer": "shoulder blade"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the common name for the sternum?",
        "answer": "breastbone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the common name for the tympanic membrane?",
        "answer": "eardrum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the second largest bone in the foot?",
        "answer": "talus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "What is the smallest bone in the human body?",
        "answer": "stirrup bone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Where are one quarter of the bones in the human body?",
        "answer": "feet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Which is the most sensitive finger?",
        "answer": "forefinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "As what is a camelopard also known?",
        "answer": "giraffe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "As what is a giraffe also known?",
        "answer": "camelopard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "As what is a moose also known?",
        "answer": "algonquin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "As what is an algonquin more commonaly known?",
        "answer": "moose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "At what age does a filly become a mare?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Does a wild rabbit live 10, 15 or 20 years?",
        "answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "How fast (mph) can a kangaroo hop?",
        "answer": "forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "How many hours a day does a ferret sleep?",
        "answer": "twenty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "How many hours does an antelope sleep at night?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "How many teeth does a walrus have?",
        "answer": "eighteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "If a robin's egg is put in vinegar for thirty days, what colour does it become?",
        "answer": "yellow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Name one male fish that gives birth?",
        "answer": "sea horse or pipe fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Of what are walrus tusks made?",
        "answer": "ivory"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "On what do honeybees have a type of hair?",
        "answer": "eyes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Some animals always grow new teeth to replace the old. Name one of them!",
        "answer": "crocodile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Some animals always grow new teeth to replace the old. Name one of them!",
        "answer": "shark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal can get the disease 'heaves'?",
        "answer": "horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal can hop as fast as 40 mph?",
        "answer": "kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal has red patches on its rear?",
        "answer": "mandrill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal lives in a form?",
        "answer": "hare"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal lives in a warren?",
        "answer": "rabbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What animal's milk is more than 54% fat?",
        "answer": "humpback whale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What are the only other animals on which the pill works?",
        "answer": "gorillas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What bird is associated with Lundy Island?",
        "answer": "puffin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What colour is a robin's egg?",
        "answer": "blue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What comprises than 54% of humpback whale's milk?",
        "answer": "fat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What dog is named after a Mexican state?",
        "answer": "chihuahua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What herbivore sleeps one hour a night?",
        "answer": "antelope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What insect has a type of hair on it's eyes?",
        "answer": "honeybees"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is a female deer called?",
        "answer": "doe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is a male deer called?",
        "answer": "buck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is a marsupium?",
        "answer": "pouch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is a word for a castrated ram?",
        "answer": "wether"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is a young whale called?",
        "answer": "calf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is another name for the coyote?",
        "answer": "prairie wolf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is another name for the prairie wolf?",
        "answer": "coyote"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the chihuahua named after?",
        "answer": "A Mexican state"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the heaviest snake?",
        "answer": "anaconda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the largest lizard?",
        "answer": "Komodo Dragon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the longest venomous snake?",
        "answer": "king cobra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the scientific name for a turkey's wishbone?",
        "answer": "furcula"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What is the technical name for an animal's pouch?",
        "answer": "marsupium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What lives in a formicary?",
        "answer": "ants"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What type of frog is the smallest frog?",
        "answer": "gold frog"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What was the first animal on the endangered species list?",
        "answer": "peregrine falcon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "What well known marsupial is the wallaby related to?",
        "answer": "kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Where do ants live?",
        "answer": "formicary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which is the largest African bird of prey?",
        "answer": "lammergeyer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which is the largest aquatic bird?",
        "answer": "albatross"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which is the largest known butterfly?",
        "answer": "Queen Alexandra's Birdwing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which is the only animal other than humans that can get leprosy?",
        "answer": "armadillos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which mammals fly?",
        "answer": "bats"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "Which snake kills the most humans?",
        "answer": "king cobra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal Kingdom",
        "question": "With which island is the puffin associated?",
        "answer": "Lundy Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animal kingdom",
        "question": "Where are there over 58 million dogs?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Animals",
        "question": "What is the most venomous snake (no, it's not the king cobra!)?",
        "answer": "Inland Taipan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Archaeology",
        "question": "Approximately how many years old is the first known written advertisement?",
        "answer": "three thousand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Archaeology",
        "question": "In which ruins was the first known written advertisement found?",
        "answer": "Thebes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Archaic Terms",
        "question": "What date is the 'Ides' of March?",
        "answer": "Fifteenth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Architecture",
        "question": "Which famous million dollar building cost more than a million dollars?",
        "answer": "Sydney Opera House"
    },
    {
        "category": "Art",
        "question": "Who painted 'Irises'?",
        "answer": "Vincent Van Gogh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "What is the art of tracing designs and making impressions of them called?",
        "answer": "lithography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Which is the largest museum in the world?",
        "answer": "Louvre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Who is a successful recording artist, talented landscape artist, and author of children's books?",
        "answer": "Ricky Van Shelton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astology",
        "question": "Who was born when Pluto, the astrological sign for death, was directly above Dallas, Texas?",
        "answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "What is the astrological sign for death?",
        "answer": "Pluto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "What is the zodiacal symbol for Capricorn?",
        "answer": "goat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "Which constellation is represented by a goat?",
        "answer": "Capricorn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "As what is Polaris also known?",
        "answer": "North Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "As what is the North Star also known?",
        "answer": "Polaris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Saturday is named after which planet?",
        "answer": "Saturn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What constellation is represented by scales?",
        "answer": "Libra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the most essential tool in astronomy?",
        "answer": "telescope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name given to a group of stars?",
        "answer": "constellation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name of brightest asteroid visible from earth?",
        "answer": "Vesta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the only day named after a planet?",
        "answer": "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the small irregular white cloud that zips around Neptune approximately every 16 hours called?",
        "answer": "Scooter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the technical name for 'falling stars'?",
        "answer": "meteors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What planet is nearest the sun?",
        "answer": "Mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "When does a full moon rise?",
        "answer": "sunset"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Which is the only planet that rotates clockwise?",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Who coined the theory that the earth revolves around the sun?",
        "answer": "Nicolaus Copernicus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Who discovered the four largest moons of Jupiter?",
        "answer": "Galileo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Who invented the telescope?",
        "answer": "Galileo Galilei"
    },
    {
        "category": "Atmosphere",
        "question": "What is the stratosphere immediately above?",
        "answer": "troposphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Atmosphere",
        "question": "What is the troposphere immediately lower than?",
        "answer": "stratosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Aviation",
        "question": "How many 'Air Force One'(s) are there?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Baseball",
        "question": "Who wore a cabbage leaf under his cap?",
        "answer": "Babe Ruth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Beverages",
        "question": "What drink is named after the queen of England who was famous for her 'sanguinary' persecution of the protestants?",
        "answer": "Bloody Mary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Beverages",
        "question": "What is made of fermented grape juice?",
        "answer": "wine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Big Peepers",
        "question": "Which animal has the largest eyes?",
        "answer": "giant squid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "As what is haemophilia also known?",
        "answer": "royal disease"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "Of what is keratitis an inflammation?",
        "answer": "cornea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "On what side should you sleep to improve digestion?",
        "answer": "right"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "To what disability can keratitis lead?",
        "answer": "blindness"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What appears when the sun activates melanocytes?",
        "answer": "freckles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What body function is improved if you sleep on your right side?",
        "answer": "digestion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?",
        "answer": "lingual nerve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What does the body release that dilates small blood vessels and so causes a person to blush?",
        "answer": "peptides"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What does the lack of iodine in the diet cause?",
        "answer": "goitre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What does the pancreas produce?",
        "answer": "insulin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What element is lacking in a diet when goitre occurs?",
        "answer": "iodine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What falls out with phalacrosis?",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What falls out with phalacrosis?",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What fleshy muscular organ is joined to the hyoid bone?",
        "answer": "tongue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What gland secretes fluid that washes the eyes?",
        "answer": "tear gland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is activated for freckles to appear?",
        "answer": "melanocytes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the biological name for the shin bone?",
        "answer": "tibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the biological term for the voice box?",
        "answer": "larynx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the common name for the larynx?",
        "answer": "voice box"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the hardest bone in the human body?",
        "answer": "jawbone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the latin name for the top set of vertebrae?",
        "answer": "cervical"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the royal disease?",
        "answer": "haemophilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is the tibia more commonly known as?",
        "answer": "shin bone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What muscle is joined by the lingual nerve to the brain?",
        "answer": "tongue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What muscles move the ears?",
        "answer": "auricularis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What protein makes blood red?",
        "answer": "Haemoglobin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What small region at end of medulla oblongata serves as 'bridge' to brain?",
        "answer": "pons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "When a tumour is cancerous, what is it said to be?",
        "answer": "malignant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "With age, what organ shrinks faster in males than in females?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Birthstones",
        "question": "What is the birthstone for May?",
        "answer": "emerald"
    },
    {
        "category": "Birthstones",
        "question": "What is the birthstone for September?",
        "answer": "sapphire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "Approximately how many years old are oak trees before they produce acorns?",
        "answer": "fifty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "One ragweed plant can release approximately how many grains of pollen?",
        "answer": "one billion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "To which family does the coffee plant belong?",
        "answer": "madder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "Which tree only produces acorns after it is fifty years old?",
        "answer": "oak"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "How many inches tall are the bearskins worn by the guards at Buckingham Palace?",
        "answer": "twenty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "In the House of Lords, where does the Lord Chancellor sit?",
        "answer": "woolsack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "In which park are Queen Mary's gardens?",
        "answer": "Regents Park"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "What are the only two london boroughs that start with the letter 'e'?",
        "answer": "Ealing and Enfield"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "What does 'The Monument' in London commemorate?",
        "answer": "Great Fire of London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "What was the second bridge built across the Thames?",
        "answer": "Westminster Bridge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "Where is Selfridges?",
        "answer": "Oxford Street, London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "Which building commemorates the Great Fire of London?",
        "answer": "Monument"
    },
    {
        "category": "Britain",
        "question": "Who at Buckingham Palace wears bearskins?",
        "answer": "guards"
    },
    {
        "category": "British History",
        "question": "What was Margaret Thatcher's nickname?",
        "answer": "Iron Lady"
    },
    {
        "category": "Buildings",
        "question": "What is the largest inhabited castle in the world?",
        "answer": "Windsor Castle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Buildings",
        "question": "Where is the 'whispering gallery'?",
        "answer": "St. Paul's Cathedral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Buildings",
        "question": "Where would you find a nave, apse, atrium and narthex?",
        "answer": "Basilica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cars",
        "question": "How is 75% of petrol in an engine wasted?",
        "answer": "combustion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cars",
        "question": "What make of car is a 'Thunderbird'?",
        "answer": "Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cars",
        "question": "What make of car is an 'Espace'?",
        "answer": "Renault"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cars",
        "question": "Which country has the most cars per mile of road?",
        "answer": "England"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Decorum",
        "question": "Donald Duck comics were banned in Finland because he didn't wear ------?",
        "answer": "pants"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "For which cartoon character was Beethoven a favourite composer?",
        "answer": "Shroeder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "How many freckles did Howdy Doody have?",
        "answer": "forty eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "The maiden names of which two cartoon characters are Slaghoople and Mcbricker?",
        "answer": "Wilma Flintstone and Betty Rubble"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What are the names of Donald Duck's nephews?",
        "answer": "Huey Dewey and Louey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What city do Batman and Robin patrol?",
        "answer": "Gotham City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What expression did Clark Kent's newspaper boss like to use?",
        "answer": "Great Caesar's ghost!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's surname?",
        "answer": "Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first cartoon character called?",
        "answer": "Oswald the Rabbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What were Wilma Flintstone and Betty Rubble's maiden names?",
        "answer": "Slaghoople and Mcbricker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which comic is drawn by Sam Keith?",
        "answer": "The Maxx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which magician did Lothar assist?",
        "answer": "Mandrake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who did the voices of Bugs Bunny, Sylvester and Tweety Pie?",
        "answer": "Mel Blanc"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who drew the comic 'The Maxx'?",
        "answer": "Sam Keith"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who patrols Gotham City?",
        "answer": "Batman and Robin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who took dictation from Perry Mason?",
        "answer": "Della Street"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Barney Rubble's best friend?",
        "answer": "Fred Flintstone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Fred Flinstone's best friend?",
        "answer": "Barney Rubble"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was born on Krypton?",
        "answer": "Superman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the black assistant of Mandrake the Magician?",
        "answer": "Lothar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the first voice of Mickey Mouse?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon trivia",
        "question": "What film was the last featuring Mel Blanc's voice?",
        "answer": "Jetsons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "20% of what is in the metal part at the end of a pencil?",
        "answer": "sulphur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "As what is sulphur also known?",
        "answer": "brimstone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "For what is the chemical formula H2O2?",
        "answer": "hydrogen peroxide"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "For what metal is 'Au' the chemical symbol?",
        "answer": "gold"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Of what is 98% of the weight of water made?",
        "answer": "oxygen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "To what group of elements do cerium, praesiodymium and promethium belong?",
        "answer": "rare earth metals"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What does the symbol 'Am' represent?",
        "answer": "americium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is a corrosive substance with a pH value less than 7 called?",
        "answer": "acid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is calcium oxide commonly called?",
        "answer": "lime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the atomic number for thalium?",
        "answer": "eighty one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the atomic number of Bromine?",
        "answer": "thirty five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the atomic number of Molybdenum?",
        "answer": "forty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the atomic number of sulphur?",
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the atomic number of uranium?",
        "answer": "ninety two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical name for quicksilver?",
        "answer": "mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
        "answer": "Au"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?",
        "answer": "Fe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the heaviest naturally occuring element?",
        "answer": "uranium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for copper?",
        "answer": "Cu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for tin?",
        "answer": "Sn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What term is applied to ethyl alcohol that has been treated with poison to make it unfit for human consumption?",
        "answer": "denatured"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What type of paper is used to test for acidity and alkalinity?",
        "answer": "litmus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Choking",
        "question": "On what do approximately 100 people choke to death every year?",
        "answer": "ballpoint pens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "How long did it take God to create the Universe?",
        "answer": "six days - he rested on the seventh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "How many children did Noah have?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "How many sayings did Jesus say from the cross?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "How many times did Peter deny Jesus?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "How old was Sarah when she had a child?",
        "answer": "ninety"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "On which day was the resurrection of Christ?",
        "answer": "Easter Sunday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "What are the first three words of The Bible?",
        "answer": "In the beginning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "What two biblical cities did God destroy with fire and brimstone?",
        "answer": "Sodom and Gomorrah"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "Which two books in the Old Testament list the ten commandments? (in order of appearance)",
        "answer": "Exodus and Deuteronomy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "Who killed Goliath?",
        "answer": "David"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "Who replaced Moses as the prophet of the Israelites?",
        "answer": "Joshua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christianity",
        "question": "Whose name did God change to Israel?",
        "answer": "Jacob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas Trivia",
        "question": "In the 'Twelve days of christmas', how many items in total are sent by 'my true love'?",
        "answer": "seventy eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "A bird in the hand is worth ------?",
        "answer": "two in the bush"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "A stitch in time saves ----?",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As clear as a -------?",
        "answer": "bell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As close as two ------ in a pod?",
        "answer": "peas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As easy as ------?",
        "answer": "pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As hard as -------?",
        "answer": "nails"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As mad as a -------?",
        "answer": "wet hen or hatter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As nervous as a long-tailed cat in a room full of ------?",
        "answer": "rocking chairs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As pretty as a ------?",
        "answer": "picture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As sick as a ------?",
        "answer": "dog"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "As sly as a ------?",
        "answer": "fox"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "Hell hath no fury like a ------?",
        "answer": "woman scorned"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clich-s",
        "question": "Time ---- when you're having fun?",
        "answer": "flies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Clothing",
        "question": "On what is an espadrille worn?",
        "answer": "foot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cocktails",
        "question": "What are the essential ingredients of a daiquiri?",
        "answer": "rum and lemon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cocktails",
        "question": "What cocktail is based on rum and lemon?",
        "answer": "daiquiri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "In alphabet radio code, what word is used for 'c'?",
        "answer": "charlie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "In alphabet radio code, what word is used for 'f'?",
        "answer": "foxtrot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "In alphabet radio code, what word is used for 'h'?",
        "answer": "hotel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "In alphabet radio code, what word is used for 't'?",
        "answer": "tango"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "In alphabet radio code, what word is used for 'x'?",
        "answer": "X-ray"
    },
    {
        "category": "Codes",
        "question": "Using morse code, what does trasmitting using 3 dots, 3 dashes and 3 dots?",
        "answer": "SOS"
    },
    {
        "category": "Coins",
        "question": "What is a south african coin containing 1 troy ounce of gold called?",
        "answer": "Krugerrand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Collective Names",
        "question": "What is a group of donkeys called?",
        "answer": "herd"
    },
    {
        "category": "Collective Names",
        "question": "What is a group of geese called?",
        "answer": "gaggle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Companies",
        "question": "The De Beers group of companies controls more than 80% of the world's supply of ------?",
        "answer": "rough diamonds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Companies",
        "question": "What product built Hershey, Pennsylvania?",
        "answer": "chocolate"
    },
    {
        "category": "Companies",
        "question": "Which company controls more than 80% of the world's rough diamond supply?",
        "answer": "De Beers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What country did the operating system 'Linux' come from?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What does 'IBM' stand for?",
        "answer": "International Business Machines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What does the 'x' mean when referring to the speed of a CD-rom (eg. 32x)?",
        "answer": "times (faster than standard speed)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What type of printer did Seiko develop for the 1964 Tokyo Olympics?",
        "answer": "dot matrix"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What was invented over 3000 years ago that is now considered the first 'computer'?",
        "answer": "abacus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What was the first version of Microsoft Windows to have networking capabilities?",
        "answer": "Windows for Workgroups"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "What was the first version of Microsoft Windows?",
        "answer": "Windows 286"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computers",
        "question": "Who is the CEO of Apple computers?",
        "answer": "Steve Jobs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Contraception",
        "question": "After who is the 'Ramses' brand condom named?",
        "answer": "Pharaoh Ramses II"
    },
    {
        "category": "Corporations",
        "question": "As what is America Online better known?",
        "answer": "AOL"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cosmology",
        "question": "What is the most widely accepted theory for the creation of the universe?",
        "answer": "Big Bang"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cosmology",
        "question": "What was created with the big bang?",
        "answer": "Universe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Crafts",
        "question": "What is kaolin?",
        "answer": "pure china clay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Crafts",
        "question": "What is liquid clay used in pottery called?",
        "answer": "slip"
    },
    {
        "category": "Crafts",
        "question": "What is pure china clay called?",
        "answer": "kaolin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Because the emu and the kangaroo cannot walk backwards, they are on the Australian ------?",
        "answer": "coat of arms"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "For which country is the lotus flower the national symbol?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "In which country is it polite to stick your tongue out at your guests?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "In which country is milk the most popular beverage?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "In which town does the famous 'running of the bulls' take place?",
        "answer": "Pamplona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Israel has the highest per capital consumption of ------?",
        "answer": "turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What London landmark has an 11 foot long hand?",
        "answer": "Big Ben"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What animals are on the Australian coat of arms?",
        "answer": "emu and kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What are the roads of Guam paved with?",
        "answer": "coral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What are the sandals called that are worn in ceremonial japanese tradition?",
        "answer": "tabi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What city do the Italians call the Monaco of bavaria?",
        "answer": "Munich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What do the Italians call Munich?",
        "answer": "Monaco of Bavaria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What famous building is located on the banks of the river Jumna?",
        "answer": "Taj Mahal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What happened on screen for the first time in India in 1977?",
        "answer": "Screen kiss"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is a water taxi known as in Venice?",
        "answer": "gondola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the most common name in italy?",
        "answer": "Mario Rossi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the name of a quarter of Jerusalem that can be translated as 'hundred gates'?",
        "answer": "Mea Shearim"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the name of the wrought iron tower in Paris?",
        "answer": "Eiffel Tower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the national symbol for India?",
        "answer": "lotus flower"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the sacred river of Hinduism?",
        "answer": "Ganges"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "What is the tribal african word for dowry?",
        "answer": "lobola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "When is turkey traditionally eaten in America?",
        "answer": "thanksgiving"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Where are the Hausa and Ibo tribes?",
        "answer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Where do the English monarchs live?",
        "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Where is the Blarney Stone?",
        "answer": "Blarney Castle, Ireland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Where was it once against the law to have a pet dog?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Where would one eat a taco?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Which country eats the most turkey per capita?",
        "answer": "Israel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Which famous museum is in Paris, France?",
        "answer": "Louvre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Culture",
        "question": "Which nationality calls Munich the 'Monaco of Bavaria'?",
        "answer": "Italians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Germany's equivalent to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "deutsche mark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Israel's equivalent to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "shekel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Italy's equivalant to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "lira"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Japan's equivalent to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "yen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Mexico's equivalent to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "peso"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Spain's equivalent to the dollar is the ------?",
        "answer": "peseta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "The quetzal is the currency of ------?",
        "answer": "Guatemala"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "What is the Japanese currency?",
        "answer": "yen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "What is the currency of Guatemala?",
        "answer": "quetzal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "What is the monetary unit of India?",
        "answer": "rupee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currencies",
        "question": "Which country has the currency 'yen'?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currency",
        "question": "What country's currency is the Bolivar?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Currency",
        "question": "What is the currency of Venezuela?",
        "answer": "Bolivar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definition",
        "question": "What is armagnac?",
        "answer": "brandy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a chronometer measure?",
        "answer": "Time"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a catalogue of languages called?",
        "answer": "ethnologue"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a gondola?",
        "answer": "water taxi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a one-party system of government in which control is maintained by force and regimentation?",
        "answer": "fascism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a word for a sorcerer who deals in black magic?",
        "answer": "necromancer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is another name for a sleepwalker?",
        "answer": "somnambulist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is ornamental work in silver or gold thread called?",
        "answer": "filigree"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the name given to a pregnant goldfish?",
        "answer": "twit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What word means 'to chew the cud'?",
        "answer": "ruminate"
    },
    {
        "category": "Dimples",
        "question": "What has 336 dimples?",
        "answer": "a golf ball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Disease",
        "question": "Sleeping sickness is carried by which insect?",
        "answer": "tsetse fly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Disease",
        "question": "What disease is carried by the tsetse fly?",
        "answer": "sleeping sickness"
    },
    {
        "category": "Distress Signals",
        "question": "What is the international cry for help?",
        "answer": "mayday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Education",
        "question": "What degree do the intials 'DDS' stand for?",
        "answer": "Doctor of Dental Surgery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Egypt",
        "question": "What egyptian object is also known as 'the key to the Nile'?",
        "answer": "Ankh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Electronics",
        "question": "As what was Sony's video recorder known?",
        "answer": "betamax"
    },
    {
        "category": "Electronics",
        "question": "Circuits can be wired in parallel or ------?",
        "answer": "series"
    },
    {
        "category": "Entomology",
        "question": "What is the only insect that can turn its head?",
        "answer": "praying mantis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Environmentalism",
        "question": "Recycling one glass jar saves enough energy to watch TV for how many hours?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "Famous Dead Bodies",
        "question": "Where is Sir Herbert Baker buried?",
        "answer": "Westminster Abbey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Famous Genitals",
        "question": "For how much did an American urologist buy Napoleon's penis? (US Dollars)",
        "answer": "$3800"
    },
    {
        "category": "Famous Initials",
        "question": "For what are Allen and Wright most famous?",
        "answer": "root beer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Famous Places",
        "question": "What Surrey town is famed for its salts?",
        "answer": "Epsom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Farming",
        "question": "What is the most rural state in the USA?",
        "answer": "North Dakota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fear",
        "question": "If hell is a lake of fire, what would the temperature be? (in degrees Fahrenheit)",
        "answer": "833"
    },
    {
        "category": "Film and Television",
        "question": "Who is the main character in 'Touched By An Angel'?",
        "answer": "Monica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Flags",
        "question": "How many stars are there on the New Zealand flag?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Flags",
        "question": "What colours are on the Belgian flag?",
        "answer": "yellow, black and red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Flags",
        "question": "Which country has a plain green flag?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Flags",
        "question": "Whose flag has the national arms on one side and the treasury seal on the other?",
        "answer": "Paraguay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Flea Abilities",
        "question": "How many times its own length can the average flea jump?",
        "answer": "150"
    },
    {
        "category": "Folklore",
        "question": "Who was the tallest of Robin Hood's men?",
        "answer": "Little John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "How many herbs and spices are used in Kentucky Fried Chicken?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "How many pieces of bun are in a Mcdonald's Big Mac?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "In which country did edam cheese originate?",
        "answer": "Holland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "In which country did the word 'biscuit' originate?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "What breakfast cereal was invented at Battle Creek Sanitarium?",
        "answer": "Cornflakes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "What did Charles Jung invent?",
        "answer": "fortune cookies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "What is another name for the carambula?",
        "answer": "star fruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "What is the most widely used seasoning?",
        "answer": "salt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "What is the oldest known vegetable?",
        "answer": "pea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Where were Cornflakes invented?",
        "answer": "Battle Creek Sanitarium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Where were fortune cookies invented?",
        "answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Who invented fortune cookies?",
        "answer": "Charles Jung"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Who invented the Egg Mcmuffin?",
        "answer": "Ed Peterson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What berries give gin its flavour?",
        "answer": "juniper berries"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "A tayberry is a cross between which two fruits?",
        "answer": "blackberry and raspberry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "Unlike other oranges, what does a navel orange not have?",
        "answer": "seeds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "What fruits are usually served 'belle helene'?",
        "answer": "pears"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "What is a cross between a blackberry and a raspberry?",
        "answer": "tayberry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "What is another name for the star fruit?",
        "answer": "carambula"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fruit",
        "question": "Where is most of the vitamin C in fruits?",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun Runs",
        "question": "What is San Francisco's equivalent to Sydney's 'City To Surf' race?",
        "answer": "Bay to Breakers footrace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Furniture",
        "question": "What is the metal part of a lamp surrounding the bulb and supporting the shade called?",
        "answer": "harp"
    },
    {
        "category": "Furniture",
        "question": "Where did venetian blinds originate?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many dots are on a twister mat?",
        "answer": "thirty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many folds does a Monopoly board have?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many numbers are on the spinner in the game of 'Life'?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How much does Park Place cost in Monopoly (in US Dollars)?",
        "answer": "450"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In a game of horseshoes, how many feet apart must the stakes be?",
        "answer": "forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In roulette, what number is green?",
        "answer": "zero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Moving anti-clockwise on a dartboard, what is the number next to '4'?",
        "answer": "eighteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "To what do opposite faces of a dice always add up?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What is another name for the card game 'Blackjack'?",
        "answer": "Twenty-one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What is another name for the card game 'Twenty-one'?",
        "answer": "Blackjack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What is the best possible score in blackjack?",
        "answer": "twenty one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What is the most popular sport in england?",
        "answer": "darts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What is the tallest piece on a chessboard?",
        "answer": "king"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What number is at 12 o'clock on a dartboard?",
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What sport/game is Bobby Fischer associated with?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Where did the card game 'bridge' originate?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Where does the annual Poker World Series take place?",
        "answer": "Las Vegas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Gastronomy",
        "question": "Approximately how many pounds of cereal will the average american/canadian eat every year?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Gems",
        "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for ------?",
        "answer": "August"
    },
    {
        "category": "Gems",
        "question": "What is the birthstone for August?",
        "answer": "peridot"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Northern hemisphere?",
        "answer": "June"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?",
        "answer": "December"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "During which month is the shortest day in the Northern hemisphere?",
        "answer": "December"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "During which month is the shortest day in the Southern hemisphere?",
        "answer": "June"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does a month beginning with a Sunday always have?",
        "answer": "Friday the 13th"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What game usually starts with 'is it animal, vegetable or mineral'?",
        "answer": "twenty questions"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the name of the office used by the president in the Whitehouse?",
        "answer": "Oval office"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is viewed during a a pyrotechnic display?",
        "answer": "fireworks"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What system do the blind use for reading?",
        "answer": "braille"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Where will children as young as 15 be jailed for cheating on their finals?",
        "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "With what day does a month start if it has a Friday the 13th?",
        "answer": "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Genetics",
        "question": "How many chromosomes do each body cell contain?",
        "answer": "forty six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geograhy",
        "question": "What is the capital of Democratic Republic of the Congo?",
        "answer": "Kinshasa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Abuja is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Accra is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Albany is the capital of -----?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Ankara is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "As what is Constantinople now known?",
        "answer": "Istanbul"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "As what is Formosa now known?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "As what is Krung Thep is more commonly known?",
        "answer": "Bangkok"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "As what is the South Pole also known?",
        "answer": "Amundsen Scott Station"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "As what was the Taj Mahal originally built?",
        "answer": "tomb"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Austin is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bamako is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Mali"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bangkok is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Thailand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Banjul is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Gambia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bismarck is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "North Dakota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bissau is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Guinea-Bissau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bogota is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Boise is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Idaho"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgetown is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Budapest is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Cheyenne is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Columbus is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Ohio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Dakar is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Senegal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Des Moines is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Iowa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Dhaka is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Djibouti is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Djibouti"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Five US states border which ocean?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Guatemala is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Guatemala"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Helena is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "How many Great Lakes are there?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "How many countries border the black sea?",
        "answer": "six - Turkey, Georgia, Russia, Ukraine, Romania and Bulgaria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "If you flew due West from Portugal, what is the first continent you would reach?",
        "answer": "North America"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what state is Silicon Valley?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Westminster Abbey?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Westminster Abbey?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Arch of Hadrian?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the famous Bond Street?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Tobruk?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the largest active volcano in the world?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which county are all ten of England's highest peaks?",
        "answer": "Cumbria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which modern day country is ancient Troy?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Tupelo?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Natchez Trail?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what ocean does the Zambezi River empty?",
        "answer": "Indian Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into which bay does the Golden Gate Strait lead?",
        "answer": "San Francisco Bay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into which estuary do the Trent and Ouse flow?",
        "answer": "Humber"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Is Belfast in Northern or Southern Ireland?",
        "answer": "Northern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Is Dublin in Northern or Southern ireland?",
        "answer": "Southern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kathmandu is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Nepal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kigali is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kingston is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kinshasa is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Democratic Republic of the Congo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kuwait City is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Kuwait"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Lansing is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Libreville is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Gabon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Malawi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Lome is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Togo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Luxembourg is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Luxembourg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Malabo is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Equatorial Guinea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Mayfair, London is a district of little streets near ------?",
        "answer": "Hyde Park"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Mexico City is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Montevideo is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Uruguay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Nashville is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Near what river is the Temple of Karnak?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "New Delhi is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Nicosia is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Cyprus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Of what are Quemoy and Matsu part?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Of which country does the Kalahari Desert cover 84%?",
        "answer": "Botswana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On the London Underground, which station has a different name on two of its platforms?",
        "answer": "Bank and Monument"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On the banks of which river is the Taj Mahal?",
        "answer": "River Jumna"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Pearl Harbor?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what river is Blackpool?",
        "answer": "River Fylde"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what river is Liverpool?",
        "answer": "Mersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what sea is the Crimea?",
        "answer": "Black Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which coast of Australia is Sydney?",
        "answer": "East"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Ouagadougou is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Burkina Faso"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Port Louis is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Mauritius"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Port Moresby is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Papua New Guinea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Raleigh is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Richmond is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Riyadh is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Rome is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Santiago is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Santo Domingo is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Singapore is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Springfield is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Illinois"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Sydney is on the east coast of ------?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Honduras"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Through which ocean does the International Date Line approximately follow the 180 degree meridian?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Tirana is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Albania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Ulan Bator is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Vaduz is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Central American country extends furthest north?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Scandinavian capital begins and ends with the same letter?",
        "answer": "Oslo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city has the world's largest black population?",
        "answer": "New York City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is part of both the East and Aest hemispheres?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt on the West?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt to the South?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Libya on the East?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Sudan to the North?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country has the biggest population?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is situated between Panama and Nicaragua?",
        "answer": "Costa Rica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is surrounded by Brazil, Argentina and Bolivia?",
        "answer": "Paraguay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was once known as 'The Breadbasket of Russia'?",
        "answer": "Ukraine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country's capital is Caracas?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What divides the American North from the South?",
        "answer": "The Mason-Dixon Line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What do Americans traditionally eat on thanksgiving day?",
        "answer": "turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What does the George Washington Bridge span?",
        "answer": "Hudson River"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is a peanut if it is not a pea or a nut?",
        "answer": "legume"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is also known as Amundsen Scott Station?",
        "answer": "South Pole"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the Southernmost country in continental Europe?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Albania?",
        "answer": "Tirana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Australia?",
        "answer": "Canberra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Bangladesh?",
        "answer": "Dhaka"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Barbados?",
        "answer": "Bridgetown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?",
        "answer": "Brasilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Burkina Faso?",
        "answer": "Ouagadougou"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of California?",
        "answer": "Sacramento"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Chile?",
        "answer": "Santiago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Colombia?",
        "answer": "Bogota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Cyprus?",
        "answer": "Nicosia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Djibouti?",
        "answer": "Djibouti"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Equatorial Guinea?",
        "answer": "Malabo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Gabon?",
        "answer": "Libreville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Gambia?",
        "answer": "Banjul"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Ghana?",
        "answer": "Accra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Guatemala?",
        "answer": "Guatemala"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Guinea-Bissau?",
        "answer": "Bissau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Honduras?",
        "answer": "Tegucigalpa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?",
        "answer": "Budapest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Idaho?",
        "answer": "Boise"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Illinois?",
        "answer": "Springfield"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of India?",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Iowa?",
        "answer": "Des Moines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Italy?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Jamaica?",
        "answer": "Kingston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Kuwait?",
        "answer": "Kuwait"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Liechtenstein?",
        "answer": "Vaduz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Luxembourg?",
        "answer": "Luxembourg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Luxembourg?",
        "answer": "Luxembourg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Malawi?",
        "answer": "Lilongwe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Mali?",
        "answer": "Bamako"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Mauritius?",
        "answer": "Port Louis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Mexico?",
        "answer": "Mexico City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Michigan?",
        "answer": "Lansing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Missouri?",
        "answer": "Jefferson City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Mongolia?",
        "answer": "Ulan Bator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Montana?",
        "answer": "Helena"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nepal?",
        "answer": "Kathmandu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of New York state?",
        "answer": "Albany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nigeria?",
        "answer": "Abuja"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of North Carolina?",
        "answer": "Raleigh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of North Dakota?",
        "answer": "Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Ohio?",
        "answer": "Columbus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Papua New Guinea?",
        "answer": "Port Moresby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Pennsylvania?",
        "answer": "Harrisburg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Rwanda?",
        "answer": "Kigali"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Saudi Arabia?",
        "answer": "Riyadh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Senegal?",
        "answer": "Dakar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Singapore?",
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Tennessee?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Texas?",
        "answer": "Austin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Thailand?",
        "answer": "Bangkok"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Togo?",
        "answer": "Lome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Turkey?",
        "answer": "Ankara"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Uruguay?",
        "answer": "Montevideo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Virginia?",
        "answer": "Richmond"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Wyoming?",
        "answer": "Cheyenne"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of the Dominican Republic?",
        "answer": "Santo Domingo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the circle of the earth at 0 degrees latitude called?",
        "answer": "equator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the correct name of Bangkok?",
        "answer": "Krung Thep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the deepest land gorge in the world?",
        "answer": "Grand Canyon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the fifth largest country in the world?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the highest peak in Fiji?",
        "answer": "Mount Victoria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in China?",
        "answer": "Shanghai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in Ecuador?",
        "answer": "Guayaquil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in Switzerland?",
        "answer": "Zurich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest country in Central America?",
        "answer": "Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest exclusively Indonesian island?",
        "answer": "Sumatra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest ocean?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?",
        "answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the oldest town in Belgium?",
        "answer": "Tongeren"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the only borough of New York City that is not on an island?",
        "answer": "Bronx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the river capital of the world?",
        "answer": "Akron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the saltiest sea in the world?",
        "answer": "The Dead Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest continent in the world?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest ocean?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest state in the USA?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest state in the USA?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the windiest place on earth?",
        "answer": "Mount Washington, New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's highest waterfall?",
        "answer": "Angel Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's largest desert?",
        "answer": "Sahara Desert"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's largest lake?",
        "answer": "Caspian Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's largest sea?",
        "answer": "Mediterranean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's widest river?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What lake is approximately 394,000 sq. km in area?",
        "answer": "Caspian Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What ocean is found along the East border of Asia?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What place is known as 'the land nowhere near'?",
        "answer": "Cape Three Points"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What seaport's name is spanish for 'white house'?",
        "answer": "Casablanca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What small island is in the bay of Naples?",
        "answer": "Isle of Capri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the 'wallops'?",
        "answer": "Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the Nazca lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the two steepest streets in the USA?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Angel Falls?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Calcutta?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Cape Hatteras?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Eurodisney?",
        "answer": "Paris, France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Gorky Park?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Lake Maracaibo?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Mount Washington?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Tabasco?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Tongeren?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is area 51 generally said to be?",
        "answer": "Groom Lake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Blue Grotto - la Grotta Azzurra ?",
        "answer": "Capri, Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Machu Picchu?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Taj Mahal?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the bridge of San Luis Rey?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the land of 10,000 lakes?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the statue 'Le Petit Pissoir'?",
        "answer": "Brussels"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the wailing wall?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the world's biggest prison camp?",
        "answer": "Siberia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the world's largest desert?",
        "answer": "North Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Californian desert drops below sea level?",
        "answer": "Death Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which English county has the smallest perimeter?",
        "answer": "Isle of Wight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Portuguese colony reverted to China in December 1999?",
        "answer": "Macau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which South American country has both a Pacific and Atlantic coastline?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which bridge spans the Hudson River?",
        "answer": "George Washington Bridge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country administers Martinique?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has the most emigrants?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country is known as the roof of the world?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country occupies the 'horn' of Africa?",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country owns Corfu?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which imaginery line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "International Date Line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the largest lake in South America?",
        "answer": "Lake Maracaibo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the most populated state/territory in Australia?",
        "answer": "New South Wales"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the most remote island in the southern atlantic ocean?",
        "answer": "Bouvet Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the only musical bird that can fly backwards?",
        "answer": "hummingbird"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the only sea below sea level?",
        "answer": "Dead Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which is the smallest independent country?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which island country lies immediately to the East of R-union?",
        "answer": "Mauritius"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which island country lies immediately to the West of Mauritius?",
        "answer": "R-union"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which island country lies to the East of Mauritius?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which island country lies to the West of Australia?",
        "answer": "Mauritius"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which large city is on the Southeastern coast of Australia?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which ocean has an area of approximately 166 sq. km?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which river passes through Germany, Austria, Slovakia, Hungary, Croatia, Yugoslavia, Romania, Bulgaria and Ukraine before arriving at the Black Sea?",
        "answer": "Danube"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which tropic passes through Australia?",
        "answer": "Tropic of Capricorn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Who owns the island of Bermuda?",
        "answer": "Britain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Yaounde is the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "Cameroon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geogrophy",
        "question": "Approximately what percentage of the earth do the oceans cover?",
        "answer": "seventy one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What is the highest active volcano in the world?",
        "answer": "Cotopaxi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What is the most reliable geyser in the world?",
        "answer": "Old Faithful"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What type of rock is marble?",
        "answer": "metamorphic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geometry",
        "question": "What is the sum of all the angles in a square? (in degrees)",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Glass Making",
        "question": "What is the glass capital of the world?",
        "answer": "Toledo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Handy Hints",
        "question": "By raising your legs slowly and laying on your back, in what can you not sink?",
        "answer": "quicksand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hisory",
        "question": "Who invented the predecessor to today's computers?",
        "answer": "Charles Babbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "After who was America named?",
        "answer": "Amerigo Vespucci"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "After who was Mickey Mouse named?",
        "answer": "Mickey Rooney"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Approximately how many children did pharaoh Ramses II father?",
        "answer": "one hundred and sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "As what was Istanbul previously known?",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "As what was Taiwan formerly known?",
        "answer": "Formosa"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "As what was winchester known by the Romans?",
        "answer": "Venta Bulgarum"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Between which countries was the shortest war in history?",
        "answer": "Zanzibar and England"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "By who was Gerald Ford almost assassinated?",
        "answer": "Squeaky Fromme"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "East Berlin was the capital of ------?",
        "answer": "East Germany"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "From what did Alexander the Great suffer?",
        "answer": "epilepsy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "George Washington Carver advocated planting peanuts and sweet potatoes to replace what?",
        "answer": "cotton and tobacco"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "George Washington Carver advocated planting what to replace cotton and tobacco?",
        "answer": "peanuts and sweet potatoes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany was split into two zones by which agreement?",
        "answer": "Yalta agreement"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His wife was Roxana, his horse was Bacephalus, he was?",
        "answer": "Alexander the Great"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many British officers were forced by Indian troops into the Black Hole of Calcutta?",
        "answer": "146"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many people were killed in the battle of Lexington?",
        "answer": "eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many years was Nelson Mandela in prison?",
        "answer": "twenty seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In 1962, for what did Britain and France sign an agreement to build together?",
        "answer": "Concorde"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In 1975, what re-opened after an 8 year closure?",
        "answer": "Suez Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In the 15th century, what was the war between the houses of Lancaster and York?",
        "answer": "War of the Roses"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which battle was George A. Custer defeated?",
        "answer": "Battle of Little Bighorn"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was paper money first used?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "King Richard the --------?",
        "answer": "Lionhearted"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Near what falls did Jimmy Angel crash his plane in 1937?",
        "answer": "Angel Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Of which Cambodian party was Pol Pot the leader?",
        "answer": "Khmer Rouge"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Of which ship was Miles Standish captain?",
        "answer": "The Mayflower"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "On what date did America become an independant nation?",
        "answer": "July 4th, 1776"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "On what day of the week did Solomon Grundy die?",
        "answer": "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "On what was Pennsylvania incorrectly spelled?",
        "answer": "Liberty Bell"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The date of which Christian festival was fixed in 325AD by the Council of Nicaea?",
        "answer": "Easter"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The ------ Tea Party?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Through the streets of what town did Lady Godiva ride naked?",
        "answer": "Coventry"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What 19th century war between Russia and England, Turkey, Britain and France, was named after a peninsula in the Black Sea?",
        "answer": "Crimean War"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What English city was known to the Romans as Venta Bulgarum?",
        "answer": "Winchester"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What United States president was in office during the civil war?",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What colour was Diana Spencer's engagement photograph suit?",
        "answer": "blue"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What country was formerly known as Siam?",
        "answer": "Thailand"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What country was ruled by Pol Pot, leader of the Khmer Rouge party?",
        "answer": "Cambodia (Kampuchea)"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did 'DMZ' stand for in the vietnam war?",
        "answer": "Demilitarized Zone"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did David Stirling found?",
        "answer": "SAS"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Ed Peterson invent?",
        "answer": "Egg Mcmuffin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Eli Whitney invent?",
        "answer": "cotton gin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Erik Rotheim invent in 1926?",
        "answer": "aerosol"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Henry Shrapnel invent?",
        "answer": "The exploding shell"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Louis Cartier invent?",
        "answer": "wristwatch"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Marie Curie die of on 4th July, 1934?",
        "answer": "radiation poisoning"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Pennsylvania legalise before any other colony?",
        "answer": "witchcraft"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did Victorian women bathe in to try to enlarge their breasts?",
        "answer": "strawberries"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What famous artist could write with both his left and right hand at the same time?",
        "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What food was almost non-existent in Ireland in the 1840's?",
        "answer": "potatoes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the 15' by 18' cell that 146 captured british officers were forced into by indian troops in the 19th century called?",
        "answer": "Black Hole of Calcutta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What kind of teeth did George Washington have?",
        "answer": "wooden"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What missionary station was built by Albert Schweitzer?",
        "answer": "Lambarene"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What period is also known as the age of fish?",
        "answer": "Devonian period"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What pre-tv radio show turned film caused people to commit suicide when it was first aired?",
        "answer": "War Of The Worlds"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What war lasted from June 5 to June 11, 1967?",
        "answer": "Six day war"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was Alaska called before 1867?",
        "answer": "Russian America"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was Alexander The Great's wife's name?",
        "answer": "Roxana"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was George A Custer's horses' name?",
        "answer": "Comanche"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was King Arthur's mother's name?",
        "answer": "Igraine"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was Russian America called after 1867?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was Thailand formerly known as?",
        "answer": "Siam"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was named after Amerigo Vespucci?",
        "answer": "America"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the D-Day invasion password?",
        "answer": "Mickey Mouse"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the capital of East Germany?",
        "answer": "East Berlin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the first American colony to legalise witchcraft?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the first fighting vehicle?",
        "answer": "war chariot"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the first product to have a barcode?",
        "answer": "Wrigley's gum"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the first ship to reach the Titanic after it sank?",
        "answer": "Carpathia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the last chinese dynasty?",
        "answer": "Manchu"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the leading cause of death in the late 19th century?",
        "answer": "tuberculosis"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of the first ironclad warship ever launched?",
        "answer": "HMS Warrior"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of the scandal that resulted in the resignation of president Nixon?",
        "answer": "Watergate"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What wonder stood 32m high in rhodes harbour?",
        "answer": "Colossus of Rhodes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "When was D-day?",
        "answer": "June 6th, 1944"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "When was Julius Caesar murdered?",
        "answer": "Ides of March"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "When was the Greek alphabet first used?",
        "answer": "800 BC"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did 'The Mayflower' take the pilgrims?",
        "answer": "New World"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did Bill and Hilary Clinton switch on Christmas lights in 1995?",
        "answer": "Belfast, Northern Ireland"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did Churchill, Roosevelt and Stalin meet in 1945?",
        "answer": "Yalta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "When was the date of the Christian festival Easter fixed by the Council of Nicaea?",
        "answer": "325 AD"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did the Bay Of Pigs take place?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did the Birkenhead sink?",
        "answer": "Danger Point"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where did the bayonet originate?",
        "answer": "Bayonne, France"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where was Napoleon defeated?",
        "answer": "Waterloo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where was Nelson mandela in prison?",
        "answer": "Robben Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where were numerous French nuclear tests conducted?",
        "answer": "Muraroa Atoll"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where were the Hanging Gardens?",
        "answer": "Babylon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Where were the first books printed?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon ?",
        "answer": "Apollo 11"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of Buffy's doll in the 1970's show 'Family Affair'?",
        "answer": "Mrs. Beasley"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which Spanish explorer first travelled to Jamaica?",
        "answer": "Christopher Columbus"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which US president said 'the buck stops here'?",
        "answer": "Harry Truman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which british comedian was the first man to appear on the cover of 'playboy'?",
        "answer": "Peter Sellers"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which country blew up a Greenpeace ship in New Zealand?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which country was split into two zones by the Yalta agreement?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which emperor made his horse a senator?",
        "answer": "Caligula"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which famous actor is honored in a statue in Leicester Square?",
        "answer": "Charlie Chaplin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which famous explorer visited Australia and New Zealand, then surveyed the Pacific coast of North America?",
        "answer": "Captain George Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which frontiersman died at the Alamo?",
        "answer": "Davy Crockett"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which houses fought the War of the Roses?",
        "answer": "Lancaster and York"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which is the most ancient walled city?",
        "answer": "Jericho"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nation did Moshoeshoe found?",
        "answer": "Basotho"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nation was led by Genghis Khan?",
        "answer": "Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nursery rhyme was the first gramophone recording?",
        "answer": "Mary Had A Little Lamb"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which period was first, jurassic or carboniferous?",
        "answer": "carboniferous"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which president was responsible for the 'Louisiana Purchase'?",
        "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which film starring Julie Andrews and Christopher Plummer won the Oscar for best picture in 1965?",
        "answer": "The Sound Of Music"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which ship did Charles Darwin captain?",
        "answer": "HMS Beagle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which was the first Chinese dynasty?",
        "answer": "Shang"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which was the first magazine to publish a hologram on its cover?",
        "answer": "National Geographic"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who advocated planting peanuts and sweet potatoes to replace cotton and tobacco?",
        "answer": "George Washington Carver"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who appeared on the back of a US banknote in 1875?",
        "answer": "Pocahontas"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who assassinated John Lennon?",
        "answer": "Mark David Chapman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who assassinated president Kennedy?",
        "answer": "Lee Harvey Oswald"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who became president of South Africa in 1989?",
        "answer": "F.W. de Klerk"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who built Camelot?",
        "answer": "King Arthur"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who built the Lambarene missionary station?",
        "answer": "Albert Schweitzer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who built the Taj Mahal?",
        "answer": "Shah Jahan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who burned Atlanta in 1864?",
        "answer": "General Sherman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who captained the HMS Beagle?",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who committed the first daytime robbery?",
        "answer": "Frank and Jesse James"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who developed the first nuclear submarine?",
        "answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who did Squeaky Fromme try to assassinate?",
        "answer": "Gerald Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who died three days after Elvis Presley?",
        "answer": "Groucho Marx"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who died three days before Groucho Marx?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who discovered the Grand Canyon?",
        "answer": "Francisco Coronado"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who drafted most of the American Declaration of Independence?",
        "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who fiddled while Rome burned?",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who fixed the date of the Christian festival 'Easter'?",
        "answer": "Council of Nicaea"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who forced 146 captured British officers into the Black Hole of Calcutta?",
        "answer": "Indian troops"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who introduced bagpipes to the British Isles?",
        "answer": "Romans"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented crop insurance?",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented the aerosol?",
        "answer": "Erik Rotheim"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented the ballpoint pen?",
        "answer": "Georgo and Laszlo Biro"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented the cotton gin?",
        "answer": "Eli Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "If Brazil had won the 1998 tournament, how many times would they have won the soccer World Cup?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented the gatling gun?",
        "answer": "Richard Gatling"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who invented the wristwatch?",
        "answer": "Louis Cartier"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is considered the father of medicine?",
        "answer": "Hippocrates"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is identified with the word 'eureka'?",
        "answer": "Archimedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is known as the high priest of revenge?",
        "answer": "Philip Seldon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is known for his 'theory of evolution'?",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is recognised as the father of geometry?",
        "answer": "Euclid"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who killed Jesse James?",
        "answer": "Robert Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1979?",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led the children of Israel out of Egypt?",
        "answer": "Moses"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led the mongols?",
        "answer": "Genghis Khan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who married actress Nancy Davis?",
        "answer": "Ronald Reagan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who met in Yalta in 1945 (in alphabetical order)?",
        "answer": "Churchill Roosevelt Stalin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who ordered the persecution of the Christians in which Peter and Paul died?",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who presided over the trial of Jesus?",
        "answer": "Pontius Pilate"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who received the nobel peace prize in 1964 for civil rights leadership?",
        "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who ruled rome when Christ was born?",
        "answer": "Augustus Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said 'eureka'?",
        "answer": "Archimedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said 'public service is my motto'?",
        "answer": "Al Capone"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who sailed to the new world in 'The mayflower'?",
        "answer": "pilgrims"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who shot Abraham Lincoln?",
        "answer": "John Wilkes Booth"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who signed the 'thanksgiving proclamation'?",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who started the second Punic war?",
        "answer": "Carthage"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who succeeded Winston Churchill as Prime Minister of England?",
        "answer": "Anthony Eden"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who tried to create the 'Great Society'?",
        "answer": "Lyndon B Johnson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was 'The Elephant Man'?",
        "answer": "Joseph Merrick"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was George Washington's vice-president?",
        "answer": "John Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick?",
        "answer": "The Elephant Man"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was King Arthur's foster-father?",
        "answer": "Ector"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was Ulysses' son, who grew to manhood in his absence?",
        "answer": "Telemachus"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was assassinated on December 8, 1980 in New York City?",
        "answer": "John Lennon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was assassinated on November 22, 1963 in Dallas, Texas?",
        "answer": "President John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was captain of 'The Mayflower'?",
        "answer": "Miles Standish"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn?",
        "answer": "George A. Custer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was forced by Indian troops into the Black Hole of Calcutta?",
        "answer": "British officers"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was given the only Nobel Peace Prize award during WWI?",
        "answer": "International Red Cross"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was kidnapped on the night of March 1, 1932?",
        "answer": "Charles Lindbergh Jr"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was known as 'the peanut president'?",
        "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first (and last) catholic president?",
        "answer": "John Fitzerald Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first person to break the sound barrier?",
        "answer": "Chuck Yeager"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first person to swim the English Channel?",
        "answer": "Captain Matthew Webb"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first woman in space?",
        "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the lead singer for Creedence Clearwater Revival, and recently released 'Blue Moon Swamp'?",
        "answer": "John Fogerty"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the leader of the Khmer Rouge?",
        "answer": "Pol Pot"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the only survivor of Custer's last stand?",
        "answer": "his horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who were the first people to be elected into the Aviation Hall Of Fame?",
        "answer": "The Wright Brothers"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Starry Messenger'?",
        "answer": "Galileo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hobbies",
        "question": "What hobby was developed by the Palmer Paint Company?",
        "answer": "Painting by numbers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hobbies",
        "question": "Who invented painting by numbers?",
        "answer": "palmer paint company"
    },
    {
        "category": "How many?",
        "question": "How many years in a vicennial?",
        "answer": "twenty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Human Achievment",
        "question": "Who hit the first golf shot on the moon?",
        "answer": "Alan Sheppard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Humanitarianism",
        "question": "What does the abbreviation 'UNICEF' stand for?",
        "answer": "United Nations Childrens' Emergency Fund"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "In mIRC, what colour does control-K + 4 give?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "On IRC, how do you ask age, sex, location?",
        "answer": "asl"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "On irc, what does a/s/l mean?",
        "answer": "age/sex/location"
    },
    {
        "category": "Impressive Fauna",
        "question": "What animal can live several weeks without its head?",
        "answer": "cockroach"
    },
    {
        "category": "Industry",
        "question": "South africa is the biggest producer and exporter of ------?",
        "answer": "mohair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Industry",
        "question": "Which country is the biggest producer and exporter of mohair?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Intelligence",
        "question": "Who founded the SAS?",
        "answer": "David Stirling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Interesting Fact",
        "question": "More people are killed by donkeys every year than are killed in ------?",
        "answer": "plane crashes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Inventors",
        "question": "Who invented 'bifocal' lenses for eyeglasses?",
        "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Inventors",
        "question": "Who invented the most common projection for world maps?",
        "answer": "Gerardus Mercator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Jokes",
        "question": "In the old gag, where is Prince Albert?",
        "answer": "In a can"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "From what Irish words is 'Dublin' derived?",
        "answer": "dubh linn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "From what language is the term 'finito'?",
        "answer": "Italian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Merging the words 'melt' and 'weld' created which word?",
        "answer": "meld"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Other than Germany, whose official language is German?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "The word rodent comes from the italian 'rodere', which means?",
        "answer": "gnaw"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What city's name is derived from the words 'dubh linn'?",
        "answer": "Dublin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What does 'alma mater' mean in English?",
        "answer": "bountiful mother"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What does 'majuba' mean?",
        "answer": "place of rock pigeons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What does 'shogun' mean in English?",
        "answer": "military governor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What does the Irish 'dubh linn' mean?",
        "answer": "black pool"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What does the word 'karate' translate to in English?",
        "answer": "open hand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is 'blackpool' in Irish?",
        "answer": "dubh linn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is 'bountiful mother' in Latin?",
        "answer": "alma mater"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is 'military governor' in Japanese?",
        "answer": "shogun"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the English word for 'fiesta'?",
        "answer": "festival"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the Israeli 'knesset'?",
        "answer": "parliament"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the Old English word for 'sneeze'?",
        "answer": "fneasan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the Spanish word for 'festival'?",
        "answer": "fiesta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the language of Hungary?",
        "answer": "Magyar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the literal meaning of 'pince-nez'?",
        "answer": "pinch nose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Mercedes Benz motto 'Das beste oder nichts'?",
        "answer": "The best or nothing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the official language of Austria?",
        "answer": "german"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What two words make the word 'meld'?",
        "answer": "melt and weld"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What was the language of ancient India?",
        "answer": "Sanskrit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Law",
        "question": "In which country was it once against the law to slam your car door?",
        "answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Lawn Mowers",
        "question": "How fast does the tip of a standard rotary mower travel? (in km/h)",
        "answer": "two hundred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "What was the Lone Ranger's real name?",
        "answer": "John Reid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Where does Nessie live?",
        "answer": "Loch Ness"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who are santa's reindeer, in alphabetical order?",
        "answer": "blitzen, comet, dancer, dasher, prancer and vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who created the round table?",
        "answer": "Merlin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who was Bonnie Parker's partner?",
        "answer": "Clyde Barrow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who was Clyde Barrow's partner?",
        "answer": "Bonnie Parker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who was John Reid?",
        "answer": "Lone Ranger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Legends",
        "question": "Who was the Lone Ranger's Indian companion?",
        "answer": "Tonto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "As what did H.G. Wells refer to Adolf Hitler?",
        "answer": "A certifiable lunatic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many books are there in Anne Rice's vampire series?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many stories did enid blyton publish in 1959?",
        "answer": "fifty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'A Christmas Carol', how many ghosts visited Scrooge?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'A Christmas Carol', what was the name of the miser?",
        "answer": "Ebenezer Scrooge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Alice In Wonderland', who never stopped sobbing?",
        "answer": "Mock Turtle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Romeo and Juliet', about what was Mercutio's long monologue?",
        "answer": "Queen Mab"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Romeo and Juliet', who gave a long monologue about Queen Mab?",
        "answer": "Mercutio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Romeo and Juliet', who said 'I have a faint cold, fear thrills through my veins'?",
        "answer": "Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Romeo and Juliet', who says 'make the bridal bed in that dim monument where Tybalt lies?",
        "answer": "Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In 'Romeo and Juliet', who says 'what must be must be'?",
        "answer": "Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In one of Donald Horne's novels, as what was Australia dubbed?",
        "answer": "The lucky country"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In one of Donald Horne's novels, which was 'the lucky country'?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In the Dr Seuss books, which elephant hatched an egg?",
        "answer": "Horton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "In which book did four ghosts visit Scrooge?",
        "answer": "A Christmas Carol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "On what book was 'Three Days Of The Condor' based?",
        "answer": "Six Days Of The Condor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "The Hardy Boys and ------?",
        "answer": "Nancy Drew"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What Dr Seuss character steals Christmas?",
        "answer": "Grinch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What controversial book did Germaine Greer write?",
        "answer": "The Female Eunuch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What shakespearean play refers to the date of epiphany?",
        "answer": "Twelfth Night"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What story features flopsy, mopsy and cottontail?",
        "answer": "Peter Rabbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What subject did 'Mr. Chips' teach?",
        "answer": "Latin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What was H.G Wells' first novel?",
        "answer": "The Time Machine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What was Lestat's last name?",
        "answer": "de Lioncourt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What were the dolls in the novel 'Valley Of The Dolls'?",
        "answer": "pills"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What were the two cities in 'A Tale Of Two Cities'?",
        "answer": "London and Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Which Tennesee Williams play is about a Sicilian-American woman?",
        "answer": "The Rose Tattoo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Which book featured the miser Scrooge?",
        "answer": "A Christmas Carol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Which is the only book written by Margaret Mitchell?",
        "answer": "Gone With The Wind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who created 'Horton' the elephant?",
        "answer": "Dr. Seuss"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who created 'Maudie Frickett'?",
        "answer": "Jonathan Winters"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who created 'The Saint'?",
        "answer": "Leslie Charteris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who did Macduff kill?",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who did author Leslie Charteris create?",
        "answer": "The Saint"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who dubbed Australia 'the lucky country'?",
        "answer": "Donald Horne"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who killed Macbeth?",
        "answer": "Macduff"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who said 'But, soft! what light through yonder window breaks'?",
        "answer": "Romeo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who was Winnie the Pooh's neighbour?",
        "answer": "Piglet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who was the author of 'Dracula'?",
        "answer": "Bram Stoker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who was the human companion of Willow?",
        "answer": "Mad Mardigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote '1984'?",
        "answer": "George Orwell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'A Christmas Carol'?",
        "answer": "Charles Dickens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'A Tale Of Two Cities'?",
        "answer": "Charles Dickens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'A Tale Of Two Cities'?",
        "answer": "Charles Dickens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Alice In Wonderland'?",
        "answer": "Lewis Carroll"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Gone With The Wind'?",
        "answer": "Margaret Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Psycho'?",
        "answer": "Robert Bloch"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Birds'?",
        "answer": "Daphne du Maurier"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Female Eunuch'?",
        "answer": "Germaine Greer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Hobbit'?",
        "answer": "J.R.R. Tolkien"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Rose Tattoo'?",
        "answer": "Tennessee Williams"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Time Machine'?",
        "answer": "H.G. Wells"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Valley Of The Dolls'?",
        "answer": "Jacqueline Susann"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Weird Harold and Fat Albert'?",
        "answer": "Bill Cosby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote 'little lamb, who made thee'?",
        "answer": "William Blake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote the 'Dragonriders Of Pern' series?",
        "answer": "Anne McCaffrey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote the 'Father Brown' crime stories?",
        "answer": "G.K. Chesterton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote the 'Myth' series?",
        "answer": "Robert Asprin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote the 'Noddy' books?",
        "answer": "Enid Blyton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who wrote the vampire series that featured Lestat as the main character?",
        "answer": "Anne Rice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Who's last words were 'Thus with a kiss I die'?",
        "answer": "Romeo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Longevity",
        "question": "How old was the world's oldest man?",
        "answer": "one hundred and forty one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Longevity",
        "question": "Who was the world's oldest man?",
        "answer": "Bir Narayan Chaudhari"
    },
    {
        "category": "Maritime Trivia",
        "question": "On a ship, what is the line that indicates the maximum load that may be transported?",
        "answer": "Plimsoll Line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many different letters are used in the roman numeral system?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is 65% of 60?",
        "answer": "39"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the maximum number of integer degrees in a reflex angle?",
        "answer": "three hundred and fifty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the maximum number of integer degrees in an acute angle?",
        "answer": "eighty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the maximum number of integer degrees in an obtuse angle?",
        "answer": "one hundred and seventy nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the minimum number of integer degrees in a reflex angle?",
        "answer": "one hundred and eighty one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the minimum number of integer degrees in an acute angle?",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the minimum number of integer degrees in an obtuse angle?",
        "answer": "ninety one"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the only digit that has the same number of letters as its value?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What is the square root of one quarter?",
        "answer": "one half"
    },
    {
        "category": "Measurement",
        "question": "What instrument measures walking distance?",
        "answer": "pedometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicien",
        "question": "In what body part does an osteopath specialise?",
        "answer": "bones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A salt enema was given to children to rid them of ------?",
        "answer": "Threadworm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Heroin is the brand name of morphine once marketed by which pharmaceutical company?",
        "answer": "Bayer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In the early 20th century, rattlesnake venom was used to treat which illness?",
        "answer": "epilepsy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "North American Indians ate watercress to dissolve gravel and stones in the ------?",
        "answer": "bladder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "North American Indians ate watercress to dissolve what in the bladder?",
        "answer": "gravel and stones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "On what part of the body is an 'LTK procedure' performed?",
        "answer": "eyes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What did North American Indians eat to dissolve gravel and stones in the bladder?",
        "answer": "watercress"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What does a sphygmomanometer measure?",
        "answer": "blood pressure"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What does hepatitis affect?",
        "answer": "liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What instrument measures blood pressure?",
        "answer": "sphygmomanometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is a the technical name for a heart attack?",
        "answer": "myocardial infarct"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is acute nasopharyngitis?",
        "answer": "A cold"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is another name for consumption?",
        "answer": "tuberculosis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is another name for tuberculosis?",
        "answer": "consumption"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What was given to children to rid them of threadworm?",
        "answer": "salt enema"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Who ate watercress to dissolve gravel and stones in the bladder?",
        "answer": "North American Indians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Who invented the smallpox vaccine?",
        "answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Who was the first to use rubber gloves during surgery?",
        "answer": "Dr. W. S. Halstead"
    },
    {
        "category": "Military",
        "question": "As a result of their wearing high leather collars to protect their necks from sabres, as what were the first US marines known?",
        "answer": "leathernecks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Military",
        "question": "What do the letters 'SAM' mean in SAM missiles?",
        "answer": "Surface To Air"
    },
    {
        "category": "Military",
        "question": "What is the mascot of the US naval academy?",
        "answer": "goat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Military",
        "question": "What is the naval equivalent of an army Major?",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Commander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Military",
        "question": "With which hand do soldiers salute?",
        "answer": "right"
    },
    {
        "category": "Minerals",
        "question": "What forms when a diamond is cut with a laser?",
        "answer": "graphite dust"
    },
    {
        "category": "Minerals",
        "question": "What is also known as the 'bishop's stone'?",
        "answer": "amethyst"
    },
    {
        "category": "Minerals",
        "question": "What is the violet variety of quartz otherwise known as?",
        "answer": "amethyst"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mining",
        "question": "Approximately how deep are the deepest mines? (in km)",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mining",
        "question": "In which country is the largest gold refinery?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mining",
        "question": "What is the deepest mine in the world?",
        "answer": "Western Deep Levels Mine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mining",
        "question": "What is the name of the largest gold refinery?",
        "answer": "Rand Refinery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mining",
        "question": "Where are the deepest mines?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Minreals",
        "question": "Graphite dust is formed when what is cut with a laser?",
        "answer": "diamond"
    },
    {
        "category": "Misnomers",
        "question": "What are Swedish buns called?",
        "answer": "Danishes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Modern Myths",
        "question": "What has no reflection, no shadow, and can't stand the smell of garlic?",
        "answer": "vampire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Monuments",
        "question": "Which man has the most monuments erected in his honour?",
        "answer": "Buddha"
    },
    {
        "category": "Monuments",
        "question": "Which woman has the most monuments erected in her honour?",
        "answer": "Virgin Mary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "From which team did Marlboro switch its backing to Mclaren in the 1974 season?",
        "answer": "BRM"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "How many pole positions did Ayrton Senna score?",
        "answer": "sixty five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "In 1976, James Hunt was disqualified after winning which Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "British"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Name the first automobile racetrack in America.",
        "answer": "Indianapolis Motor Speedway"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Over what time period is the Le Mans endurance motor race?",
        "answer": "Twenty four hours"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "To which team did Marlboro switch its backing from BRM in the 1974 season?",
        "answer": "Mclaren"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "What colours was the Ferrari Formula 1 car in the 1964 US Grand prix?",
        "answer": "blue and white"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "What event marked the 1954 french grand prix?",
        "answer": "The return of Mercedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Where do the Italians host the Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "Monza"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Which car won the 1953 Italian Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "Maserati"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Which new engine regulation replaced the 2.5 litre rule at the start of the 1961 season?",
        "answer": "1.5 litre rule"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Who hosts the Monza Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Who qualified for pole position in the 1984 Brazilian Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "Elio de Angelis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Who was disqualified after winning the 1976 British Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "James Hunt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Who was the driver for the Jordan team in the 1998 Grand Prix?",
        "answer": "Damon Hill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Motor Racing",
        "question": "Who won the 1966 F1 championship?",
        "answer": "Jack Brabham"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mottos",
        "question": "Whose motto is 'Be prepared'?",
        "answer": "Boy Scouts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mountain Climbing",
        "question": "Who conquered the Matterhorn in 1865?",
        "answer": "Edward Whymper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Stars",
        "question": "Who was Lauren Bacall's first husband?",
        "answer": "Humphrey Bogart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "About which family are the Godfather films?",
        "answer": "Corleone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "For which film did Art Carney win best actor Oscar in 1974?",
        "answer": "Harry and Tonto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In 'Star Wars', who was C3P0's sidekick?",
        "answer": "R2D2"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In 'The Shining' what was the child's imaginary friend's name (the one who told him things that were going to happen)?",
        "answer": "Tony"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the 'Nightmare On Elm Street' films, who played Freddy Krueger?",
        "answer": "Robert Englund"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'American Hot Wax', who did Jay Leno play?",
        "answer": "Mookie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'American Hot Wax', who played the 'Mookie'?",
        "answer": "Jay Leno"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'Hackers', how old was 'zero_kool' when he was first arrested?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'Home Alone', who played the baddies?",
        "answer": "Joe Pesci and Daniel Stern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'Pretty Woman', for who was Goldie Hawn the body double?",
        "answer": "Julia Roberts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film 'The Day Of The Jackal', who played the Jackal?",
        "answer": "Edward Fox"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In what did someone squish her hands to make the sound of e.t walking?",
        "answer": "jelly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In what film did Whoopi Goldberg make her screen debut?",
        "answer": "The Color Purple"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which James Bond film does the villain cheat at golf?",
        "answer": "Goldfinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which film did Henry Fonda play a fallen priest?",
        "answer": "The Fugitive"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which film did Paul Newman and Robert Redford hold hands and jump into a river?",
        "answer": "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which film was Goldie Hawn the body double for Julia Roberts?",
        "answer": "Pretty Woman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Juliette Binoche won an academy award for best supporting role in which film?",
        "answer": "English Patient"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Pancho was whose faithful sidekick?",
        "answer": "Cisco Kid's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "The film 'The Wizard Of ------'?",
        "answer": "Oz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Tippi Hedren is best known for her lead role in which film?",
        "answer": "The Birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Was Shirley Temple 21, 25 or 29 when she made her last film?",
        "answer": "21"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What Marlon Brando film was widely banned?",
        "answer": "Last Tango In Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What did Dorothy's house land on in 'The Wizard Of Oz'?",
        "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the West"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film featured a cat named Mr. Bigglesworth?",
        "answer": "Austin Powers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film is generally considered the worst film ever made?",
        "answer": "Attack of the Killer Tomatoes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film marked James Cagney's return to the screen after 20 years?",
        "answer": "Ragtime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film starred Helen Hunt, Cary Elwes and Bill Paxton?",
        "answer": "Twister"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What film starred Rosie O'Donnell, Rita Wilson and Meg Ryan?",
        "answer": "Sleepless in Seattle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the film in which Steven Segal's character dies?",
        "answer": "Executive Decision"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What is the sequel to the film 'Every Which Way But Loose'?",
        "answer": "Every Which Way You Can"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Ben Stiller's character called in 'Mystery Men'?",
        "answer": "Mr. Furious"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Eddie Murphy's character name in 'Beverley Hills Cop'?",
        "answer": "Axel Foley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Garth's last name in 'Wayne's World'?",
        "answer": "Algar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was John Wayne's real name?",
        "answer": "Marion Morrison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Keanu Reeves' computer world alias in 'The Matrix'?",
        "answer": "Neo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Keanu Reeves' first big film?",
        "answer": "Point Break"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was Kevin Bacon's first big hit?",
        "answer": "Footloose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was painted on Peter Fonda's helmet motorcycle helmet in 'Easy Rider'?",
        "answer": "stars and stripes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first film directed by Robert Redford?",
        "answer": "Ordinary People"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the pinball machine in the film 'Tommy'?",
        "answer": "Wizard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of the two space shuttles in 'Armegeddon'?",
        "answer": "Freedom and Independence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "What was used for blood in the film 'psycho'?",
        "answer": "chocolate syrup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which basketball star played a genie in 'Kazaam'?",
        "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which film preceded 'Magnum Force' and 'The Enforcer'?",
        "answer": "Dirty Harry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which films are about the Corleone family?",
        "answer": "The Godfather films"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Which was the first 'Indiana Jones' film?",
        "answer": "Raiders Of The Lost Ark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who appeared in 'St. Elmo's Fire', 'The Scarlett Letter' and 'Striptease'?",
        "answer": "Demi Moore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who did Charlie Becker play in 'The Wizard of Oz'?",
        "answer": "The mayor of the munchkins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who directed 'The Shining'?",
        "answer": "Stanley Kubrick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who directed the Movie 'Psycho' from Robert Bloch?",
        "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who directed the classic thriller 'The Birds'?",
        "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who directed the film 'Ordinary People'?",
        "answer": "Robert Redford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who directed the film 'The Birds' from Daphne du Maurier?",
        "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who does the voice for Yoda in the Star Wars films?",
        "answer": "Frank Oz"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played 'Johnny Mnemonic'?",
        "answer": "Keanu Reeves"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Clyde to Faye Dunaway's Bonnie?",
        "answer": "Warren Beatty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Dr. Frankenfurter in the pop-culture film 'The Rocky Horror Picture Show?",
        "answer": "Tim Curry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Dr. Kildare?",
        "answer": "Richard Chamberlain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Eddie in the pop-culture film 'The Rocky Horror Picture Show?",
        "answer": "Meat Loaf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Hopalong Cassidy?",
        "answer": "William Boyd"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Louis in 'Interview With The Vampire'?",
        "answer": "Brad Pitt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Queen Amidala in the latest 'Star Wars' film?",
        "answer": "Natalie Portman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played in the film 'Ragtime' after 20 years offscreen?",
        "answer": "James Cagney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the 'Universal Soldier'?",
        "answer": "Jean-Claude Van Damme"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the mayor of the munchkins in 'The Wizard of Oz'?",
        "answer": "Charlie Becker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the murder victim in the original version of 'Psycho'?",
        "answer": "Janet Leigh"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the president of the U.S in 'Air Force One'?",
        "answer": "Harrison Ford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the title role in the 'Mad Max' series of films?",
        "answer": "Mel Gibson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who played the title role in the 1978 version of 'Superman'?",
        "answer": "Christopher Reeve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred in 'Conan The Barbarian'?",
        "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred in the 1952 film 'Niagara'?",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred in the film 'The Man With Two Brains'?",
        "answer": "Steve Martin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred in the film version of 'To Kill A Mockingbird'?",
        "answer": "Gregory Peck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Dr. Zhivago's great love?",
        "answer": "Lara"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was John Wayne's musical co-star in true grit?",
        "answer": "Glen Campbell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Miss Hungary in 1936?",
        "answer": "Zsa-Zsa Gabor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the Cisco Kid's faithful sidekick?",
        "answer": "Pancho"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the director of 'Terminator' and 'Titanic'?",
        "answer": "James Cameron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the villain in 'Star Wars'?",
        "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Whose films include 'Giant', 'Written On The Wind' and 'A Farewell To Arms'?",
        "answer": "Rock Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie trivia",
        "question": "In which film did Jay Leno play 'Mookie'?",
        "answer": "American Hot Wax"
    },
    {
        "category": "Multiple Meanings",
        "question": "What animal has the same name as a high church official?",
        "answer": "cardinal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "'Hang On Sloopy' was the official rock song of which band?",
        "answer": "Ohio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "'White Room' was a hit off which Eric Clapton album?",
        "answer": "Cream"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "As what is Merle Haggard also known as?",
        "answer": "Okie from Muskogee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Besides the Stones, which group had the longest touring career until the founder's death in 1995?",
        "answer": "The Grateful Dead"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Bill Justis was a studio musician when he recorded this 'sloppy' instrumental in october 1957?",
        "answer": "Raunchy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Country singer Vince ----?",
        "answer": "Gill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Crosby, Stills and Nash's debut album included a song about a girl and the colour of her eyes. Name that song.",
        "answer": "Sweet Judy Blue Eyes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "For whom did Colonel Tom Parker act as manager?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Formerly with Spencer Davis, he went on to form Traffic with Dave Mason. He is?",
        "answer": "Steve Winwood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "From what platform does the 'Chattanooga Choo Choo' leave Pennsylvania station?",
        "answer": "twenty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "From which station does the 'Chattanooga Choo Choo' leave?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania station"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Hey! What was the name of the hit song released by 'The Romantics' in February 1980?",
        "answer": "That's What I Like About You"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "How many members are in the 'fairfield four'?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "How old was Leann Rhimes when she became a country music star?",
        "answer": "fourteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "How old was Leann Rhimes when she recorded her first album?",
        "answer": "eleven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 'La Traviata', what does Violetta sing?",
        "answer": "Sempre Libera"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 'La Traviata', who sings 'Sempre Libera'?",
        "answer": "Violetta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 1958, who had a pop music hit with 'Willie and the Hand Jive'?",
        "answer": "Johnny Otis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 1968, who released 'Carnival of life' and 'Recital'?",
        "answer": "Lee Michaels"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 1981, who won song of the year with 'Sailing'?",
        "answer": "Christopher Cross"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In 1987, who released her second album 'Solitude Standing'?",
        "answer": "Suzanne Vega"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In a 1976 release, who wanted to 'fly like an eagle'?",
        "answer": "Steve Miller Band"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In late 1957, Buddy Holly's solo release 'Peggy Sue' challenged which song recorded with The Crickets?",
        "answer": "Oh Boy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In the opera 'Don Giovanni', what was Leporello?",
        "answer": "servant"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta sing 'Sempre Libera'?",
        "answer": "La Traviata"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "In which opera does Leporello entertain a vengeful jilted lover?",
        "answer": "Don Giovanni"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Michael di Lorenzo was one of the lead dancers on which Michael Jackson video?",
        "answer": "Beat It"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "R. Kelly sings: 'If I can see it then I can do it, if I just believe it, there's nothing to it'. What's the song title?",
        "answer": "I Believe I Can Fly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Randy Travis said his love was 'deeper than the ------'?",
        "answer": "holler"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Savage Garden took 13 nominations and 10 wins at which awards?",
        "answer": "ARIA awards"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Singer Paula ------?",
        "answer": "Abdul"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Sung by Robert Palmer, '------ to love'?",
        "answer": "Addicted"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What Don Mclean song laments the day Buddy Holly died?",
        "answer": "American Pie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What album holds the world record for copies sold?",
        "answer": "Thriller"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What are the separators on a guitar neck called?",
        "answer": "frets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What classic rock band sang the song 'Paint It, Black'?",
        "answer": "Rolling Stones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What did George Harrison discover on the Witwatersrand?",
        "answer": "gold"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What did Sheryl Crow do before she became a singer?",
        "answer": "teach"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What does the term 'DJ' mean?",
        "answer": "Disc Jockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What hardcore rock group sings, 'Blind' and 'Clown'?",
        "answer": "Korn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What instrument are you playing when you perform a rim shot?",
        "answer": "drums"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What instrument does an organ grinder play?",
        "answer": "hurdy gurdy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is Cape Town's major choir called?",
        "answer": "Philharmonic choir"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is Elton John's real name?",
        "answer": "Reginald Dwight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is Vanilla Ice's real name?",
        "answer": "Robert van Winkle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is a cello's full name?",
        "answer": "violoncello"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is a violoncello usually called?",
        "answer": "cello"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is the name given to the type of West Indian music made famous by artists such as Bob Marley and Peter Tosh?",
        "answer": "reggae"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What is the official birthplace of country music?",
        "answer": "Bristol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What license plate number is on the Volkswagon on the cover of The Beatles' 'Abbey Road' Album?",
        "answer": "281F"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song did Elton John and George Michael sing as a duet?",
        "answer": "Don't Let The Sun Go Down On Me"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song was originally 'Good Morning To You' before the words were changed and it was published in 1935?",
        "answer": "Happy Birthday To You"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What song's words were changed and then published in 1935 as 'Happy Birthday To You'?",
        "answer": "Good Morning To You"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was Elvis Presley's twin brother's name?",
        "answer": "Garon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was Jethro Tull before donating his name to a British epic rock group?",
        "answer": "agriculturist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was the average age of United States soldiers in the Vietnam war?",
        "answer": "nineteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was the first CD pressed in the USA?",
        "answer": "Born In The USA"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "What was the original name of Paul McCartney's fictional church cleaner 'Eleanor Rigby'?",
        "answer": "Miss Daisy Hawkins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Where did George Harrison discover gold?",
        "answer": "Witwatersrand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Where is the Rock and Roll Hall Of Fame?",
        "answer": "Cleveland, Ohio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which 1960's group sang a song inspired by 'Alice In Wonderland'?",
        "answer": "The Jefferson Airplane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which 1980's Pink Floyd album was made into a film that starred Bob Geldof, and featured the artwork of cartoonist Gerald Scarfe?",
        "answer": "The Wall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which Australian duo took 13 nominations and 10 wins at the ARIA awards?",
        "answer": "Savage Garden"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which Elton John song was re-recorded as a requiem for Lady Diana Spencer?",
        "answer": "Candle In The Wind"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which british group recorded the 1983 hit 'Owner Of A Lonely Heart'?",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which country and western singer is known as the 'okie from muskogee'?",
        "answer": "Merle Haggard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which singer is a former school teacher?",
        "answer": "Sheryl Crow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Which singer/songwriter worked in a factory making toilets for airplanes before he recorded 'Aint No Sunshine'?",
        "answer": "Bill Withers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who 'imagined' a better world?",
        "answer": "John Lennon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who advised us to 'break on through to the other side'?",
        "answer": "Jim Morrison (of The Doors)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who appeared solo at the Woodstock festival after leaving 'The Lovin' Spoonful'?",
        "answer": "John Sebastian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who began his career with 'The Yardbirds' and established himself as one of the best rock guitarists of his generation?",
        "answer": "Eric Clapton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who began his professional career with Black Sabbath?",
        "answer": "Ozzy Osbourne"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who collaborated with John Lennon on 'Whatever Gets You Through The Night'?",
        "answer": "Elton John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who did a version of 'One Bourbon, One Scotch, One Beer' on his 1977 debut album?",
        "answer": "George Thorogood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who did the music for the 1970's film 'Saturday Night Fever'?",
        "answer": "Bee Gees"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who discovered gold on the Witwatersrand?",
        "answer": "George Harrison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who founded 'Live Aid' and 'Band Aid'?",
        "answer": "Bob Geldof & Midge Ure"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who is Reginald Dwight known as?",
        "answer": "Elton John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who is Robert van Winkle?",
        "answer": "Vanilla Ice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who is the elder statesman of 'british blues', and fronted 'The Bluesbreakers'?",
        "answer": "John Mayall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who is the lead singer of 'The Doors'?",
        "answer": "Jim Morrison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who is the only singer to have no.1 hits in the 50's, 60's, 70's, 80's and 90's?",
        "answer": "Cliff Richard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who produced 'Sgt Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band'?",
        "answer": "George Martin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who recorded 'A Boy Named Sue'?",
        "answer": "Johnny Cash"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who released 'Time, Love and Tenderness' in 1981?",
        "answer": "Michael Bolton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who released 'Tuesday Night Music Club' in 1993?",
        "answer": "Sheryl Crow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who released a chart-busting album in 1976 which featured 'The Lido Shuffle'?",
        "answer": "Boz Scaggs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who released the double album 'Goodbye Yellow Brick Road' in 1973?",
        "answer": "Elton John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'All Right Now'?",
        "answer": "Free"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Any Way You Want Me'?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Bad Case Of Loving You'?",
        "answer": "Robert Palmer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Beat It'?",
        "answer": "Michael Jackson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Beauty and the Beast'?",
        "answer": "Celine Dion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Born In The USA'?",
        "answer": "Bruce Springsteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Forever and Ever, Amen'?",
        "answer": "Randy Travis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Good Morning To You?",
        "answer": "Mildred and Patty Hill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'I'm A Believer'?",
        "answer": "Monkees"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'In The Air Tonight'?",
        "answer": "Phil Collins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Islands In The Stream' with Dolly Parton?",
        "answer": "Kenny Rogers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Islands In The Stream' with Kenny Rogers?",
        "answer": "Dolly Parton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Jet Airliner'?",
        "answer": "Steve Miller Band"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'Rescue Me'?",
        "answer": "Fontella Bass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'That's Alright Mama'?",
        "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'We've only just begun'?",
        "answer": "Carpenters"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang 'You Can Call Me Al'?",
        "answer": "Paul Simon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang about 'Commitment'?",
        "answer": "Leann Rhimes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang about 'The Boogie Woogie Bugle Boy Of Company B'?",
        "answer": "The Andrews Sisters"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang about Desmond and Molly Jones?",
        "answer": "The Beatles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang for 'Bad company' and 'Free', then went out on his own?",
        "answer": "Paul Rodgers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sang with 'The Dakotas'?",
        "answer": "Billy J. Kramer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who sings 'Sweet Home Alabama'?",
        "answer": "Lynyrd Skynyrd"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wanted 'a lover with a slow hand'?",
        "answer": "The Pointer Sisters"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wanted 'a new drug'?",
        "answer": "Huey Lewis and The News"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was 'hooked on a feeling'?",
        "answer": "Blue Suede"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was a member of 'Crosby, Stills and Nash' and 'The Hollies'?",
        "answer": "Graham Nash"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the Indian maiden in Johnny Preston's 'Running Bear'?",
        "answer": "Little White Dove"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the first female to enter the Billboard charts in 1985?",
        "answer": "Whitney Houston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the oldest member of The Beatles?",
        "answer": "Ringo Starr"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who was the only songwriter to win the Eurovision Song Contest twice?",
        "answer": "Johnny Logan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Roll Over Beethoven'?",
        "answer": "Chuck Berry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the opera 'The Giant'?",
        "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the opera 'The Masked Ball'?",
        "answer": "Giuseppe Verdi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the opera 'Tosca'?",
        "answer": "Giacomo Puccini"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the opera 'norma'?",
        "answer": "Vincenzo Bellini"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the oprea 'La Traviata'?",
        "answer": "Guiseppe Verdi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the song 'Do They Know It's Christmas' with Bob Geldof?",
        "answer": "Midge Ure"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who wrote the song 'Do They Know It's Christmas' with Midge Ure?",
        "answer": "Bob Geldof"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "Who's first release was 'Talking Heads 77'?",
        "answer": "Psycho Killer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Music",
        "question": "----- in the name of love?",
        "answer": "Stop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Muthology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, the riddle of what did Oedipus solve?",
        "answer": "sphinx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mytholgy",
        "question": "Apollo was the Greek god of ------?",
        "answer": "prophecy and archery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Dionysus was the greek god of ------?",
        "answer": "Wine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Egyptian mythology, what is the life force called?",
        "answer": "Ka"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who is known as the god of the desert?",
        "answer": "Ash"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who is the god of the underworld?",
        "answer": "Osiris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who was Horus' mother?",
        "answer": "Isis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who was Isis the wife of?",
        "answer": "Osiris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In English mythology, who caused the death of the Lady of Shallot?",
        "answer": "Sir Lancelot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology who did Athena turn into a spider?",
        "answer": "Arachne"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, how many heads did Hydra have?",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, into what did Athena turn Arachne?",
        "answer": "spider"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, what animal is associated with Athena?",
        "answer": "owl"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, what did Daedalus construct for Minos?",
        "answer": "labyrinth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, what was Minos the king of?",
        "answer": "Crete"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, where did Perseus kill his grandfather?",
        "answer": "Larrisan games"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Jocasta marry?",
        "answer": "Oedipus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Minos hire to construct the labyrinth?",
        "answer": "Daedalus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who had nine heads?",
        "answer": "Hydra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who hired Daedalus to construct the labyrinth?",
        "answer": "Minos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who ruled over the island of Samos?",
        "answer": "Polycrates"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who solved the riddle of the Sphinx?",
        "answer": "Oedipus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who turned Arachne into a spider?",
        "answer": "Athena"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Jason's wife?",
        "answer": "Medea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Medea's husband?",
        "answer": "Jason"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the only mortal gorgon?",
        "answer": "Medusa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the son of Peleus and Thetis?",
        "answer": "Achilles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "In Greek mythology, who were Achilles' parents?",
        "answer": "Peleus and Thetis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Neptune was the Roman god of the ------?",
        "answer": "sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Persephone was the Greek goddess of ------?",
        "answer": "spring"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Poseidon was the Greek god of the ------?",
        "answer": "sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "What mythical Scottish town appears for one day every 100 years?",
        "answer": "Brigadoon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Which Norse god had the Valkyries as handmaidens?",
        "answer": "Odin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Which Titan had snakes for hair?",
        "answer": "Medusa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who did the Norse god Odin have as handmaidens?",
        "answer": "Valkyries"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who is the Greek messenger god?",
        "answer": "Hermes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who is the Norse god of lightning?",
        "answer": "Odin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who is the Norse god of mischief?",
        "answer": "Loki"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who is the Norse god of thunder and war?",
        "answer": "Thor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who is the mother of Apollo and Artemis?",
        "answer": "Leto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was Hercules' father?",
        "answer": "Zeus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was Hercules' stepmother?",
        "answer": "Hera"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was the Greek god of fire?",
        "answer": "Hephaestus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was the Greek god of prophecy and archery?",
        "answer": "Apollo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was the Greek god of wine?",
        "answer": "Dionysus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of spring?",
        "answer": "Persephone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mythology",
        "question": "Who, in Egyptian mythology, is the god of the dead?",
        "answer": "Anubis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nationalities",
        "question": "Which people invented the compass?",
        "answer": "Chinese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Approximately how many pounds of salt is in every gallon of seawater?",
        "answer": "one quarter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "At which time of year do children grow fastest?",
        "answer": "springtime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "By what process is rock worn down by the weather?",
        "answer": "erosion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "During pregnancy, how many times its normal size does the human uterus expand?",
        "answer": "five hundred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "How many hearts do earthworms have?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "Of what do earthworms have five?",
        "answer": "hearts"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What animal has bony plates and rolls up into a ball if it is frightened?",
        "answer": "armadillo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What has approximately 1/4 pound of salt in every gallon?",
        "answer": "seawater"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "What is the heart rate of the blue whale? (in beats per minute)",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nature",
        "question": "When does the human uterus expand 500 times its normal size?",
        "answer": "during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nomenclature",
        "question": "Eras are divided into units called --------?",
        "answer": "periods"
    },
    {
        "category": "Not Telling!",
        "question": "What can be either new, last or gibbous?",
        "answer": "The moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nuresry rhymes",
        "question": "Who sat on her tuffet?",
        "answer": "Little Miss Muffet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "In the song 'Skip To My Lou', in what beverage are the flies?",
        "answer": "Buttermilk"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Where did Little Miss Muffet sit?",
        "answer": "On her tuffet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nursery Rhymes",
        "question": "Who is Mother Goose's son?",
        "answer": "Jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "Is wholemeal bread brown or white?",
        "answer": "brown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "Lack of Vitamin D causes which disease?",
        "answer": "rickets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "Rickets is caused by a lack of which vitamin?",
        "answer": "vitamin D"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "Six ounces of orange juice contains the minimum daily requirement for which vitamin?",
        "answer": "vitamin C"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "What does iron deficiency cause?",
        "answer": "anaemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Nutrition",
        "question": "What makes brown bread healthier than white bread?",
        "answer": "wholemeal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "Basmati is a type of what?",
        "answer": "Rice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What does a notaphile collect?",
        "answer": "Banknotes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What does a philluminist collect?",
        "answer": "Match box labels"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What does an ombrometer measure?",
        "answer": "rainfall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What is a 'funambulist'?",
        "answer": "A tightrope walker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What is a pugilist?",
        "answer": "boxer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What is another name for a  tightrope walker?",
        "answer": "funambulist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "What is someone who collects banknotes called?",
        "answer": "Notaphile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd Words",
        "question": "With what is rainfall measured?",
        "answer": "ombrometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Odd words",
        "question": "What is a 'somnambulist'?",
        "answer": "sleepwalker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Oil Production",
        "question": "Which south african oil company has estblished the only commercially proven 'oil from coal' operations in the world?",
        "answer": "Sasol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "In ancient Greece, where were the original Olympics held?",
        "answer": "Olympia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "The Olympic motto 'citius, altius, fortius' means what?",
        "answer": "Faster, higher, stronger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "What is the Olympic motto in the original Latin?",
        "answer": "Citius, altius, fortius"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "Where were the 1956 Summer Olympics held?",
        "answer": "Melbourne, Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "Where were the 1960 summer Olympics held?",
        "answer": "Rome, Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "Who did Zola Budd trip in the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics?",
        "answer": "Mary Decker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Olympics",
        "question": "Who tripped Mary Decker in the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics?",
        "answer": "Zola Budd"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "How many episodes were there in the original Star Trek series?",
        "answer": "seventy five"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "In 'Star Trek' Jean ------ Picard?",
        "answer": "Luc"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "In 'Star Trek', what is Data's rank?",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Commander"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "In 'Star Trek', who was the captain of the 'Enterprise C'?",
        "answer": "Rachel Garret"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "What is the registry number of the enterprise in the original Star Trek?",
        "answer": "NCC 1701"
    },
    {
        "category": "One For The Trekkies",
        "question": "Who played Deanna Troi in 'Star Trek The Next Generation'?",
        "answer": "Marina Sirtis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Optics",
        "question": "What colour on black produces the most visible combination?",
        "answer": "yellow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Orienteering",
        "question": "On maps, what is the technical name for the 'you are here' arrow?",
        "answer": "ideo locator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Philosophy",
        "question": "The last line of which document is 'working men of all countries, unite!'?",
        "answer": "Communist Manifesto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "At what angle above the horizon must the sun be to create a rainbow? (in degrees)",
        "answer": "forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "Waves 'break' when their height is how much more than the depth of the water?",
        "answer": "seven tenths"
    },
    {
        "category": "Physics",
        "question": "What is the name given to elementary particles originating in the sun and other stars, that continuously rain down on the earth?",
        "answer": "cosmic rays"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "In England, what is the Speaker of the House not allowed to do?",
        "answer": "speak"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Of which island do Ireland, Britain, Iceland and Norway dispute ownership?",
        "answer": "Rockall"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "What does Israel call its parliament?",
        "answer": "Knesset"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Which island do the nationalist Chinese occupy?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Which nation calls its parliament 'The Knesset'?",
        "answer": "Israel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Politics",
        "question": "Who succeeded Charles de Gaulle as president of France?",
        "answer": "Georges Pompidour"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pop Optics",
        "question": "What colour lenses are required to view a 3-D film?",
        "answer": "red and green"
    },
    {
        "category": "Popsicle Inventors",
        "question": "Who invented popsicles?",
        "answer": "Frank Epperson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "As who is Vincent Furnier known?",
        "answer": "Alice Cooper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "What is Alice Cooper's real name?",
        "answer": "Vincent Furnier"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "What is Conway Twitty's real name?",
        "answer": "Harold Lloyd Jenkins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "What is Harold Lloyd Jenkins' stage name?",
        "answer": "Conway Twitty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "What is Wynonna Judd's real name?",
        "answer": "Christina Clair Ciminella"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "Who is Anne Mae Bullock better known as?",
        "answer": "Tina Turner"
    },
    {
        "category": "Pseudonyms",
        "question": "Who is Christina Claire Ciminella otherwise known as?",
        "answer": "Wynonna Judd"
    },
    {
        "category": "Psychology",
        "question": "Of what did Sigmund Freud have a morbid fear?",
        "answer": "ferns"
    },
    {
        "category": "Psychology",
        "question": "Who wrote 'Sexual Behavior In The Human Male' in 1948?",
        "answer": "Alfred Kinsey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Psychology",
        "question": "With what branch of medicine is Franz Mesmer associated?",
        "answer": "hypnotism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Railways",
        "question": "New York has the longest subway system in ------?",
        "answer": "North America"
    },
    {
        "category": "Railways",
        "question": "What city has the most underground stations in the world?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Recorded Media",
        "question": "Who is the spokesperson for the exercise tapes 'Tae Bo'?",
        "answer": "Billy Blanks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Recreational Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the common name for lysergic acid diethylamide?",
        "answer": "LSD"
    },
    {
        "category": "Relativity",
        "question": "What does the 'c' in the equation e=mc^2 stand for?",
        "answer": "speed of light"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "A catholic minister is known as a?",
        "answer": "Priest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "In what city does a certain church forbid burping or sneezing?",
        "answer": "Omaha, Nebraska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Of the 266 popes, how many died violently?",
        "answer": "thirty three"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "To where do Muslims make pilgrimage?",
        "answer": "Mecca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "What is God called in the Muslim faith?",
        "answer": "Allah"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "What is a person who has made a pilgimage to Mecca?",
        "answer": "Hajji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "What religious movement was founded by William Booth?",
        "answer": "Salvation Army"
    },
    {
        "category": "Religion",
        "question": "Who founded the Salvation Army?",
        "answer": "William Booth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sad, But True",
        "question": "What are 35% of people using personal ads for dating?",
        "answer": "married"
    },
    {
        "category": "Saints",
        "question": "St Frideswide the patron saint ------?",
        "answer": "Oxford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Saints",
        "question": "St Patrick the patron saint of ------?",
        "answer": "Ireland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Saints",
        "question": "St. Bernard the patron saint of -----?",
        "answer": "skiers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Saints",
        "question": "St. Christopher the patron saint of ------?",
        "answer": "travellers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Saints",
        "question": "Who is the patron saint of skiers?",
        "answer": "St. Bernard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Satellites",
        "question": "What country has the third most satellites in orbit?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "As what is minus forty celcius the same?",
        "answer": "minus forty fahrenheit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "As what is minus forty fahrenheit the same?",
        "answer": "minus forty celcius"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "How many beams of light are used to record a holograph?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "In what does a rhinologist specialise?",
        "answer": "human nose"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "In what was the strength of early lasers measured?",
        "answer": "gillettes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "In which branch of science are monocotyledon and dicotyledon terms?",
        "answer": "Botany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Meteorology is the study of ------?",
        "answer": "weather"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Of what did Aristotle say all things were made up?",
        "answer": "air, earth, fire, and water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Of what is genetics the study?",
        "answer": "heredity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Paedology is the study of ...... ?",
        "answer": "soil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What did Wilhelm Roentgen discover in 1895?",
        "answer": "X-rays"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does breaking the sound barrier cause?",
        "answer": "A sonic boom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What does the Rankine scale measure?",
        "answer": "temperature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is name applied to the study of soil?",
        "answer": "paedology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the number of blue razor blades a given beam can puncture?",
        "answer": "gillette"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the scientific name for brimstone?",
        "answer": "sulphur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the scientific name for earth's outer layer of surface soil or crust?",
        "answer": "lithosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the study of prehistoric plants and animals?",
        "answer": "paleontology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the study of the composition of substances and the changes they undergo?",
        "answer": "chemistry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the study of the earth's physical divisions termed?",
        "answer": "Geography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What is the term that refers to the search for the existence of ghosts?",
        "answer": "eidology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "What was the first recorded message?",
        "answer": "Mary had a little lamb"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Which freezes faster - hot or cold water?",
        "answer": "hot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who developed the laws of electrolysis?",
        "answer": "Michael Faraday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who discovered X-rays?",
        "answer": "Wilhelm Roentgen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who first transmitted radio signals across the Atlantic?",
        "answer": "Enrico Marconi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who said all things were made up of air, earth, fire, and water?",
        "answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Science",
        "question": "Who spoke the first recorded message?",
        "answer": "Thomas Edison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Scouts",
        "question": "What is the boy scout motto?",
        "answer": "Be prepared"
    },
    {
        "category": "Scouts",
        "question": "Who founded the Boy Scouts?",
        "answer": "Lord Baden Powell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sea Crawlies",
        "question": "How many legs does a crab have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Secretions",
        "question": "What is cerumen?",
        "answer": "earwax"
    },
    {
        "category": "Secretions",
        "question": "What is the scientific name for earwax?",
        "answer": "cerumen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a female calf called?",
        "answer": "heifer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a female cat called?",
        "answer": "queen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a male cat called?",
        "answer": "tom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a person who makes barrels called?",
        "answer": "cooper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a resident of Manchester called?",
        "answer": "Mancunian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is a resident of liverpool?",
        "answer": "Liverpudlian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is another word for a female sheep?",
        "answer": "ewe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is podobromhidrosis?",
        "answer": "Smelly feet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is the name given to male sheep?",
        "answer": "ram"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is the name given to the switching of letters in an expression (e.g. saying Jag of Flapan instead of Flag of Japan)?",
        "answer": "spoonerism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Semantics",
        "question": "What is the study of weather technically called?",
        "answer": "meteorology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Shoe Trivia",
        "question": "What is the covering on the tip of a shoelace called?",
        "answer": "aglet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "After who was Deana Carter named?",
        "answer": "Dean Martin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What instrument does Woody Allen play?",
        "answer": "clarinet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What is Cher's maiden name?",
        "answer": "Sarkassian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What is Tina Turner's real name?",
        "answer": "Anne Mae Bullock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What is tattooed on Glen Campbell's arm?",
        "answer": "dagger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What musical instrument did Jack Benny play?",
        "answer": "violin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What was Betty Grable's nickname?",
        "answer": "The Legs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "What was Don Rickles' nickname?",
        "answer": "Mr. Warmth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who is Melanie Griffith's mother?",
        "answer": "Tippi Hedren"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who is Tippi Hedren's daughter?",
        "answer": "Melanie Griffith"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who is married to Eddie Van Halen?",
        "answer": "Valerie Bertanelli"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who is married to Valerie Bertanelli?",
        "answer": "Eddie Van Halen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who married Mutt Lange?",
        "answer": "Shania Twain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who married Shania Twain?",
        "answer": "Robert \"Mutt\" Lange"
    },
    {
        "category": "Show Biz",
        "question": "Who said 'you'd be surprised how much it costs to look this cheap'?",
        "answer": "Dolly Parton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Similes",
        "question": "As neat as a ------?",
        "answer": "pin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Space",
        "question": "In which state is the Houston Space Centre?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Space",
        "question": "What is the biggest criterion for prospective astronauts?",
        "answer": "eyesight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "As who is Cassius Clay now known?",
        "answer": "Mohammed Ali"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Atlanta ------?",
        "answer": "Braves"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Boston ------?",
        "answer": "Red Sox"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Chicago ------?",
        "answer": "Cubs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Cleveland ------?",
        "answer": "Indians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Florida ------?",
        "answer": "Marlins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Houston ------?",
        "answer": "Astros"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Kansas City ------?",
        "answer": "Royals"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Milwaukee ------?",
        "answer": "Brewers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The New York ------?",
        "answer": "Mets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Philadelphia ------?",
        "answer": "Phillies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The St. Louis ------?",
        "answer": "Cardinals"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Baseball: The Texas ------?",
        "answer": "Rangers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Basketball: The Denver ------?",
        "answer": "Nuggets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Chicago ------?",
        "answer": "Bears"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Dallas ------?",
        "answer": "Cowboys"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Denver ----?",
        "answer": "Broncos"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The Pittsburgh ------?",
        "answer": "Steelers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Football: The San Diego ------?",
        "answer": "Chargers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Calgary -------?",
        "answer": "Flames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Hockey: The Toronto ------?",
        "answer": "Maple Leafs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many dimples does a golf ball have?",
        "answer": "three hundred and thirty six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many sides does a baseball homeplate have?",
        "answer": "five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "How many stitches are on a regulation baseball?",
        "answer": "108"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In baseball, who won their first world series in 1969?",
        "answer": "New York Mets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In hockey, what is the equivalent of a rugby scrum?",
        "answer": "face-off"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In rugby, what is the equivalent of a hockey face-off?",
        "answer": "scrum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In showjumping, how many points are incurred for knocking down a fence?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In what sport did the word 'crestfallen' originate?",
        "answer": "cockfighting"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In what sport do you find 'coursing'?",
        "answer": "greyhound racing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "In what sport is the term 'terminal speed' used?",
        "answer": "Drag Racing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Other than England, which european country took part in the 1996 cricket World Cup?",
        "answer": "Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Other than skiing, which sport takes place on a piste?",
        "answer": "fencing"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "The first cricket one-day international was held between england and ------?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What are the two basic aids in orienteering?",
        "answer": "map and compass"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is soccer star Pele's real name?",
        "answer": "Edson Arantes do Nascimento"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the maximum number of clubs a golfer may use in a round?",
        "answer": "fourteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the misshapen ear that boxers often have called?",
        "answer": "cauliflower ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the name given to a rower who competes in an individual event?",
        "answer": "sculler"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the regulation height for a pin in tenpin bowling? (in inches)",
        "answer": "fifteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the score of a forfeited baseball game?",
        "answer": "9-0"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What is the score of a forfeited softball game?",
        "answer": "7-0"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What nationality is Gabriela Sabatini?",
        "answer": "Argentinian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport has sprint, tandem and team pursuit events?",
        "answer": "cycling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport is sometimes called 'rugger'?",
        "answer": "rugby union"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What sport/game is Chris Evert associated with?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What trophy is awarded to the winner of the NHL playoffs?",
        "answer": "Stanley Cup"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What was Jack Nicklaus' nickname?",
        "answer": "Golden Bear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "What was Mohammed Ali's original name?",
        "answer": "Cassius Clay"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Where is Capitol Hill?",
        "answer": "Washington DC"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which country always leads the opening Olympic procession?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which cricket player holds the world record for the highest individual score in first-class cricket?",
        "answer": "Brian Lara"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which sport allows substitutions without stoppage in play?",
        "answer": "hockey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Which tennis star wore denim shorts during matches?",
        "answer": "Andre Agassi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who did 'Tennis World' name rookie of the year in 1974?",
        "answer": "Martina Navratilova"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who had the nickname 'Golden Bear'?",
        "answer": "Jack Nicklaus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who has played in the most consecutive baseball games?",
        "answer": "Cal Ripken Jr"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who holds the NHL record for the most goals scored during a regular season?",
        "answer": "Wayne Gretzky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who hosted the 1999 cricket World Cup?",
        "answer": "England"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who is Edson Arantes do Nascimento better known as?",
        "answer": "Pele"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the 1990 Wimbledon women's singles runner-up?",
        "answer": "Zina Garrison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the NBA MVP in 1976, 1977 and 1980?",
        "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the NBA's most valuable player in 1976, 1977 and 1980?",
        "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the last Briton to win the men's singles at Wimbledon?",
        "answer": "Fred Perry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who was the only boxer to knock out Mohammed Ali?",
        "answer": "Larry Holmes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "Who won the 1982 soccer world cup?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With what did cricketer Mansoor Ali Khan Pataudi frequently play with in his hands?",
        "answer": "glass eye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With what sport is Chris Boardman associated?",
        "answer": "cycling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With what sport is Gabriela Sabatini associated?",
        "answer": "tennis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport",
        "question": "With what sport is Jack Nicklaus associated?",
        "answer": "golf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Sport and Entomology",
        "question": "What swimming stroke is named after an insect?",
        "answer": "butterfly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Squid Trivia",
        "question": "How many tentacles does a squid have?",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Superstition",
        "question": "What were comfrey baths were believed to restore?",
        "answer": "virginity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Superstitions",
        "question": "According to superstition, what do you make when you stub the toes on your right foot?",
        "answer": "A wish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Swimming",
        "question": "What did Captain Matthew Webb swim first?",
        "answer": "English Channel"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "As who is Terry Bollea known?",
        "answer": "Hulk Hogan"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "For which ad campaign was the line 'I can't believe I ate the whole thing' used?",
        "answer": "Alka Seltzer"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "From where was Ricky in 'I Love Lucy'?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In 'Coronation Street', who is Ken and Denise's son?",
        "answer": "Daniel"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV series 'Seinfeld', who does Michael Richards play?",
        "answer": "Kramer"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV series 'Seinfeld', who plays Kramer?",
        "answer": "Michael Richards"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV series 'The Brady Bunch', what was Cindy's toy doll's name?",
        "answer": "Kitty Carrie All"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV series 'The Fall Guy', who did Lee Majors play?",
        "answer": "Colt Seavers"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV series 'The Fall Guy', who played Colt Seavers?",
        "answer": "Lee Majors"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the TV sitcom 'Married With Children', what is the dog's name?",
        "answer": "Buck"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "In the children's tv series 'Sesame Street', what two characters were roomates?",
        "answer": "Bert and Ernie"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Kelsey Grammer sings and plays the theme song for which TV show?",
        "answer": "Frasier"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "On 'Dragnet', who played officer Bill Gannon?",
        "answer": "Harry Morgan"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "On 'The Lucy Show', who played Vivian Bagley?",
        "answer": "Vivian Vance"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "TV series: 'American ------'?",
        "answer": "Bandstand"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "To which elemetary school did TV's 'Brady Bunch' go?",
        "answer": "Dixie Canyon Elementary"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What TV network features programming just for children?",
        "answer": "Nickelodeon"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What TV series from 1970-1974 starred Susan Dey?",
        "answer": "Partridge Family"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What did Dr. David Banner become when he got angry?",
        "answer": "The Incredible Hulk"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What is Hulk Hogan's real name?",
        "answer": "Terry Bollea"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What is Kermit D Frog's girlfriend's name?",
        "answer": "Miss Piggy"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What is the drummer's name in 'The Muppet Show'?",
        "answer": "Animal"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What is the frog's name in 'The Muppet Show'?",
        "answer": "Kermit D Frog"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Jaleel White's character in the tv series 'Family ties'?",
        "answer": "Steve Urkel"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What night club did Ricky work at on 'I Love Lucy'?",
        "answer": "The Tropicana"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What show/game has characters such as Bulbasaur and Pikachu?",
        "answer": "Pokemon"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What was Lucy's maiden name on 'I Love Lucy'?",
        "answer": "McGillicuddy"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Ross' pet monkey on 'Friends'?",
        "answer": "Marcel"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Which famous male actor made his name in 'I Dream Of Jeannie'?",
        "answer": "Larry Hagman"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who did Larry Hagman portray in the TV series 'Dallas'?",
        "answer": "J.R. Ewing"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who did Pat Sajak play on the soapie 'Days Of Our Lives'?",
        "answer": "Kevin Hathaway"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who did Patrick Duffy portray in the TV series 'Dallas'?",
        "answer": "Bobby Ewing"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who did Vivian Vance play on 'The Lucy Show'?",
        "answer": "Vivian Bagley"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who killed Kenny?",
        "answer": "They"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Bobby Ewing in the TV series 'Dallas'?",
        "answer": "Patrick Duffy"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who played George Costanza on 'Seinfeld'?",
        "answer": "Jason Alexander"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Kevin Hathaway on the soapie 'Days Of Our Lives'?",
        "answer": "Pat Sajak"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who played Steve Erkel in 'Family Matters'?",
        "answer": "Jaleel White"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who played commander Riker in 'Star Trek'?",
        "answer": "Jonathan Frakes"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who plays many voices, such as Dr Nick, and Moe on 'The Simpsons'?",
        "answer": "Hank Azaria"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who sings and plays the theme song for the TV show 'Frasier'?",
        "answer": "Kelsey Grammer"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who starred as 'ouboet' in the first TV series of 'Orkney Snork Nie'?",
        "answer": "Frank Opperman"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the alter ego of 'The Incredible Hulk'?",
        "answer": "Dr. David Banner"
    },
    {
        "category": "TV Trivia",
        "question": "Who were Lucy and Ricky's next door neighbours and best friends?",
        "answer": "Fred and Ethel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Taboos",
        "question": "Over what place in india is it forbidden to fly an airplane?",
        "answer": "Taj Mahal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Technology",
        "question": "Who has the world's largest double-decker tram fleet?",
        "answer": "Hong Kong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Textiles",
        "question": "What colour thread is used for filigree?",
        "answer": "silver or gold"
    },
    {
        "category": "The Space Race",
        "question": "What was the name of the first space shuttle ever built?",
        "answer": "Enterprise"
    },
    {
        "category": "Theatre",
        "question": "In the opera 'La Traviata', what was Violetta's occupation?",
        "answer": "courtesan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Theme Parks",
        "question": "Which is the largest theme resort hotel?",
        "answer": "Lost City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Things",
        "question": "What can be tulip, balloon or flute?",
        "answer": "wine glasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Toys",
        "question": "From what were balloons originally made?",
        "answer": "animal bladders"
    },
    {
        "category": "Toys",
        "question": "What toy was originally made from the bladder of an animal?",
        "answer": "balloon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Travel",
        "question": "What city does Orly airport serve?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Travel",
        "question": "Which airline has the registration prefix 'VR'?",
        "answer": "Cathay Pacific"
    },
    {
        "category": "Travel",
        "question": "Which city is served by Ringway Airport?",
        "answer": "Manchester"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "5% of Canadians don't know the first seven words of the Canadian anthem, but know the first nine words of which anthem?",
        "answer": "The American anthem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "7% of Americans don't know the first nine words of the American anthem, but know the first seven words of which anthem?",
        "answer": "Canadian anthem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Betsy Ross is the only real person to ever have been the head of a ------?",
        "answer": "Pez dispenser"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "How much do nine pennies weigh?",
        "answer": "one ounce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Like what can a fully ripened cranberry be dribbled?",
        "answer": "basketball"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Of what are throat, foxing and platform parts?",
        "answer": "shoe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What have woodpecker scalps, porpoise teeth and giraffe tails all been used as?",
        "answer": "money"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What is 'mother's ruin'?",
        "answer": "gin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What is the range, in miles, of an Aim-7 Sparrow?",
        "answer": "twenty eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "What keeps one from crying when peeling onions?",
        "answer": "chewing gum"
    },
    {
        "category": "Trivia",
        "question": "Who is the only real person to ever have been the head on a Pez dispenser?",
        "answer": "Betsy Ross"
    },
    {
        "category": "Tunnels",
        "question": "How long is the longest tunnel? (in kms)",
        "answer": "one hundred and sixty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Tunnels",
        "question": "The world's longest tunnel connects Delaware and ------?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Tunnels",
        "question": "The world's longest tunnel connects New York and ------?",
        "answer": "Delaware"
    },
    {
        "category": "Tunnels",
        "question": "What is the world's longest tunnel?",
        "answer": "The Water Supply Tunnel"
    },
    {
        "category": "US Aeronautics",
        "question": "Where is the Kennedy Space Centre?",
        "answer": "Cape Canaveral, Florida"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "In the USA, for how many years is a patent good?",
        "answer": "seventeen"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "What is on a 5000 acre landfill at the head of Jamaica Bay near New York City?",
        "answer": "John F. Kennedy Airport"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "What is the most popular street name in the US?",
        "answer": "Park Street"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "What was Nancy Davis Reagan's birth name?",
        "answer": "Anne Frances Robbins"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "What was the Statue Of Liberty originally named?",
        "answer": "Liberty Enlightening The World"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Where is Stone Mountain?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Where were Tommy Lee Jones and Al Gore freshman roommates?",
        "answer": "Harvard University"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Which city is a 'player with railroads, and the nation's freight handler'?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Which two cities are known as the twin cities?",
        "answer": "Minneapolis and Saint Paul"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who is the only man to have been both chief justice and president of the US?",
        "answer": "William Taft"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who was Al Gore's freshman roommate at Harvard?",
        "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' freshman roommate at Harvard?",
        "answer": "Al Gore"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who was born Anne Frances Robbins?",
        "answer": "Nancy Davis Reagan"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who was born Sarah Jane Fulks?",
        "answer": "Jane Wyman Reagan"
    },
    {
        "category": "United States",
        "question": "Who was the first black mayor of Chicago?",
        "answer": "Harold Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "United states",
        "question": "What was Jane Wyman Reagan's birth name?",
        "answer": "Sarah Jane Fulks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Ventilation",
        "question": "If locked in a completely sealed room, of what will you die before you suffocate?",
        "answer": "carbon monoxide poisoning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Very Big Guns",
        "question": "Where is the biggest calibre cannon?",
        "answer": "Kremlin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Weather",
        "question": "Approximately how many times a minute does lightning strike the earth?",
        "answer": "six thousand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Weather",
        "question": "Which US state holds the record for most snowfall in a day, recorded February 7, 1916?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "What is it?",
        "question": "What is 9 metres high, 7 metres wide and 2,500 kilometres long?",
        "answer": "Great Wall of China"
    },
    {
        "category": "Wines",
        "question": "Good Rhine wines are bottled in what colour bottles?",
        "answer": "brown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Woodchucks",
        "question": "How much wood can a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could chuck wood?",
        "answer": "All the wood that a woodchuck could if a woodchuck could chuck wood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Association",
        "question": "Which word is related to these three: rat, blue, cottage?",
        "answer": "cheese"
    },
    {
        "category": "Word Pairs",
        "question": "Cattle are bovine, sheep are ------ ?",
        "answer": "ovine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Words containing 'for'",
        "question": "Pardon?",
        "answer": "FORgive"
    },
    {
        "category": "World Affairs",
        "question": "What arabian peninsula nations recently merged under communist leadership?",
        "answer": "Yemen"
    },
    {
        "category": "World Climate",
        "question": "What is a calm ocean region near the equator called?",
        "answer": "doldrum"
    }
]